<?xml-model href="lockhart-journals-teicustomization.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en" xmlns:hlu="http://www.osu.edu/ulman/reliablewitnesses/ns/1.0">
   <!-- TO-DO LIST 
   - Update glosses to P5
   -->
   
   <teiHeader type="AACR2">
      <!--
      The type attribute in teiHeader element above asserts that the header provides 
      enough information to create a bibliographic record that complies with the 
      Anglo-American Cataloguing Rules, 2nd ed. (1978; rev. 1988).
      -->
      
      <fileDesc>
      <!--
      The  file description, tagged <fileDesc>, contains "a full bibliographical description 
      of the computer file itself, from which a user of the text could derive a proper bibliographic 
      citation, or which a librarian or archivist could use in creating a catalogue entry recording 
      its presence within a library or archive" (TEI P4X, ch. 5).
      -->
         
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Ernest Earl Lockhart's Antarctic Journal,<lb/>25 December 1940 to 16 January 1941</title>

            <!-- 
            Here we list the editors of the edition, using the form of your name
            that you use for professional publications.
             -->
            <editor><persName ref="#EKC">Erin Kathleen Cahill</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#moriah">Moriah Cheatham</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#ME">Meg Edison</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#AK">Alan Keep</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#CH">Caitlin Hurdley</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#RSL">Rachel Layfield</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#Kathy">Kathy Mielecki</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#FP">Francis Pellicciaro</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#tamika">Tamika Smith</persName></editor>
            <editor role="principal-editor"><persName ref="#HLU">H. Lewis Ulman</persName></editor>
            <editor><persName ref="#AJW">Adam J. Waisanen</persName></editor>
            
            <!-- 
            Statement of Responsibility supplies a statement of responsibility for the 
            intellectual content of a text, edition, recording, or series, where the 
            specialized elements for authors, editors, etc. do not suffice or do not apply.
            For our purposes, use your full name (first middle last) for now.
             -->
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Creation of digital scans of manuscript pages: </resp>
               <orgName>ArcaSearch</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Creation of initial machine-readable transcript: </resp>
               <persName ref="#EKC">Erin Kathleen Cahill</persName>
               <persName ref="#moriah">Moriah Cheatham</persName>
               <persName ref="#ME">Meg Edison</persName>
               <persName ref="#AK">Alan Keep</persName>
               <persName ref="#CH">Caitlin Hurdley</persName>
               <persName ref="#RSL">Rachel Layfield</persName>
               <persName ref="#Kathy">Kathy Mielecki</persName>
               <persName ref="#FP">Francis Pellicciaro</persName>
               <persName ref="#tamika">Tamika Smith</persName>
               <persName ref="#HLU">H. Lewis Ulman</persName>
               <persName ref="#AJW">Adam J. Waisanen</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup: </resp>
               <persName ref="#EKC">Erin Kathleen Cahill</persName>
               <persName ref="#moriah">Moriah Cheatham</persName>
               <persName ref="#ME">Meg Edison</persName>
               <persName ref="#AK">Alan Keep</persName>
               <persName ref="#CH">Caitlin Hurdley</persName>
               <persName ref="#RSL">Rachel Layfield</persName>
               <persName ref="#Kathy">Kathy Mielecki</persName>
               <persName ref="#FP">Francis Pellicciaro</persName>
               <persName ref="#tamika">Tamika Smith</persName>
               <persName ref="#HLU">H. Lewis Ulman</persName>
               <persName ref="#AJW">Adam J. Waisanen</persName>
            </respStmt>

         </titleStmt>
         
         <extent>approx. 275 kilobytes</extent>

         <publicationStmt>

            <publisher>The Ohio State University Libraries
               <address>
                  <addrLine n="2">327 Main Library</addrLine>
                  <addrLine n="3">1858 Neil Avenue Mall</addrLine>
                  <addrLine n="4">Columbus, OH 43210</addrLine>
               </address>
            </publisher>

            <pubPlace>Columbus, OH</pubPlace>

            <!-- 
            The <idno> element is only required for documents with a standard id number
            such as a library call number.. 
            -->
            <idno type="Location">RG 56.206 — Box 1 / Folder 11 / Location 054-846-7</idno>

            <availability>
               <p><emph rend="bold">Availability</emph>: The Ernest E. Lockhart journal represented
                  in this edition is the property of the Byrd Polar Research Center Archival Program
                  (BPRCAP) of The Ohio State University, which has grant the editors permission to
                  publish this edition of the manuscripts. The original journal is held in Box 1,
                  Folder 11 of the Ernest Earl Lockhart Collection, BPRCAP. For a complete inventory
                  to the Lockhart Collection, please see <media mimeType="text/html"
                     url="http://rave.ohiolink.edu/archives/ead/OhCoUBP0006">
                     <desc>http://rave.ohiolink.edu/archives/ead/OhCoUBP0006</desc>
                  </media>.This edition is published under a Creative Commons license (see below).
                  Any use of the edition should acknowledge the BPRCAP and the editors of the
                  journal. </p>
               <p xml:id="CreativeCommons">
                  <![CDATA[<a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/"><img alt="Creative Commons License" style="border-width:0" src="http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights20.png"/></a><br/>This work is licensed under a <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0  License</a>.
                  The license does not transfer any rights regarding material used in the edition by permission of a third party.]]>
               </p>
            </availability>

            <date>2014-04-23</date>

         </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc> 
            <biblFull>

               <titleStmt>

                  <!--
                  The "level" attribute "indicates whether this is the title of an article, book, journal, 
                  series, or unpublished material, indicated as a, b, j, s, or u" (TEI P4X, ch. 5.2.1).
                  -->
                  <title level="u">Journal covering period Dec 25 1940 until return home
                     about May 1<hi rend="superscript underlined">st</hi> 1941
                  </title>

                  <author>Ernest Earl Lockhart (1912-2006)</author>


               </titleStmt>               

               <!-- 
                    The <extent> element indicates the size of your source document, in whatever 
                    units are appropriate (usually pages; for example, 2 pp.) 
                -->
               <extent>118 pp.</extent>

               <publicationStmt>
                  <authority>Ernest Earl Lockhart Collection, Byrd Polar Research Center Archival Program, The Ohio State University</authority>
               </publicationStmt>

               <!-- 
                      TAKE NOTE: Your entire header should answer the following questions about your 
                      source document. At this point in your header, you should discuss anything in 
                      this list not mentioned elsewhere in the header.
                     
                        1. What is the document (letter, will, etc.)?
                        2. What does it say about itself (titles, descriptive notes, etc.)?
                        3. What does it contain (no. of pages/sheets, enclosures, etc.)?
                        4. How is it put together (folded sheets, binding, etc.)?
                        5. What is it made of (paper, vellum, etc.)?
                        6. What is its size (i.e., physical dimensions)?
                        7. How is it packaged/contained (binding, envelope, folder, box, etc.)?
                        8. How is it related to other versions (original, copy, print history)?
                     
                        You can use more than one paragraph (tagged <p> </p>).
                   -->
               <notesStmt>
                  
                  <note type="descriptive" resp="ed">
                     <!-- 
                     We will use this note to describe the physical diary.
                     -->
                        <p>
                         <figure rend="embed">
                           <head>Front Cover</head>
                            <graphic url="https://images.asc.ohio-state.edu/is/image/englishdocs/f/f6740eaf-5b89-47d7-87f8-ff9c9e993803.jpg?scale=0.1&amp;rgn=0,0,252,313&amp;fmt=png"/>
                           <figDesc>
                              Front Cover
                           </figDesc>
                         </figure>
                        <figure rend="embed">
                           <head>Page Edges</head>
                           <graphic url="lockhart-journal-page-edges.jpg"/>
                           <figDesc>
                              Page Edges
                           </figDesc>
                        </figure>
                       </p>
                     <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">Collation</emph>: The journal contains 118 pages arranged as follows: 1 (blank paste-down endpaper);
                        2 (blank except for "1/9" written in the upper right-hand corner); 3 (blank except for "1" written in the upper left-hand
                        corner; 4-40 (journal entries on pages numbered 1 through 37 consecutively, odd numbers in the upper right-hand corners,
                        even numbers in the upper left-hand corners of pages); 41-117 (blank pages); 118 (list of outgoing mail on a paste-down
                        endpaper). The text block consists of a gathering of four quires of 6, 20, 16, and 18 leaves—including the paste-down
                        endpapers in the first and last quires—sewn through the fold and glued (?) to the binding.
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <figure rend="embed">
                           <head>Watermark</head>
                           <graphic url="lockhart-paper-watermark.jpg"/>
                           <figDesc>
                              Watermark
                           </figDesc>
                           <media mimeType="jpeg" url="lockhart-paper-watermark.jpg"><desc>Click to Enlarge</desc></media>
                        </figure>
                        <emph rend="bold">Paper</emph>: The pages of the journal consist of cream-colored paper, 20.5 cm wide by 25.8 cm tall, with 1.5 cm top and bottom
                        unlined margins. The body of the pages contains 28 horizontal blue lines spaced 0.8 cm apart and a vertical red line defining
                        a 2.54 cm left margin. Some pages contain all or part of a 10 x 7.4 cm oval watermark depicting a seated female figure 
                        holding a spear in the crook of her right arm and leaves in her extended left hand. A 3 x 5 cm crown sits above the oval.
                        <title>Paper Watermarks</title> identifies a nearly identical watermark with stationers Waterlow Bros. &amp; Layton, London;
                        however, the watermark illustrated on <title>Paper Watermarks</title> contains the decorative initials "WBL" below the
                        oval. Another page of the journal bears the watermark "Original Superfine."
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">Binding</emph>: Dark brown leather over buckram-wrapped boards. The leather is worn and chipped, exposing buckram, and 
                        the front cover is embossed with "THE ACADEMY" (centered) and "REORDER NO. 411" (lower righthand corner). The spine is unmarked.  
                        The top, bottom, and fore-edge of the text block are stippled.
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">Loose Radiograms</emph>: Twenty-five loose radiograms are tucked inside the back cover of the bound journal. The radiograms
                        fall into two groups: typed copies of radiograms Lockhart received via the Army Amateur Radio Service from friends and family, and typed drafts 
                        of outgoing messages. The incoming radiograms are all on cream-colored onionskin measuring 20.2 cm wide by 13.5 cm tall with two spiral binding 
                        holes along one edge (in all but one case at the top of the message). The outgoing messages are on heavier cream-colored paper, most 
                        measuring 21.6 cm wide by 14 cm tall except for three from April 1941 measuring 21.5 cm wide by 17.6 cm tall.
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">Publication: </emph>Unpublished manuscripts.
                     </p>
                  </note>

                  <note type="introductory" resp="ed">
                     <!-- 
                     We will use this note to contain an historical/critical introduction to the
                     text of the Smith diary.
                     -->
                     <quote rend="epigraph">I am now a firm believer that one trained so completely in 
                        theoretical matters as I have been in the past should go away on an expedition 
                        for a year or two.<lb/>
                        -- Earl Lockhart, 1 January 1941</quote>
                     <p>
                        <figure rend="embed">
                           <head>Ernest Earl Lockhart<lb/>ca. 1939-1941</head>
                           <graphic url="usase-lockhart-watermarked.png"/>
                           <figDesc> Ernest Earl Lockhart, ca. 1939-1941 </figDesc>
                        </figure> Ernest Earl Lockhart (1912-2006) earned a PhD in biochemistry from
                        the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in 1938 and joined the 1939-1941
                        United States Antarctic Service Expedition (USASE) the following year, serving as a
                        physiologist stationed at the West Base near the Bay of Whales, an inlet of
                        the Ross Sea on the Ross Ice Shelf. Lockhart kept personal journals
                        throughout his service in Antarctica, four volumes of which are held in the
                        Ernest Earl Lockhart Collection of the Byrd Polar Research Center Archival
                        Program at The Ohio State University, along with personal correspondence,
                        newspaper and magazine clippings, reports and publications, photographs and
                        film, and several artifacts <bibl><ref><title level="a">Ernest Earl Lockhart
                                 Collection</title></ref></bibl>. This edition presents Lockhart's
                        manuscript journal for the period 25 December 1940 through 16 January 1941,
                        as well as twenty-five radiograms sent or received by Lockhart during
                        roughly the same period (the radiograms are tucked, loose, inside the
                        journal).
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        On New Year's Day 1941, a 28-year-old
                        poised between a great adventure and his return home, Lockhart composed an
                        especially reflective journal entry in which he assesses the lessons learned
                        during his stay in Antarctica and his future prospects: he writes, <q>Home
                        again! What visions in the future that small phrase conjures up!</q>
                     </p>
                     <p> Lockhart's New Year's reverie captures
                        much of the content and character of the journal represented in this
                        edition. For instance, Lockhart and other members of the USASE were never as
                        isolated from home as explorers in earlier eras. Thanks in part to a network
                        of amateur radio operators, expedition members could regularly exchange
                        radiograms—like the ones included in this edition—with family and friends
                        back home. The scientific work to which Lockhart regularly refers no doubt
                        constituted the <foreign xml:lang="fr">raison d'être</foreign> of the
                        expedition for Lockhart and the members of the expedition's various science
                        teams, but their work required support from surveyors, medics,
                        photographers, pilots, mechanics, carpenters, cooks, navigators, radio
                        operators, quartermasters, tank and tractor drivers, and dog drivers.
                        Lockhart regularly helps with such support work, in the process learning
                           <q>the meaning of work and what a working man thinks about the type of
                           work not requiring a strong back and plenty of perspiration.</q> He takes
                        particular interest in the dog teams and, to a lesser degree, in the
                        performance of various support vehicles—two aircraft, a tank, and a tractor.
                        No doubt, the looming prospect of war—already underway in Europe—lent
                        particular importance for the expedition's leaders to testing logistics and
                        equipment for moving personnel and materiel in extreme conditions, though
                        Lockhart never specifically mentions the war or the activities of other
                        nations in Antarctica in these early years of World War II. Finally, we
                        should note that expedition members' time wasn't completely filled with
                        work. Weather, logistics, and concern for morale all provided opportunities
                        for rest and relaxation, and Lockhart at times reflects on his reading and
                        on movies shown at the base. In one journal entry concerning his reading of
                           <title level="m">Gone with the Wind</title>, this young New Englander
                        takes the opportunity to ask <q>some of the Southern boys here</q> about the
                        South, which he admits <q>has been a mystery to me and no doubt to countless
                           other Americans.</q> In what follows, we provide further historical
                        context that we hope will enrich readers' understanding of the
                           <soCalled>lifeworld</soCalled> to which Lockhart's journal entries refer,
                        drawing whenever possible on contemporary sources. </p>
                     <p rend="h3" xml:id="science">Scientific Work of the USASE</p>
                     <p>First paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p><hi rend="bold">Sub-head</hi>. Second paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p rend="h3" xml:id="dogs">Dog Teams</p>
                     <p>
                           Sled dog teams, whose roots lie far beyond their late 19th-century popularization, 
                        share a relationship with their masters marked not only by deep affection but 
                        also a certain measure of calculated cruelty.Indigenous peoples of Arctic North 
                        America, Siberia and Greenland used sled dogs widely, and it <ref target=" #Florio">"was in Siberia  
                        that dog-driving was first adapted to geographic exploration."</ref> This use spread to  
                        the rest of Russia by the 17th-18th centuries, the cartographical records left from 
                        Russian explorers inspiring the 1890s development of planned sled team use by Norwegian and American 
                        explorers. Fridhtjof Nansen's Arctic expedition although failures, revealed that through <ref target="#Florio">"the use 
                        of dogs and sleds [could bring] him closer to [the Arctic] than any previous explorer."</ref>
                        The next and one of the most famous uses of sled dogs was the American explorer Peary, who succeeded 
                        in reaching the North Pole through his creation of a system in which he would butcher certain of 
                        his dogs to feed the others at various points along their route. This was not unknown on the Nansen 
                        expedition which suffered from food shortages and starvation and of which there were only two dog survivors, 
                        but the creation of a systematic reduction of dogs through cannibalism was Peary's innovation. This system, 
                        used later by Amundsen is described as being as fast a Mercedes, but the <ref target="#Florio">"critical difference 
                        between the two was that an E-class carburetor could not be eaten, but a dog could."</ref> The strange mixture of 
                        love and cruelty is one that seems to be present in all polar expeditons, with Amundsen overseeing at different 
                        points in his work both the organizing of dog teams so that dogs believed to know one another could work together, 
                        as well as carefully planning which dogs would be butchered for the others to eat on the toughest portions of the journey. 
                        Lockhart's deep admiration and love of the dogs on his own expedition may or may not have been tempered 
                        with the knowledge that so many of their fellow animals were butchered by men who loved them as much as he 
                        did.
                     </p>
                     <p>Second paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p rend="h3" xml:id="geopolitics">Other Nations' Activities in Antarctica ca. 1939-1941</p>
                     <p>First paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p>Second paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p rend="h3" xml:id="entertainment">Reading and Recreation</p>
                     <p>First paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p>Second paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p rend="h3" xml:id="equipment">Testing Equipment in Severe Cold</p>
                     <p>First paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p>Second paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p rend="h3" xml:id="communications">Communications</p>
                     <p>First paragraph of this section.</p>
                     <p>Second paragraph of this section.</p>
                   </note>

               </notesStmt>

            </biblFull>
            
            <list type="dogs">
               <item xml:id="Sheila">
                  <name>Sheila</name>
                  <trait type="breed"><desc>Siberian Huskie</desc></trait>
                  <trait type="sex"><desc>Female</desc></trait>
                  <state type="age" when="1939-09-26"><desc>3</desc></state>
                  <desc>In his entry for January 5, 1941, Lockhart recounts an occasion on which Sheila tried to bite him,
                     misbehavior that causes Lockhart to violate his general rule of not hitting the dogs.</desc>
               </item>
               <item xml:id="Spot">
                  <name>Spot</name>
                  <trait type="breed"><desc>Eskimo</desc></trait>
                  <trait type="sex"><desc>Male</desc></trait>
                  <state type="age" when="1939-09-26"><desc>1</desc></state>
                  <desc>In a radiogram to his sister dated January 4, 1941 and in his journal entry for January 5, 1941, 
                     Lockhart notes that he hopes to take Spot, his "lead dog," home with him.
                  </desc>
               </item>
               <item xml:id="Peterdog">
                  <name source="#koulouris">Peter</name>
                  <trait type="sex"><desc>Male</desc></trait>
                  <desc>Peter is one of two dogs that lived at his parents' house in Mattapan during the Expedition. Both dogs are mentioned
                  several times as they were being bulked up in preparation to be able to play with the sled dog Spot.</desc>
               </item>
               <item xml:id="Petedog">
                  <name source="#koulouris">Pete</name>
                  <trait type="sex"><desc>Male</desc></trait>
                  <desc>Pete is one of two dogs that lived at his parents' house in Mattapan during the Expedition. Both dogs are mentioned
                  several times as they were being bulked up in preparation to be able to play with the sled dog Spot. Pete was later donated to
                  the military to assist with the war effort.</desc>
               </item>
            </list>


            <list type="vehicles">
               <item xml:id="Condor">
                  <name type="aircraft" source="#Bertrand #eel-19410103">Condor</name>
                  <desc>Twin-motored Curtiss-Wright Condor biplane loaded at Valparaiso. Each base had a Condor plane. According to Bertrand,
                  this type of plane was the same as the William Horlick which had been used on
                  long flights during the Second Byrd Expedition. These planes had been used for 5 years by the USMC.
                  The Condor was used to bring supplies to trail parties and dog teams. Lockhart writes about the Condor's final flight on January 3, 1941; it had engine trouble according to 
                  Lockhart; Bertrand mentions a fire. After this engine failure or fire, the Condor was subsequently abandoned.</desc>
               </item>
               <item xml:id="Bear">
                  <name type="ship" source="#Bertrand">U.S.S. Bear, Bear of Oakland</name>
                  <desc>One of two ships used on the 1939-41 expedition led by Admiral Byrd. Originally named the "Bear of Oakland," it was 
                     used during Admiral Byrd's second expedition (1933-35) as an ice ship, then later  reconditioned and commissioned by the 
                     U.S. navy as the "U.S.S. Bear" before being assigned to the 1939-41 expedition <bibl><ref target="#Bertrand"><title level="m">Americans in Antarctica</title></ref></bibl>.</desc>
               </item>
               <item xml:id="Beechcraft">
                  <name type="aircraft" source="#Bertrand #eel-19410303">Beechcraft</name>
                  <desc>According to Bertrand, the Beechcraft was a new, light, single-motored, 5 passenger plane 
                  that was mounted on skis and supposed to be transported on the Snow Cruiser for aerial exploration
                  within a distance of 300 miles. When the Condor was disabled on January 3, 1941, Pete and Pappy flew the Beechcraft to rescue 
                  supplies left in the Condor and to fly men back to West Base.</desc>
               </item>
               <item xml:id="SnowCruiser">
                  <name type="cruiser" source="#bertrand">Snow Cruiser</name>
                  <desc>According to Bertrand, the Snow Cruiser could store food for a year, and it 
                  carried 2500 gallons of diesel oil which would last 5000 miles as well as 1000 gallons of gas for flying. 
                  Its maximum speed was 30 miles per hour, and it was created to function at very low temperatures
                  and travel in deep, soft snow. It could also be living space for the crew. It ultimately failed. 
               </desc>
               </item>
               <item xml:id="tank">
                  <name type="tank" source="#Bertrand">Tank</name>
                  <desc>The tank appears to be a Marmon-Herrington CTLS that was used during the Expedition.
                  It was not equipped with any weapon systems, instead having an open cockpit design. It was 
                  mostly used for moving personnel and equipment and also served as a test of the tank in extreme
                  cold weather.</desc>
               </item>
               <item xml:id="Star">
                 <name type="ship" source="#USCG #Shipscribe">U.S.C.G.C. North Star, Star</name>
                  <desc>The North Star was a wooden cruising cutter built in 1932 for the U.S. Department
                     of the Interior's Bureau of Indian Affairs, operating between Seattle, Washington, and 
                     Alaska.  After two Antarctic voyages, including Lockhart's (1939-41), she was commissioned for the
                     U.S. Coast Guard on 15 May 1941 and joined the Northeast Greenland Patrol on 1 July 1941, 
                     (along with the other ship from the 1939-41 Antarctic expedition, U.S.S. Bear). </desc>
               </item>
               </list>

            <list type="rhetorical-figures">
               <head>Rhetorical figures, schemes, and tropes</head>
               <item>
                  <interpGrp type="figures">
                     <interp xml:id="adage"></interp>
                     <interp xml:id="adynaton"></interp>
                     <interp xml:id="aetiologia"></interp>
                     <interp xml:id="anesis"></interp>
                     <interp xml:id="anthypophora"></interp>
                     <interp xml:id="aporia"></interp>
                     <interp xml:id="epicrisis"></interp>
                     <interp xml:id="metaphor"></interp>
                  </interpGrp>
                  <interpGrp type="tropes">
                     <interp></interp>
                  </interpGrp>
               </item>
            </list>
            
            <listPerson type="mentioned">
               <head>People Mentioned in Ernest E. Lockhart's Journal </head>
               <person xml:id="EEL">
                  <persName>Lockhart, Ernest Earl</persName>
                  <birth when="1912-09-10"><placeName ref="#Boston">Boston, MA</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="2006-07-26"><placeName ref="#WestDennis">West Dennis, MA</placeName></death>
                  <note type="biographical">bio note</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Cruzen" source="#Stark">
                  <persName>Cruzen, Richard H. (Richard Harold), 1897-1970</persName>
                  <birth when="1897-04-28"><placeName>Gallatin, MO</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="1970-04-15"></death>
                  <occupation>Naval officer</occupation>
                  <state type="rank" when="1941-01-05"><desc>Lieutenant Commander, USN</desc></state>
                  <note type="biographical">bio note</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Perk">
                  <persName>Perkins, Jack E. <addName type="nickname">Perk</addName></persName>
                  <occupation when="1940">biologist</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">Jack Perkins led a biological party into the Fosdick Mountains in December 1940. Mount Perkins, a
                  peak at the east end of the Fosdick Mountains, was named after Perkins in 1947 <bibl><ref target="#MPerkins"><title level="a">Mount Perkins</title></ref></bibl>.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Bursey" source="#Passel #personnel #WikiBursey">
                   <persName>Bursey, Jack <addName type="nickname">Jack B.</addName></persName>
                  <birth when="1903-09-20">St. Lunaire, Newfoundland, Canada</birth>
                  <death when="1980-03-01">Montague, Michigan</death>
                  <occupation when="1940">dog driver</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">A dog driver who had worked with Byrd on previous expeditions. Published two books about his expeditions, Antarctic Night and 
                     St. Lunaire, Antarctic Lead Dog. During this expedition he made one of the longest dog trips ever recorded, and one of the Hal Flood mountains became named "Mt. Bursey" after him.
                     Was from Grand Rapids, Michigan, and would have been survived by his wife Ada Bursey<bibl><ref target="#WikiBursey">"Jack Bursey"</ref></bibl></note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Shirley" source="#personnel">
                  <persName>Shirley, Charles S.</persName>
                  <occupation when="1940">photographer</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">A photographer on the expedition. Was from San Diego California, worked both bases, and would have been survived by his wife Anna.<bibl><ref target="#personnel">"Personnel 1939-1940"</ref></bibl></note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Richardson" source="#Passel #personnel">
                  <persName>Richardson H. H. <addName type="nickname">Jack</addName></persName>
                  <occupation>dog driver</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">A dog driver on the expedition who features in both Lockhart and Passel's accounts. Also took video footage of some of the expedition. Was from Franklin, New Hampshire 
                     and would have been survived by his brother Harold C. Richardson. Goes primarily by the nickname "Jack"<bibl><ref target="#personnel">"Personnel 1939-1940"</ref></bibl><bibl><ref target="#Passel">"Ice"</ref></bibl></note>
                   </person>
               <person xml:id="Sherman" source="#ANB">
                  <persName>Sherman, General William Tecumseh</persName>
                  <occupation>Union Army General</occupation>
                  <birth when="1820-02-08">
                     <placeName>Lancaster, Ohio</placeName>
                  </birth>
                  <death when="1891-02-14">
                     <placeName>New York City, New York</placeName>
                  </death>
                  <note type="biographical">Lockhart mentions Sherman's burning of Atlanta while recording his 
                     reactions to Gone With the Wind<bibl><ref target="#ANB">"William Tecumseh Sherman"</ref></bibl></note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Warner" source="#personnel #Passel">
                  <persName>Warner, Lawrence A. <addName type="nickname">Larry</addName></persName>
                  <occupation>geologist</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">A geologist on the expedition. Was from Monroe, Ohio and would have been 
                     survived by his parents Mr. and Mrs. C.F. Warner <bibl><ref target="#personnel">"Personnel 1939-1940"</ref></bibl> </note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Guernsey" source="#Card">
                  <persName>Guernsey, George Rockwell</persName>
                  <birth when="1884-02-15">Canton, Bradford Co., Pennsylvania</birth>
                  <residence when="-1952">Wellesley, Massachusetts</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Lockhart exchanges radiograms with a George Guernsey of Wellesley Massachusetts, 
                     about Christmas and his potential trips to Panama and Seattle. There's a Guernsey by that name living there according 
                     to a family genealogy, barring another man with the same name it's presumably the same man.<bibl><ref target="#Card">"Garnsey-Guernsey Genealogy"</ref></bibl></note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="JackMahan">
                  <persName>Mahan, Jack</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">A friend of Lockhart's whose father passed away during Christmas of 1940.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="MrsMahan">
                  <persName>Mrs. Mahan</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">The wife of Mr. Mahan and mother to Jack and Margaret Mahan. Lockhart sends her a radiogram
                  to extend his condolences regarding the death of her husband.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="MrMahan">
                  <persName>Mr. Mahan</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when="1940"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">The father of Lockhart's friend Jack. Mr. Mahan passed away during Lockhart's trip. He had suffered from heart trouble.
                     Lockhart is saddened by his death and reminisces about their relationship, remarking that Mr. Mahan would've liked to hear about Antarctica.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Gutenko" source="#personnel #MGutenko">
                  <persName>Gutenko, Sigmund</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Cook</occupation>
                  <residence when="1940">Baltimore, Maryland</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Gutenko was the cook and steward for the West Base. He was from Baltimore, Maryland. The Gutenko Mountains
                     in Antarctica are named after him.<bibl><ref target="#personnel">"Personnel, 1939-1940"</ref>; <ref target="#MGutenko">"Mount Gutenko"</ref></bibl></note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="CharliePassel" source="#personnel #Passel">
                  <persName>Passel, Charles F.</persName>
                  <birth when="1911"><placeName>Indianapolis, Indiana</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="2001"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Geologist</occupation>
                  <residence when="1940">Indianapolis, Indiana</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Passel was a geologist from Indianapolis, Indiana. Lockhart ran metabolism tests on him. In 1995, his Antarctic diaries detailing the expedition, 
                     called <title level="m">Ice</title>, were published.<bibl><ref target="#personnel">"Personnel, 1939-1940"</ref>; <ref target="#Passel"><title type="m">Ice</title></ref></bibl></note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="PappyGray" source="#personnel #Gray #Pappy #Pappy Gray">
                 <persName>Gray, Orville <addName type="nickname">Pappy</addName></persName> 
                 <occupation when="1940">aviation mechanic and captain</occupation> 
                 <residence when="1940">Folmouth, Virginia</residence> 
                 <note>Orville "Pappy" Gray was an airplane mechanic from West Base.
                       Not to be confused with J.A. "Pappy" Reece, a radio operator. Where "Pappy" is mentioned and specified as neither, as in journals 2-24 and 2-25, the person is question is dealing with engine trouble on the Condor and is thus presumably Gray. 
                       Lockhart mentions him harnessing puppies to the airplane sled and driving them around.
                       Gray was the one who flew the Beechcraft back to get engine parts for the Condor when the Condor's engine broke down.
                       Gray is mentioned being spotted by coincidence and then joined when Lockhart, Tony, and Court were out going toward the Barrier Cache</note> 
               </person>
               <person xml:id="ClarkGable">
                <persName>Gable, Wiliam Clark</persName>
                <birth when="1901-02-01">Cadiz, Ohio</birth>
                <death when="1960-11-16">West Hollywood, California</death>
                <occupation when="1940">Actor</occupation>
                <residence when="1940">Encio, California</residence>
                <note type="biographical">Gable appeared in 97 films from 1924 to 1961, his last film being released after his death.
                Gable was nominate for the best leading actor academy award in 1934, 1935, and 1939. He won it in 1934 for his role in "It Happened One Night." 
                Gabel was leading actor in over 60 films and is best known for his role in Gone With the Wind in 1939</note>
                <note>Lockhart mentions Gabel when comparing the film adaptation of Gone with the Wind to the novel. Lockhart finds Gabel fitting in his role as Rhett Butler</note>  
               </person>
               <person xml:id="VivienLeigh">
                <persName>Leigh, Vivien</persName>
                <birth when="1913-11-05">Darjeeling, British India</birth>
                <death when="1967-07-08">London, England</death>
                <occupation when="1940">Actress</occupation>
                <residence when="1940">England</residence>
                <note type="biographical">Leigh appeared in 37 plays and 20 films from 1935 to 1966.
                 Leigh won the best actress academy award in 1939 and 1951 for her roles in Gone with the Wind and A Streetcar Named Desire, respectively.
                 Leigh is best known for the aforementioned roles and was married to British actor Laurence Olivier from 1940 to 1960.</note>
                <note>Lockhart mentions Leigh when comparing the film adaptation of Gone with the Wind to the novel. Lockhart expresses doubt that Leigh was the right actress to play Scarlett</note>  
               </person>
               <person xml:id="MargaretMitchell">
                 <persName>Mitchell, Margaret</persName>
                 <birth when="1900-11-08">Atlanta, Georgia</birth>
                 <death when="1949-08-16">Atlanta, Georgia</death>
                 <occupation when="1940">Housewife (formerly a writer and journalist)</occupation>
                 <residence when="1940">Atlanta, Georgia</residence>
                 <note type="biographical">Margaret Mitchell was an author and a journalist for The Atlanta Journal.
                        Gone with the Wind, the only work of hers published during her lifetime, won the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction in 1937
                        Over 30 million copies of the novel Gone with the Wind have been printed worldwide.</note>
                 <note>Lockhart mentions Mitchell in his comparison of the film adaptation of Gone with the Wind to the novel. He is unsure
                       which ending was more appropriate; Mitchell's written ending of the film ending,</note> 
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Darwin">
                <persName>Darwin, Charles</persName>
                <birth when="1809-02-12">Shropshire, United Kingdom</birth>
                <death when="1882-04-19">Downe, United Kingdom</death>
                <occupation>Geologist and Naturalist</occupation> 
                <note type="biographical">Charles Darwin is one of the most influential scientists the world has known. His theory of natural selection 
                    forms the basis of modern views on the diversity of life and how different forms of life come about.</note>
                  <note>Lockhart mentions Darwin when he says that he is 
                        reading "Homo versus Darwin a judicial examination of statements recently published by Mr. Darwin regarding 'The Descent of Man'"
                        itself a commentary on Daron's book "The Descent of Man, and Selection in Relation to Sex." 
                        Lockhart said that he bought the commentary to accompany the book itself, which he had at home.</note>  
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Fitz" source="#personnel #WikiFitz">
                  <persName>Fitzsimmons, Roy <addName type="nickname">Fitz</addName></persName>
                  <birth when="1916"></birth>
                  <death when="1945"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Physicist</occupation>
                  <residence when="1940">Newark, New Jersey</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Roy Fitzsimmons was a physicist from Newark, New Jersey. He ran the Rockefeller Mountains seismic station during the expedition. Lockhart talks about running metabolism tests on him and them
                     going out on excursions together. Mount Fitzsimmons in Antarctica is named after him.<bibl><ref target="#personnel">"Personnel, 1939-1940"</ref>; <ref target="#WikiFitz">"Roy Fitzsimmons"</ref></bibl></note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Pete" source="#Bertrand #personnel #Passel #Petras #eel-19410103"><persName>Petras, Theodore A. <addName type="nickname">Pete</addName>
               </persName>
                  <birth when="1911-05-16"><placeName>Birmingham, Alabama</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="2004-05-09"><placeName>Miami, FL</placeName></death>
                  <occupation>Pilot</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">Pete, not to be confused with Lockhart's dog or a baby named Peter who was
                    mentioned in the journals, was an expedition man and a pilot. Pete's rank during the expedition was 
                    was Tech Sergeant (NAP) in the USMC. 
                     He was assigned to the Snow Cruiser and piloted the Condor on its last flight before it caught fire and was abandoned on January 3, 1941. 
                     Pete successfully rescued men using the Beechcraft and made it back to West Base. He wanted to break altitude and 
                     enjoyed "making hops" in planes and taking tanks out for fun; Pete also played ukelele. Pete also shot skua gulls and tried to get blood samples from them.  
                     He achieved the rank of Colonel in the USMC and was inducted into the 
                     Alabama Aviation Hall of Fame on December 17, 1993.</note></person>
               <person xml:id="Mac" source="#Bertrand #personnel #Passel #mccoy #jamescharles #eel-19410103"><persName>McCoy, James C. <addName type="nickname">Mac</addName> <addName>McCoy, Charles James</addName><addName>McCoy, James Charles</addName>
               </persName>
                  <birth when="1905-05-09"><placeName>Bountiful, Utah</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="1981-03-03"><placeName>Jacksonville, FL</placeName></death>
                  <occupation>Pilot</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">Mac was a pilot and part of the West Base crew. His rank during the expedition was ACMM (Aviation Chief Machinist Mate) (NAP) in the USN.
                     He was a member of the dog team 
                  that was transported back to West Base by Pete the day of the Condor incident on January 3, 1941. Mac achieved the rank of Commander. He discovered and named a mountain after his wife, Alma McCoy; 
                  the mountain's name was later changed to Mount McCoy.</note></person>
               <person xml:id="Giles" source="#Bertrand #Passel #personnel eel-19410103"><persName>Giles, Walter R. <addName>Giles, W. R. </addName><addName type="nickname">Giles</addName></persName> 
                  <birth when="1912-01-03"><placeName>Newtown County, GA</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="1996-04-11"><placeName>Rockdale, GA</placeName> </death>
                  <occupation>Assistant Pilot and Radio Operator</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">Giles, whose name is often listed as W.R. Giles, was an assistant pilot and radio operator for West Base. 
                     He was part of the dog team that was transported back to West Base by Pete the day of the Condor incident on January 3, 1941.  At the time of the expedition, he 
                  was a Staff Sergeant (NAP) in the USMC. He achieved the rank of Colonel in the USMC.</note></person>
               <person xml:id="Ferranto" source="#FindAGrave #personnel">
                  <persName>Ferranto, Felix Louis</persName>
                  <birth when="1911-12-05"></birth>
                  <death when="2002-10-20"></death>
                  <occupation>USMC Radio Officer</occupation>
                  <state type="rank"><desc>Sergeant, USMC</desc></state>
                  <note type="biographical">Felix Ferranto was the radio operator for the Snow Cruiser. He achieved the 
                     rank of Lieutenant Colonel in the USMC. The Antarctic summit Mount Ferranto was named after him in
                     1947 <bibl><ref target="#MFerranto"><title level="a">Mount Ferranto,</title></ref> <ref target="#FindAGrave"><title level="a">Felix Louis Ferranto</title></ref></bibl>.</note>
               </person> 
               <person xml:id="Court" source="#Arnold #Malone">
                  <persName>Court, Arnold</persName>
                  <birth when="1914-06-20"><placeName ref="#Seattle">Seattle, WA</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="1999"></death>
                  <occupation>Climatologist/Meteorologist</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">Court was the Chief Meteorologist for the 1939-1941 expedition. 
                     Court and Lockhart took samples of the air and worked together to determine whether 
                     the air in Antarctica is oxygen deficient <bibl><ref target="#Arnold"><title level="a">Arnold Court,</title></ref> <ref target="#Malone">Malone, Thomas F., ed.></ref></bibl>.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="DocFrazier" source="#Russell">
                  <persName>Frazier, Dr. Russell G.</persName>
                  <birth when="1893-07-05"><placeName>Fraziers Bottom, WV</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="1968-01-14"><placeName>Salt Lake City, UT</placeName></death>
                  <occupation>Medical Doctor</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">Doc Frazier served as the physician for the 1939-1941 expedition. 
                     In addition to caring for those at West Base, he conducted research on how exposure to 
                     extreme cold for long periods of time affects the human body. The Antarctic peak Mount 
                     Frazier was named after him in 1947 <bibl><ref target="#MFrazier"><title level="a">Mount Frazier,</title></ref> <ref target="#Russell"><title level="a">Russell G. Frazier</title></ref></bibl>.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="mamma" source="#koulouris">
                  <persName>Westhaver, Celeste Althea <addName type="formal">Mrs. Clinton Daniel Lockhart</addName></persName>
                  <birth when="1880-10-23"></birth>
                  <death when="1957-10"></death>
                  <event type="marriage" when="1904-09-21"><desc>Celeste Althea Westhaver married Clinton Daniel Lockhart in Boston, Suffolk, MA, USA.</desc></event>
                  <note type="biographical">Celeste Althea Westhaver was Lockhart's mother. She and her 
                     husband were both born and raised in Nova Scotia, on opposite sides of the Bay of 
                     Fundy. In their 20s, both Celeste and Clinton immigrated to Boston. Whether they 
                     knew each other beforehand is unclear. While her son, Ernest Lockhart, was in 
                     Antarctica, Celeste Althea often corresponded with him via radiogram.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="clinton" source="#koulouris">
                  <persName>Lockhart, Clinton Daniel</persName>
                  <birth when="1880-12-23"></birth>
                  <death when="1964-05"></death>
                  <event type="marriage" when="1904-09-21"><desc>Clinton Daniel Lockhart married Celest Althea Westhaver in Boston, Suffold, MA, USA.</desc></event>
                  <note type="biographical">Clinton Daniel Lockhart was Lockhart's father. He and his wife
                  were both born and raised in Nova Scotia, on opposite sides of the Bay of Fundy. In their 20s, 
                  both Clinton and Delest immigrated to Boston, USA. Whether they knew each other before is unclear.
                  While his son, Ernest Lockhart, was in Antarctica, his wife often corresponded with him
                  via radiogram.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Beatie" source="#koulouris">
                  <persName>Lockhart, Beatrice R. <addName type="nickname">Beatie</addName></persName>
                  <birth when="1905-05"></birth>
                  <death when="1990-07"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">Beatrice had two younger brothers: Clinton Carl and Ernest Earl. 
                     While Ernest was in Antarctica, he and Beatie often corresponded via radiogram.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Hawthorne" source="#personnel #ExploratoryFlights">
                  <persName>Hawthorne, Roger</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="not before 1945"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Recorder of the Expedition</occupation>
                  <residence when="1940">Middleboro, Massachusetts</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Roger Hawthorne was the Recorder of the Expedition and later
                  published an essay on the expedition for the American Philosophical Society entitled 
                  "Exploratory Flights of Admiral Byrd (1940)." Lockhart distrusted him because he believed
                  Hawthorne was in league with Byrd in exaggerating the dangers of their expedition for publicity purposes.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Tony" source="#Passel #personnel #MColombo">
                  <persName>Colombo, Louis P.<addName type="nickname">Tony</addName></persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Supply Man, Assistant Mechanic</occupation>
                  <residence when="1940">Astoria, New York</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Louis "Tony" Colombo, a member of the biological party of the West Base, is listed as being the "supply man" as 
                     well as the assistant mechanic in varying sources <bibl><ref target="#Passel"><title level="m">Ice: The Antarctic Diary of Charles F. Passel</title></ref>; <ref target="#personnel"><title level="u">"Personnel, 1939-1940"</title></ref></bibl>. 
                     Mount Colombo, a mountain in the Ford Ranges, was later named for him <bibl><ref target="#MColombo"><title level="a">Mount Colombo</title></ref></bibl>.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Asman" source="#Passel #personnel #AsmanR #White">
                  <persName>Asman, Adam<addName type="nickname">Sgt., Nib, Nibble</addName></persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Tank Driver</occupation>
                  <residence>Westerfield, Massachusetts</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">In Charles Passel's personal account of his experiences during the 1939-41 expedition, he refers to Asman as "Sgt."; 
                     presumably Asman was a member of the US army <bibl><ref target="#Passel"><title level="m">Ice: The Antarctic Diary of Charles F. Passel</title></ref></bibl>. As a member of the U.S. Antarctic Service (USAS) West Base party, during the expedition he served 
                     as the army tank driver <bibl><ref target="#personnel"><title level="u">"Personnel, 1939-1940"</title></ref></bibl>. He mentioned in a newspaper article written in 1944, as having special assignment in the Arctic with Byrd testing army 
                     tanks under extreme conditions <bibl><ref target="#White"><title level="a">Byrd Expeditions Paying Off Today On Our Frozen Fronts</title></ref></bibl>. Later Asman Ridge, a ridge on the south side of Arthur glacier, was named for Asman <bibl><ref target="#AsmanR"><title level="a">Asman Ridge</title></ref></bibl>.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Mary" source="#eel-19410110 #koulouris">
                     <persName>Guernsey, Mary</persName>
                     <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                     <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                     <event type="marriage" when="1940-10-25"><desc>Mary Guernsey married Clinton Carl Lockhart</desc></event>
                     <note type="biographical">Mary was Dr. Lockhart's sister in law. She also sent correspondence to Lockhart through both mail and radiograms 
                     with her husband Carl.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Carl" source="#eel-19410110 #koulouris">
                   <persName>Lockhart, Clinton Carl</persName>
                   <birth when="1907-01-25"></birth>
                   <death when="2000-12-07"></death>
                   <event type="marriage" when="1940-10-25"><desc>Clinton Carl Lockhart married Mary Guersey</desc></event>
                   <note type="biographical">Carl was Dr. Lockhart's brother. He also sent correspondence to Lockhart through both mail and radiograms
                   with his wife Mary.</note>
               </person>
               
               <person xml:id="CharlesFord" source="#eel-19401228a">
                  <persName>Ford, Charles</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">It is unknown whether, at this time, he had any other occupation beyond being an author.</occupation>
                  <residence when="1940">Unknown</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Author of the book "Death Sails with Magellan," published in 1937, which Dr. Lockhart reads during the expedition.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Van" source="#eel-19410110" >
                  <persName>Van</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">Sent correspondence to Lockhart.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="BuckBoyd" source="#Passel #personnel #BoydG">
                  <persName>Boyd, Vernon D.<addName type="nickname">Buck</addName></persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Master Mechanic</occupation>
                  <residence>Uniontown, Pennsylvania</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Vernon "Buck" Boyd, a member of the 1939-41 U.S. Antarctic Service (USAS) West Base <bibl><ref target="#personnel"><title level="u">"Personnel, 1939-1940"</title></ref></bibl>. According to Charles Passel's 
                     personnel account of the expedition, Boyd is listed as the "master mechanic" <bibl><ref target="#Passel"><title level="m">Ice: The Antarctic Diary of Charles F. Passel</title></ref></bibl>. A glacier flowing between Bailey Ridge and Mount Douglass in 
                     the Ford Ranges was later named Boyd Glacier for him <bibl><ref target="#BoydG"><title level="a">Boyd Glacier</title></ref></bibl>.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Vivian" source="#eel-19410110" >
                  <persName>Vivian</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">Sent correspondence to Lockhart.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="BillLeckie" source="#eel-19410427">
                  <persName>Leckie, William<addName type="nickname">Bill</addName></persName>
                  <birth when-custom="uknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1941">Unknown</occupation>
                  <residence>Unknown</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">In 1941, the Dept. of the Interior authorized a radiogram sent to Dr. Lockhart from William Leckie, in which
                     Leckie asked for Lockhart's opinion of Harris Food Mixture, a form of nourishment
                     that was presumably used in Antarctic expeditions.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Dave" source="#eel-19410110">
                  <persName>Dave</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">Sent correspondence to Lockhart.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Klondicke" source="#Passel #personnel #MBerlin">
                  <persName>Berlin, Leonard M.<addName type="nickname">Klondicke, Len</addName></persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Cadastral Engineer</occupation>
                  <residence when="1940">Juneau, Alaska</residence>
                  <note type="biographical"> Leonard "Klondicke" Berlin, a member of the 1939-41 U.S. Antarctic Service (USAS) West Base, 
                     was a cadastral engineer on the expedition according to Charles Passel's personal account 
                     <bibl><ref target="#Passel"><title level="m">Ice: The Antarctic Diary of Charles F. Passel</title></ref>; <ref target="#personnel"><title level="u">"Personnel, 1939-1940"</title></ref></bibl>. Mount Berlin, formerly Mount Hal Flood, 
                     was named for Berlin <bibl><ref target="#MBerlin"><title level="a">Mount Berlin</title></ref></bibl>.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Henry" source="#eel-19410110">
                  <persName>Henry</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">Sent correspondence to Lockhart.</note>
               </person>
               
               <person xml:id="Trefts">
                  <persName>Trefts, George W.</persName>
                  <birth when="1919"></birth>
                  <death when="1994"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">military personnel</occupation>
               </person>
               
               <person xml:id="Schlossbach">
                  <persName>Schlossbach, Isaac <addName type="nickname">Lt., Cmdr., Ike, </addName></persName>
                  <birth when="1891-08-20"><placeName>Bradley Beach, NJ</placeName></birth>
                  <death when="1984"><placeName>Bradley Beach, NJ</placeName></death>
                  <occupation> American Polar Explorer, submariner and aviation pioneer and Navigator.</occupation>
                  <note type="biographical">American Polar Explorer, submariner and aviation pioneer and Navigator. Ike Schlossbach is referenced as "Schlossback" within the Journals written by Lockhart.</note>
               </person>
                  <person xml:id="Wiener" source="#personnel">
                     <persName>Wiener, Murray</persName>
                  <birth when="1909" precision="low"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Physicist and Dog Doctor</occupation>
                  <residence>130 Main St  Bradley Beach, NJ</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Wiener was a member of the west base along side Lockhart. He is often mentioned in the journal, and is believe to be the person behind the influence of the nickname Fort Wiener in the journal.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Dot" source="#eel-19410110">
                  <persName>Dot</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note>Sent correspondence to Lockhart</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Bailey">
                  <persName>Bailey, Clay w.</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1939">Radio Chief</occupation>
                  <residence>Belmont, Mass</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Clay Bailey was a commander in the United States Navy and member of the Byrd Antarctic
                  Expedition. In 1939 until 1941, Bailey served as a radio chief for Rare Radio for the West Base Party of the 
                  United States Antarctic Service.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Siple" source="#personnel #WikiSiple">
                  <persName>Siple, Dr. Paul A</persName>
                  <birth when="1908">December 18, 1908</birth>
                  <death when="1968">November 25, 1968 </death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Base Leader</occupation>
                  <residence>1158 W. 5th Street Erie, PA</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Dr. Siple was base leader at the west base. He is often referred to as Siple, but is also the same person called Paul in the Lockhart journal.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Elenore" source="#eel-19410110">
                  <persName>Elenore</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">Sent correspondence to Lockhart.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id= "Douglas">
                  <persName>Douglas, Doug</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Joe">
                  <persName>Wells, Joe</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
               </person>
               
               <person xml:id="Wade" source="#Passel">
                  <persName>Wade, Dr. Franklin Alton</persName>
                  <birth when="1903" precision="low"></birth>
                  <death when="1978" precision="low"></death>
                  <occupation>Senior Scientist and Geographer</occupation>
                  <residence>Oxford, Oh</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Doctor Wade was the Senior Scientist and a member of the Snow Cruiser Unit.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Jenene" source="#eel-19410110 #koulouris">
                  <persName>Lockhart, Jenene</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <note type="biographical">She was Dr. Lockhart's first cousin and also sent correspondence to Lockhart.</note>
               </person>
               
               <person xml:id="Malcolm" source="#personnel">
                  <persName>Douglass, Malcolm C.</persName>
                  <birth when-custom="unknown"></birth>
                  <death when-custom="unknown"></death>
                  <occupation when="1940">Sled Dog Driver</occupation>
                  <residence>East Orange, N.J.</residence>
                  <note type="biographical">Malcolm was a sled dog driver on the Expedition who at one point
                  expressed his mood by stating that he may just walk off the base, suggesting suicidal
                  thoughts.</note></person>
                  <person xml:id="MargaretMann" source="eel-19410116"> <persName>Mann, Margaret</persName>
               <birth>unknown</birth> <death>unknown</death> <note type="biographical">Sent radiograms to Lockhart. No other information is known about this person.</note></person>
               <person xml:id="Daumcarden" source="#eel-19410116"> <persName>Daumcarden</persName>
               <birth>unknown</birth>
               <death>unknown</death>
               <note type="biographical">Mentioned in radiogram sent to Lockhart by Margaret Mann. No other information has been found about this person.</note></person>
            </listPerson>
            
            <listPerson type="editors">
               <head>Editors</head>
               <person xml:id="HLU">
                  <persName>Ulman, H. Lewis</persName>
                  <birth when="1952">
                     <placeName>Williamsport, PA</placeName>
                  </birth>
                  <education>BA, Lycoming College (1974)</education>
                  <education>MA, The Pennsylvania State University (1980)</education>
                  <education>PhD, The Pennsylvania State University (1985)</education>
                  <occupation>College Professor</occupation>
                  <nationality>U.S.A.</nationality>
                  <note type="biographical">H. Lewis Ulman is Associate Professor of English at The Ohio State
                     University and Director of Digital Media Studies in the Department of English.
                     He has edited <title level="m">The Minutes of the Aberdeen Philosophical Society, 1758–1773</title>
                     (Aberdeen University Press, 1990) and, with Dennis Quon, “Semiotics in
                     Eighteenth-century Aberdeen: Thomas Gordon’s Contributions to the Aberdeen
                     Philosophical Society” (<title level="m">Studies on Voltaire and the Eighteenth-Century</title> 317
                     (1994): 57–115). He is also the author of <title level="m">Things, Thoughts, Words and Actions:
                     The Problem of Language in Late Eighteenth-Century British Rhetorical Theory</title>
                     (Southern Illinois University Press, 1994). Since 2005, he has worked with
                     undergraduate and graduate students in textual editing courses to create a
                     series of electronic textual editions of nineteenth- and early
                     twentieth-century American manuscripts in the Rare Books and Manuscripts
                     Library at Ohio State. An example of that work can be viewed online at
                     http://people.cohums.ohio-state.edu/ulman1/SSCoxJournal/. Beginning with an NEH
                     Digital Humanities Start-Up Grant awarded in 2008, he has collaborated with
                     Melanie Schlosser, metadata librarian at Ohio State University Libraries, to
                     build a model of preservation for distributed, multimodal digital humanities
                     projects. He is delighted to be working at a time when manuscript, print, and
                     digital media can be studied in relationship to one another, allowing him and
                     his students to learn more about all three media than they could by studying
                     any one in isolation.</note>                
               </person>
               <person xml:id="RSL">
                  <persName>Layfield, Rachel</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Rachel Layfield is a third-year English major who is 
                     minoring in both Professional Writing and French. Post-graduation, she plans to 
                     earn her MLS and become a librarian.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="AK">
                  <persName>Keep, Alan</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Alan Keep is a senior English major with a minor in Sexuality Studies. 
                     After graduation he plans to enroll in Kent State's MLS program and become a librarian. </note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="ME">
                  <persName>Edison, Meg</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Meg Edison is a second-year English and History major at 
                     The Ohio State University.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="FP">
                  <persName>Pellicciaro, Francis</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Francis Pellicciaro is a sophomore at The Ohio State University,
                     majoring in English and journalism. He is a native of Seaford, New York. Following Graduation, 
                     he hopes to make a living writing.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="CH">
                  <persName>Hurdley, Caitlin</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Caitlin Hurdley is a senior English major, minoring in 
                  Cultural Anthropology at The Ohio State University. Following graduation, her goal is
                  to see the world as an English as a Second Language teacher.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="AJW">
                  <persName>Waisanen, Adam J</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Adam Waisanen is a third-year History major at The Ohio State
                  University. He has currently served in the U.S. Military for over eleven years. After 
                  graduation he plans earn a Masters in Library Science to become either an archivist or
                  a librarian.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="Kathy">
                  <persName>Mielecki, Kathy</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Kathy is a librarian from Chicago (MLS, Dominican University) who is taking courses as a non-degree student in digital media and literacy.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="tamika">
                  <persName>Smith, Tamika</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Tamika Smith is a third-year English major, minoring in Political
                  Science at The Ohio State University. Following her undergraduate graduation, she plans on 
                  attending graduate school and eventually persuing a career in Print and Magazine editing.</note>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="moriah">
                  <persName>Cheatham, Moriah</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Moriah is a junior English major, minoring in Youth
                     Development at The Ohio State University. After obtaining her degree, Moriah
                     plans on pursuing law school in the hopes of working at juvenile
                     court.</note>
               </person>
               <person>
                  <persName>Cahill, Erin Kathleen</persName>
                  <note type="biographical">Erin is an English graduate student at the Ohio State University focusing on composition, digital media, 
                  and folklore.</note>
               </person>
            </listPerson>
            
            <listPlace>
               <head>Places Mentioned in Ernest E. Lockhart's Journal</head>
               <place type="city" xml:id="Boston" source="#TGN">
                  <placeName>Boston</placeName>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <region type="state">Massachusetts</region>
                  <desc>Lockhart's birthplace.</desc>
                  <location><geo>40.0667 -82.8000</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="WestDennis" source="#TGN">
                  <placeName>West Dennis</placeName>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <region type="state">Massachusetts</region>
                  <desc>Lockhart's home on Cape Cod, Massachusetts, to which he retired and where he died in 2006</desc>
                  <location><geo>39.1500 -84.4500</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="range" xml:id="HalFlood" source="#FloodRange">
                  <placeName>Hal Flood</placeName>
                  <country>Antarctic</country>
                  <desc>Range of snow covered mountains. Reconnaissance flights by the United Antarctic Service (1939-41), 
                     of which Lockhart was a member, explored the range. The principle mountain was named "Mount Hal Flood" 
                     (later changed to Mount Berlin) by Admiral Byrd for his uncle, the Hon. Henry D. Flood, U.S. Senator 
                     from Virginia. The name was later applied to the entire range.</desc>
                  <location><geo>-76.0300 -134.3000</geo></location>
                  </place>
               
               <place type="address" xml:id="ArlingtonStreet" source="#eel-19401226a">
                  <placeName>Arlington Street</placeName>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <region type="city">Hyde Park</region>
                  <region type="state">Massachusetts</region>
                  <desc>The home of the Mahan family. Mr. Mahan, the father of Lockhart's friend Jack, passed away while Lockhart was in Antarctica.
                   Lockhart sends a radiogram expressing his condolences to Mrs. Mahan at Arlington Street.</desc>
                  <location><geo>42.2595897 -71.11632</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="country" xml:id="NewZealand" source="#TGN">
                  <placeName>New Zealand</placeName>
                  <desc>Island nation of the Southwest Pacific. The Bear is mentioned having just 
                     left New Zealand on its way to Antarctica early in the journal</desc>
                  <location><geo>-42.0000 174.0000</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="country" xml:id="Canada" source="#TGN">
                 <placeName>Canada</placeName> 
                  <desc>North American nation to the north of the United States. Lockhart expresses a desire to go camping, and considers Canada to be a 
                     prime location for camp sites</desc>
                  <location><geo>60.0000 -096.0000</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="Atlanta" source="#TGN">
                  <placeName>Atlanta</placeName>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <region type="state">Georgia</region>
                  <region type="county">Fulton</region>
                  <desc>Lockhart discusses Sherman's burning of Atlanta when talking about his 
                     reactions to Gone with the Wind</desc>
                  <location><geo>33.7333 -84.3833</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="address" xml:id="UplandRoad" source="#TGN">
                  <placeName>7 Upland Road</placeName>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <region type="city">Wellesley</region>
                  <region type="state">Massachusetts</region>
                  <desc>The address of The Guernsey Family</desc>
               </place>
           
               <place type="cache" xml:id="depot105" source="#Passel #Bertrand #TGN #eel-19401226a">
                  
                 <placeName>105-Mile Depot</placeName>
                  <country>Antarctica</country>
                  <desc>Cache and depot established 105 miles east of West Base and 10 miles south
                     of Breckenridge Peak Rockefeller Mountains. It was named because of its distance from West Base.
                     The depot was established prior to the sledge journeys so the parties could restock supplies and dog food.
                     Other caches of dog food were also established between West Base and Depot 105.
                     Lockhart refers to it as 105; Passel calls it 105 Mile Cache, and Bertrand refers to it as 105-Mile Depot.</desc>
               <location><geo>-78.279767 -155.535556</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="Valparaiso" source="#Bertrand #TGN #eel-19410115a #eel-19401231a #eel-19410116">
                  <placeName>Valparaiso <addName>Valpo</addName></placeName>
                  <country>Chile</country>
                  <desc>Supplies, including the Condor plane, were loaded at Valparaiso, and mail was available for the crew from people
                     who had not been able to send mail on the Star before it departed. 
                     Lockhart's ship passed through Valpo, Panama, and Seattle on his way home.</desc>
                  <location><geo>-33.0478 -71.6011</geo></location></place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="Dunedin" source="#Bertrand #TGN #eel-19410115a #eel-19410116a"><placeName>Dunedin</placeName>
                  <country>New Zealand</country>
                  <desc>The Star spent several days in Dunedin on its way to West Base to pick up the crew. 
                  According to Lockhart it took about 10 days to travel from Dunedin to West Base.</desc>
                  <location><geo>-45.8667 170.5000</geo></location>
                  </place>
               
               <place type="country" xml:id="Panama" source="#eel-journal2-radiograms #TGN">
                  <placeName>Panama</placeName>
                  <desc>Lockhart talks about traveling back through Panama on his return trip in several radiograms.</desc>
                  <location><geo>8.537981 -80.782127</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               
               <place type="geography" xml:id="LittleAmerica">
                 <placeName>Little America</placeName>
                  <region type="harbor">Bay of Whales</region>
                  <desc>Little America was used as an Antarctic Exploration Base which Lockhart periodically references
                  within his journals.</desc>
                  <location><geo>-77.0000 -162.0000</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="interstate" xml:id="Route90">
                  <placeName>U.S Route 90</placeName>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <desc>U.S Route 90 is a United States highway which spans east-west. "90" is reference by Lockhart in his
                  journals when he talks about the Tractor Party"s route returning to base. </desc>
               </place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="helsinki" source="#eel-19401231e #TGN">
                  <placeName>Helsinki</placeName>
                  <country>Finland</country>
                  <desc>Located on peninsula in Gulf of Finland. In a radiogram to Dr. Lockhart, his mother writes of having 'snaps' 
                     he had taken in "helsiki" enlarged; presumably "helsiki" refers to the Finnish city, Helsinki. According to Paul Koulouris,
                     Dr. Lockhart worked in Sweden from September 1938 to July 1939, and took time off to travel in the summer of 1939; it is likely 
                     that during this time Dr. Lockhart went to Finland, and that the enlargements thus mentioned by Dr. Lockhart's mother were of photos 
                     taken during this trip. Koulouris mentions that Lockhart had a good camera; in one letter Dr. Lockhart mentions taking over 500 photos.</desc>
                  <location><geo>60.1333 25.0000</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="Mattapan" source="#personnel #eel-19401226 #eel-19410104a #koulouris">
                 	<placeName>Mattapan</placeName>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <region type="county">Suffolk</region>
                  <region type="state">Massachusetts</region>
                  <desc>A suburb of Boston, MA where Mamma and Beatie lived. Dr. Lockhart is also listed as living here, 
                     and this is where the three Lockhart children grew up.</desc>
                  <location><geo>42.27715 -71.091539</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="Cleveland" source="#TGN">
                 <placeName>Cleveland, Ohio</placeName> 
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <region type="state">Ohio</region>
                  <region type="county">Cuyahoga</region>
                  <location><geo>41.482222, -81.669722</geo></location>
                  <desc>There are four radiograms here involving Cleveland; one that Lockhart sent and three that he received.
                       These radiograms are all between Lockhart and Margaret Mann/Mrs. W.H. Mann. These two are likely the same person. Weather or not this was thrut, the woman lived in Cleveland. 
                       Note that the radiogram sent by Lockhart was to Mrs. W.H. but the ones received were from Margaret. Also note that the four radiograms are not necessarily on any order.
                       In these radiograms, she and Lockhart mostly talk about holiday wishes and when his coming return.</desc>
              </place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="richmond">
                 <placeName>Richmond, Indiana</placeName> 
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <region type="state">Indiana</region>
                  <location><geo>39.830189, -84.890668</geo></location>
               </place>
               <place type="state" xml:id="Florida" source="#TGN">
                 <placeName type="state">Florida</placeName>
                 <country>United States</country>
                 <location><geo>28.1000, -81.6000</geo></location>
                 <desc>Lockhart mentions Florida in talking about the books he has been reading, which have taken place in the south.
                 He mentions South Moon Under which takes place in Florida.</desc> 
               </place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="Balboa" source="#TGN">
                 <placeName type="city">Balboa</placeName> 
                 <country>Roublic of Panama</country>
                 <region type="geographic">Central America</region>
                  <location><geo>8.9500 -79.5667</geo></location>
                  <desc>Balboa is mentioned along with Valparaiso as a stopover city for mail going to the Antarctic 
                  expedition, as well as the place where journalists wanted to interview Lockhart</desc>
               </place>
               
               <place type="base" xml:id="EastBase" source="#James">
                  <placeName>East Base</placeName>
                  <country>Antarctica</country>
                  <desc>East Base is a U.S. station located near Margeurite Bay on Stonington Island.   
                     It was established in March 1940 and has been used as a base only once since then 
                     (by the Ronne Antarctic Research Expedition in January 1948). During the 1939-1941
                     expedition, Richard Black of the US Navy was the East Base commander.</desc>
                  <location><geo>-68.193247 -67.014542</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="geography" xml:id="SouthPole" source="#National">
                  <placeName>South Pole</placeName>
                  <country>Antarctica</country>
                  <desc>Though in fact a very specific location, the term "south pole" was used colloquially in 
                     radiograms to refer to the entire continent of Antarctica and the bases where the expedition
                     took place. The 1939-1941 expedition did not reach the South Pole, nor was it intended to do so.</desc>
                  <location><geo>90.0000 0.0000</geo></location>
               </place>
               
               <place type="city" xml:id="Wellesley" source="#TGN #eel-19410103a">
                  <placeName>Wellesley</placeName>
                  <region type="state">Massachusetts</region>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <desc>Home of the Guernsey family.</desc>
                  <location><geo>42.2833 -71.2833</geo></location>
               </place>
               <place type="unknown" xml:id="FortWiener" source="#eel-19401225a">
                  <placeName>Fort Wiener</placeName>
                  <country>Antarctica</country>
                  <desc>More than likely the barracks or tent of Murray Wiener. There is not mention of an actual Fort Wiener beyond this journal that can be found, therefore leading to the belief that this location is actually a nickname for the barracks or a tent of Murry Wiener.</desc>
                  <location cert="unknown"></location>
               </place>
               <place type="city" xml:id="HydePark" source="#eel-journal2-radiograms #eel-19401226b">
                  <placeName>Hyde Park</placeName>
                  <region type="state">Massachusetts</region>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <desc>Home of the Mahan family that Lockhart was close to. They lived on Arlington Street.</desc>
                  <location><geo>42.2556° N, 71.1244° W</geo></location>
               </place>
               <place type="city" xml:id="Wilmington" source="#eel-19401231">
                  <placeName>Wilmington, Delaware</placeName>
                  <region type="state">Delaware</region>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <desc>Wilmington is the home of Mary and Carl, his brother and sister-in-law, that Lockhart receives radiograms from.</desc>
                  <location><geo>39.7458° N, 75.5467° W</geo></location>
               </place>
               <place type="geography" xml:id="Equator" source="#eel-19410113a">
                  <placeName>Equator</placeName>
                  <location><geo>0° latitude</geo></location>
                  <desc>The equator was to be a set location to compare air samples against, though it is unclear if these samples were taken.</desc>
               </place>
               <place type="geography" xml:id="BayofWhales" source="#TGN">
                  <placeName>Bay of Whales</placeName>
                  <location><geo>78.3000° S, 164.2000° W</geo></location>
                  <desc>The Bay is where the ships did their loading and unloading and were also stored here for the duration of the Expedition</desc>
               </place>
               <place type="city" xml:id="Seattle" source="#TGN">
                  <placeName>Seattle</placeName>
                  <location><geo>47.6097° N, 122.333°1 W</geo></location>
                  <region type="state">Washington</region>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <desc>This was to be the final destination for The Star before it was redirected to join The Bear in Boston.</desc>
               </place>
               <place type="city" xml:id="KansasCity" source="#DailySentinel #Saratogian">
                  <placeName>Kansas City</placeName>
                  <location><geo>39.0997° N, 94.5786° W</geo></location>
                  <region type="state">Missouri</region>
                  <country>United States</country>
                  <desc>The Kansas City Star, a local news source, sent a radio salute to the members of the
                  expedition via WEAF-NBC at 11:30 pm Central Time on the evening of 3 January 1941.</desc>
               </place>
               
            </listPlace>
            
            
            
            <listOrg>
               <head>List of Organizations Mentioned in Ernest E. Lockhart's Journal</head>
              <org xml:id="AARS" source="#QST">
                 <orgName>Army Amateur Radio System</orgName>
                 <state type="company">
                    <desc>
                       The Army Amature Radio System was an organization of amature radio operators that would send and receive radio messages for the military.
                    </desc>
                 </state>
                 <desc>
                    The AARS sent and received messages between members of the Expedition and their families back home. Once the message was recorded in the states, it was
                    then mailed out to the family members. The family members could then respond with a written letter that would then be transmitted back to the Expedition.
                 </desc>
              </org>
               <org xml:id="WLMC" source="#QST">
                  <orgName>WLMC</orgName>
                  <state type="operator">
                     <desc>
                        WLMC was operated by Edward J. Day as part of the Army Amature Radio System during the time of the Expedition.
                     </desc>
                  </state>
                  <desc>
                     WLMC appears to be the only operator in the United States who received and transcribed radiograms for the Expedition.
                     Between November 25 1939 to May 4 1941, this station processed around 15,000 messages to and from the Expedition.
                  </desc>
               </org>
               <org xml:id="Colliers">
                  <orgName>Collier's Weekly</orgName>
                  <state type="company">
                     <desc>
                        A magazine famous for running articles about social issues from the 20s on, also featured serialized stories
                     </desc>
                  </state>
                  <desc>
                     Lockhart was asked about being interviewed for a story in Colliers, which ran weekly serial stories as well as exposés and "muckraking" articles about working conditions in factories, 
                     trusts, etc. Lockhart would have been interviewed about his experiences with Harris Food Mixture, but it seems that no such article ended up printed.
                  </desc>
                  </org>
               <org xml:id="BostonTraveler" source="#Traveler">
                  <orgName>Boston Traveler</orgName>
                  <state type="company"></state>
                     <desc>A daily newspaper based in Boston, Massachusetts, it ran from 1914-1967, and was published by Boston Herald, Inc 
                        <bibl><ref target="#Traveler"><title level="a">"About the Boston traveler"</title></ref></bibl>. In his journal, Lockhart mentions that the newspaper is sponsoring a mail bag to be delivered to the base camps.</desc>
               </org>
               <org xml:id="USDptoftheInt" source="#eel-19410427 #Richard">
                  <orgName>US Department of the Interior</orgName>
                  <state type="government"></state>
                  <desc>Per President Roosevelt's suggestion, the Department of the Interior was one of the 
                     departments that helped plan and fund the 1939-1941 expedition. It was too great a task for any one
                     department to finance independently. Sponsors included the DOI, the US Navy, the US State 
                     Department, the US Department of the Treasury, and various private citizens and organizations.
                     In 1941, the DOI authorized a radiogram sent to Dr. Lockhart from William Leckie. In this
                     radiogram, Leckie asked for Lockhart's opinion of Harris Food Mixture, a form of nourishment
                     that was presumably easily transported and was therefore used in Antarctic expeditions.</desc>
               </org>
               <org xml:id="ThePolarTimes" source="#PolarTimes">
                  <orgName>The Polar Times</orgName>
                  <state type="company"></state>
                  <desc>The Polar Times was produced as an inhouse magazine during discovery expedition to Antarctica.
                     The original purpose is to maintain morale and document the lives and work of the people on the expedition.</desc>
               </org>
            </listOrg>
            
<!--            
             <listEvent>
               <event when="1940-01-01">
                  <label>Label</label>
                  <desc>description</desc>
               </event>
            </listEvent>
-->            
            <listBibl>
               
               <!-- Though TEI provides for more fine-grained encoding, we will enter bibliography items
            as we would expect them to be displayed, except for noting text that requires special
            formatting (e.g., titles). -->
               
               <head>Works Cited</head>
               <bibl xml:id="koulouris" n="koulouris">Koulouris, Paul. "Lockhart Info.doc." Message to the editors. 10 March 2013. E-mail attachment. Earl Lockhart's nephews,
                  Paul Koulouris and George Lockhart, as well as George Lockhart's mother, Mary Guernsey Lockhart, provided the editors with biographical details about
                  the Lockhart family.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="LyonDarwin" n="Homo vs. Darwin">Lyon, William Penman <title level="a">Homo versus Darwin : a judicial examination of statements recently published by Mr. Darwin regarding "The descent of man."</title> <title level="s">Archive.org</title> 
                  Philadelphia: Claxton, Remsen and Haffelfinger, 1872. Web. 24 March 2014.  https://archive.org/details/homoversusdarwin00lyonrich</bibl>
              <bibl xml:id="Florio" n="RunUntilDead">Florio, Marget <title level="a">Run... Until... Dead...: A Brief History of the Polar Expedition Dog</title>
                 Mercersburg, Pennsylvania: The Polar Press, 2010. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="WikiGWTW" n="Gone With the Wind"><title level="a">Gone With the Wind</title><title level="s">Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</title>
                  http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gone_with_the_Wind 18 Mar 2014. Web. 18 Mar 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="GMTAntarctica" n="AntarcticaStandardTime"><title level="a">Antarctica</title><title level="s">Greenwich Mean Time</title>
                  http://wwp.greenwichmeantime.com/time-zone/antarctica/ Web. 18 Mar 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Magellan" n="FordMagellan">Ford, Charles.<title level="a">Death Sails with Magellan</title><title level="s">Hathi Trust</title>
                  http://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=mdp.39015059400450;view=1up;seq=8 Web. 18 Mar 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="WikiBursey" n="JackBursey"><title level="a">Jack Bursey</title><title level="s">Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</title> 
                  http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Bursey 19 Nov 2012 Web. 27 Feb 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Allen" n="Allen">Allen, Glover M.<title level="m">Extinct And Vanishing Mammals of the Western Hemisphere</title>
               Pennsylvania: The Intelligence Printing Company, 1942. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Ronne" n="Ronne">Ronne, Finn. <title level="m">Antarctica My Destiny</title>. New
                  York: Hastings House, 1979. Print.
               </bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Passel" n="Passel">Passel, Charles F. <title level="m">Ice: The Antarctic Diary of Charles F. Passel</title>. Ed.
                  T. H. Baughman. Lubbock, TX: Texas Tech UP, 1995. Print.
               </bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Stefansson" n="Stefansson">Stefansson, Vilhjalmur. <title level="m">Hunters of the Great North</title>. 
                  New York: Harcourt, Brace, and Company, 1922. Print.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="watermarks" n="paper"><title level="m">Paper Watermarks</title>. N. p. 25 August 2007. Web. 27 January 2014.
                  &lt;http://www.watermarks.info/indexi.htm&gt;</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Field-news" n="Greetings"><title level="a">Greetings Received at Museum
               from Byrd Expedition.</title> <title level="j">Field Museum News</title> Feb. 1940: 8. Print.
                  Available through the <title level="m">Biodiversity Heritage Library</title>
                  at http://www.biodiversitylibrary.org/item/25715#page/16/mode/1up.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="QST" n="Bailey">Bailey, Clay W.<title level="a">U.S. Antarctic Service Expresses Appreciation</title>
               <title level="j"> QST</title> November 1941. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Lockhart1942" n="Lockhart">Lockhart, Ernest E.<title level="a">Oxygen Deficiency in Antarctic Air</title><title level="j">Monthly Weather Review</title>
               May 1942. Print.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="personnel" n="personnel"><title level="u">Personnel, 1939-1940</title>. 1939-40. TS. Papers
               of Admiral Richard E. Byrd. Series II: Expeditionary Records. Sub-Series 6: United States Antarctic Services. 
               Box 203, Folder 7234, Location: 054-774.20-4. The Byrd Polar Research Center Archival Program, The Ohio State
               University Libraries, Columbus, OH.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Blondie" n="Blondie"><title level="m">Blondie</title>. Dir. Frank R. Strayer. Perf.
                  Penny Singleton, Arthur Lake, and Larry Simms. Columbia Pictures, 1938. Film.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Stark" n="Stark">Stark, David. <title level="a">Admiral Richard H. Cruzen -- A Biography.</title>
               <title level="m">Gallatin</title>. Davis County Historical Society. Gallatin, MO. 2 May 2004. Web. 12 Feb. 2014.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="TGN" n="Getty">Getty Research Institute. <title level="m">Getty
                  Thesaurus of Geographic Names Online.</title> N.d. Web. 12 Feb. 2014.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="ANB" n="American National Biography"><title level="a">Sherman, William Tecumseh</title>
                  <title level="m">American National Biography</title> Oxford University Press 2010 Web. 22 Feb. 2014</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Card" n="The Garnsey-Guernsey Family Genealogy">Card, Eva Louise Garnsey and Guernsey, Howard Abram <title level="m">The Garnsey-Guernsey Genealogy: An Account of Thirteen Generations 
                  of Descendants from Henry Garnsey (---- -1692)of Dorchester, Mass., and Joseph Guernsie-Garnsey (---- -1688) of Stamford, Conn </title> <title level="s">Hathi Trust</title> Urbana, Ill. 
                  : E. and L. Card, 1963. Web. 25th Feb 2014
                  </bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Unz" n="Unz.org">Unz, Robert <title level="s">Collier's</title> <title level="m">Unz.org</title>Web. 25 Feb. 2014</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="LOC" n="Library">The Library of Congress. <title level="m">Library of Congress Authorities</title>. 
                  6 Jan. 2012. Web. 12 Feb. 2014.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Traveler" n="LOC"> The Library of Congress. <title level="a">About the Boston traveler.</title> <title level="m">Chronicling America.</title> 
                  n.d. Web. 26 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn91057123/&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="MPerkins" n="Mount"><title level="a">Mount Perkins.</title> <title level="m">Geographical Names Information System (GNIS)</title>. United States
                  Geological Survey. N. d. Web. 12 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://geonames.usgs.gov/pls/gnispublic/f?p=gnispq:5:::NO::P5_ANTAR_ID:11624&gt;.</bibl> 
               
               <bibl xml:id="MFerranto" n="Mount"><title level="a">Mount Ferranto.</title> <title level="m">Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</title>. United States 
                  Geological Survey, n.d. Web. 26 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://geonames.usgs.gov/apex/f?p=136:3:0::NO::P3_ANTAR_ID,P3_TITLE:4843,Mount%20Ferranto&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="MFrazier" n="Mount"><title level="a">Mount Frazier.</title> <title level="m">Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</title>. United States 
                  Geological Survey, n.d. Web. 26 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://geonames.usgs.gov/apex/f?p=136:3:0::NO::P3_ANTAR_ID,P3_TITLE:5262,Mount%20Frazier&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="NatGeo" n="Skua"><title level="a">Arctic Skua.</title> <title level="m">National Geographic.</title> National Geographic. n.d. Web.
                  23 March 2014. &lt;http://animals.nationalgeographic.com/animals/birds/arctic-skua/&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="MColombo" n="Mount"><title level="a">Mount Colombo.</title> <title level="m">Geographical Names Information System (GNIS)</title>. United States
                  Geological Survey. n.d. Web. 28 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://geonames.usgs.gov/apex/f?p=136:3:0::NO::P3_ANTAR_ID,P3_TITLE:2978,Mount%20Colombo&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="AsmanR" n="Ridge"><title level="a">Asman Ridge.</title> <title level="m">Geographical Names Information System (GNIS)</title>. United States
                  Geological Survey. n.d. Web. 28 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://geonames.usgs.gov/apex/f?p=136:3:0::NO::P3_ANTAR_ID,P3_TITLE:653,Asman%20Ridge&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="BoydG" n="Glacier"><title level="a">Boyd Glacier.</title> <title level="m">Geographical Names Information System (GNIS)</title>. United States
                  Geological Survey. n.d. Web. 28 Feb. 2014 &lt;http://geonames.usgs.gov/apex/f?p=136:3:0::NO::P3_ANTAR_ID,P3_TITLE:1786,Boyd%20Glacier&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="MBerlin" n="Mount"><title level="a">Mount Berlin.</title> <title level="m">Geographical Names Information System (GNIS)</title>. United States
                  Geological Survey. n.d. Web. 28 Feb. 2014 &lt;http://geonames.usgs.gov/apex/f?p=136:3:0::NO::P3_ANTAR_ID,P3_TITLE:1274,Mount%20Berlin&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Arnold" n="Arnold"><title level="a">Arnold Court.</title> <title level="m">Marquis Biographies Online.</title> Marquis Who's Who LLC., n.d. Web. 22 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://search.marquiswhoswho.com.proxy.lib.ohio-state.edu/profile/100002028842&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Malone" n="Malone">Malone, Thomas F., ed. <title level="j">Compendium of Meteorology.</title> 
                  Baltimore: Waverly Press, Inc., 1951. <title level="m">Internet Archive.</title> Web. 26 Feb. 2014.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="LibUTexas" n="Guide"><title level="a">A Guide to the Charles F. Passel Antarctic Exploration Collection, 1911-2001</title> <title>University of Texas Library</title> 
                  n.d. Web. 25 Feb. 2015</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="FindAGrave" n="FindAGrave"><title level="a">Felix Louis Ferranto.</title> <title type="m">FindAGrave.com.</title> N.p., n.d. Web. 26 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=72466677&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Russell" n="Russell"><title level="a">Russell G. Frazier.</title> <title level="m">Utah History to Go.</title> Utah.gov Services, n.d. Web. 26 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://historytogo.utah.gov/people/utahns_of_achievement/russellgfrazier.html&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="FloodRange" n="Flood"><title level="a">Flood Range.</title> <title level="m">Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</title>. United States
                  Geological Survey, n.d. Web 24 Feb. 2014 &lt;http://geonames.usgs.gov/apex/f?p=136:3:0::NO::P3_ANTAR_ID,P3_TITLE:5051,Flood%20Range&gt;</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Atlantic" n="Atlantic"><title level="m">Atlantic Canada Genealogy Project.</title> N.p., n.d. Web. 26 Feb. 2014. &lt;http://www3.telus.net/chignecto/atlanticcanada/aqwg2503.htm&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="James" n="James">James, Donald. <title level="a">U.S. Stations and Camps in Antarctica.</title>
                  <title level="m">NASA Quest.</title> NASA, n.d. Web. 1 Mar. 2014.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Richard" n="Richard"><title level="a">Richard E. Byrd: Byrd Antarctic Expedition III: 
                  The United States Antarctic Service Expedition.</title> <title level="m">South-Pole.com.</title> N.p., n.d. Web. 2 Mar. 2014.
                  &lt;http://www.south-pole.com/p0000109.htm&gt;.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="National" n="National"><title level="a">National Science Foundation Office of Polar
                  Programs U.S. Antarctic Program: Your Stay at Amundsen-Scott South Pole Station.</title> 
                  <title level="m">NASA Quest.</title> NASA, n.d. Web. 2 Mar. 2014.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="MGutenko" n="GutenkoMountains"><title level="a">Gutenko Mountains.</title> <title level="m">Geographic Names Information System (GNIS).</title> United States 
                  Geological Survey, n.d. Web. 3 Mar. 2014.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="WikiFitz" n="Roy"><title level="a">Roy Fitzsimmons</title><title level="s"> Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</title> 
                 10 May 2013. Web. 3 March 2014.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Bertrand" n="Bertrand">Bertrand, Kenneth J. <title level="m">Americans in Antarctica.</title> New York: American Geographical Society, 1971. Print.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="Wings1980"><title level="m">The Eagle and the Turtle</title> Mal Holcomb. "The Eagle and teh Turtle." Wings Magazine February 1980: 1. Web.</bibl>
               
               <bibl xml:id="White" n="White"> White, James A. <title level="a">Byrd Expeditions Paying Off Today On Our Frozen Fronts.</title> <title level="j">The Palm Beach Post</title>
                Google news, n.d. Web. 4 March 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Petras" n="Petras"><title level="a">Theodore A. Petras</title><title level="m">Enlisted Naval Aviation Pilots</title>Turner Publishing Company, 2002.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="McCoy" n="McCoy"><title level="a">Commander James Charles McCoy Explorer</title><title level="m">Geneaology.Rootsweb.Ancestry.Com</title>N.p., n.d. Web. 27 February 2014. 
                  http://freepages.genealogy.rootsweb.ancestry.com/~jcmccoyjr/UnderConstruct/Page_5x.html</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="JamesCharles" n="JamesCharles"><title level="a">James Charles McCoy</title><title level="m">Ancestry.Com</title>N.p., n.d. Web. 27 February 2014.
                  http://records.ancestry.com/James_Charles_McCoy_records.ashx?pid=80142976</bibl>
            
               <bibl xml:id="IMBdRB" n="Risky"><title level="a">Risky Business</title><title level="m"> IMDb.</title> IMDb, n.d. Web.</bibl> 
               <bibl xml:id="IMBdJF" n="Jones"><title level="a">Jones Family in Hollywood</title><title level="m"> IMDb.</title> IMDb, n.d. Web.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="IMBdGwtW" n="Gone"><title level="a">Gone with the Wind</title><title level="m"> IMDb.</title> IMDb, n.d. Web.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="IMBdB" n="Blondie"><title level="a">Blondie</title><title level="m">I MDb.</title> IMDb, n.d. Web.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="ExploratoryFlights" n="ExploratoryFlights">Hawthorne, Roger. <title level="a">Exploratory Flights of Admiral Byrd (1940).
               </title><title level="j">Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society</title> 89.1 (30 April 1945): 398a-398e. Print. </bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="DailySentinel" n="DailySentinel">Butterfield, C.E. <title level="a">Radio Day by Day.</title><title level="j">Daily
               Sentinel </title> [Rome, N.Y.] 3 January 1941, Friday evening: 13. Print</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Saratogian" n="Saratogian"><title level="a">Best Radio Programs: Leading Station Features.</title><title level="j">
               The Saratogian </title> [Saratoga Springs, N.Y.] 3 January 1941: 11. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="USCG" n="USCG"><title level="a">USS North Star, CG, 1941.</title> <title level="m">U.S. Coastguard Historian's Office</title>, n.p., n.d. Web. 25 February 2014.
                  http://www.uscg.mil/history/webcutters/North_Star_1941.pdf</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Shipscribe" n="Shipscribe"><title level="a">North Star (IX-148) Photographs.</title><title level="m">Shipscribe.com</title>, n.p., n.d. Web. 25 February 2014.
                  http://www.shipscribe.com/usnaux/IX3/IX148-p.html</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="PerkBiology" n="Perkins">Perkins, Jack E. <title level="a">Biology at Little America III, 
                  the West Base of the United States Antarctic Service Expedition 1939-1941.</title> 
                  <title level="j">Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society</title> 89. 1 (1945): 272-273. 
                  Print. <title level="j">JSTOR.</title> Web. 18 Mar. 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="PolarTimes" n="PolarTimes"><title level="a">Understanding the Past and the Present</title><title level="m">Discovering Antarctica</title> N.p., n.d. Web. 25 March 2014.
                  http://www.discoveringantarctica.org.uk/multimedia/flash/13/meltdown/13_understanding_meltdown.html</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="WikiSiple" n="Siple"><title level="a">Paul Siple</title><title level="s"> Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</title> 
                  28 Jan 2014. Web. 20 March 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="Philatelic" n="Philatelic">
                  Bennett, Russell and James Watson. <title level="m">Philatelic Terms Illustrated, 2nd Edition.</title>
                  London: Stanley Gibbons Publications Ltd., 1978. Print.
               </bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="South-Pole" n="South-Pole">
                  <title level="m">South-Pole.com</title>Web. 25 February 2014.
               </bibl>
               <bibl xml:id="ASPP" n="ASPP">
                  <title level="m">American Society of Polar Philatelists.</title>American Society of Polar Philatelists.
                  Web. 25 February 2014.
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </sourceDesc>

      </fileDesc>

      <!--
         The encoding description, tagged <encodingDesc>, describes "the relationship 
         between an electronic text and its source or sources" (TEI P4X, ch. 5).
         -->
      <encodingDesc>

         <projectDesc>
            <p>This edition is the latest in a series of collaboratively produced electronic
               editions of previously unpublished nineteenth-century American manuscripts held in
               the Special Collections of The Ohio State University Libraries. Previous
               editions include "My Dear Elizabeth," five letters written by Sophia Peabody
               Hawthorne to her sister Elizabeth Palmer Peabody between ca. 1837 and 1868 (currently
               being revised); "Dear Wife," twenty-one letters written by riverboat captain William
               B. Anderson to his wife Louisa while he plied the Ohio river during the height of the
               American Civil War, 1862&#x2013;1864; "Journal of a Tour to Europe," by Samuel Sullivan Cox;
               and "Louisa A. Doane's Journal of Two Ocean Voyages (1852-1853). These documentary
               editions are intended to provide wide exposure and access to manuscripts that might
               otherwise be difficult for scholars to discover and consult, and to provide users
               with a variety of tools for studying those texts. </p>
            <p>Each text was edited in connection with an undergraduate or graduate course offered
               by H. Lewis Ulman, Associate Professor of English at The Ohio State University. The
               courses provide students with an opportunity to explore issues of textuality
               and mediation that arise when our cultural archives spread from page to screen and
               from library shelves to networked databases. Electronic textual editing serves as our
               vehicle for examining what happens—and envisioning what might happen—when artifacts
               in one medium are represented in another medium, especially with regard to the
               interpretive work of reading. Electronic textual editions also provide a contact zone
               that can help us reflect on what manuscript, print, and "born digital" artifacts can
               tell us about their unique properties and their relationships to one another.</p>
            <p>While providing a reliable textual edition is a <foreign xml:lang="lat">sine qua
                  non</foreign>, the Lockhart edition also explores ways of telling four stories
               inextricably woven into our work: the lives and historical milieu evoked by the
               texts, the history of the physical journal, the
               editorial process that gave rise to this particular interpretation of the text, and
               the mediation of our electronic delivery system.</p>
            <p rend="h3" xml:id="ack">Acknowledgments</p>
            <p>The editors would like to thank The Ohio State University Libraries for permission to
               publish this edition of Earl Lockhart's Antarctic journal and to incorporate images
               of the manuscript held in the Byrd Polar Research Center Archival Program. Laura
               Kissel, Polar Curator, introduced the principal editor to the Lockhart journal and
               suggested that he and his students edit the volume.
            </p>
            <p> The Ernest Earl Lockhart Papers were donated to the Byrd Polar Research Center
               Archival Program by Paul Koulouris, nephew and executor of the Helen S. Lockhart
               Estate (Helen was Earl Lockhart's wife). Earl Lockhart's nephews Paul Koulouris and
               George Lockhart, and George's mother Mary Guernsey Lockhart, provided the editors
               with information about Earl Lockhart's family and early life. </p>
            <p>
               This edition also depends on technical support from a number of organizations and
               individuals at The Ohio State University. The College of Arts and Sciences hosts this
               Web site. High-resolution images of the manuscipt pages are housed on the Colleges of
               the Arts and Sciences Media Manager application, which allows the edition to provide
               users with zoomable views and numerous detail views of the manuscript pages on the
               fly, all from archived master images. George Abraham, Web Applications Developer, and
               Allen Coleman, Digital Library Developer, offered frequent advice and encouragement
               for our custom applications of the Media Manager image server.
            </p>
            <p>
               Finally, we would like to thank the Digital Media Project (DMP) in the Department of English at The Ohio
               State University, which provided classroom support for the editorial team. The former
               director of the DMP, Professor Scott Lloyd Dewitt, generously allocated funds from
               the DMP to purchase a classroom license for the specialized XML-editing software used
               by the editorial team, and DMP Manager Amy Spears has provided invaluable support.
            </p>
            
         </projectDesc>

         <!--
            In addition to prose description, the Editorial Practices Declaration may contain 
            specialized elements concerned with correction, normalization, quotation, hyphenation, 
            segmentation, date and number format, and interpretive apparatus (TEI P4X, ch. 5.3.3).
         -->
         <editorialDecl>
            
            <!-- 
               TAKE NOTE: Explain your editorial method:
               
                  If you employ image files, describe how they were produced and note where they are stored.
                  Describe any editorial guidelines you followed (e.g., how you treated hyphenation, whether 
                  you corrected apparent errors, and any other decisions about how to treat recurrent features).
                  Describe any special symbols that you use in your text to indicate additions, corrections, 
                  cancellations, and so on. This important explanation provides a reader's guide to the text.
               
                  You can use more than one paragraph (tagged <p> </p>).
                  
                  We might include a system diagram, showing where all of the assets are stored
                  and how the systems interact. We might include a database of assets. And we
                  might include screen shots of the edition running on various systems as a step
                  toward a descriptive bibliography of an online edition.
            -->

            <p>
               <emph rend="bold">Scanning</emph>. The manuscript pages were scanned at
               300 dots per inch (dpi) in an RGB color space by the vendor, ArcaSearch, and saved in three file
               formats: PDF, JPEG, and JPEG2000.
            </p>
            <p>
               <emph rend="bold">Production Location of Digital Assets</emph>. The TEI P5-encoded
               transcription of the Lockhart journal, along with XSL style sheets used to provide
               variant "views" of the edition, TEI ODD documents used to produce custom schemas
               based on the TEI markup language, and the resulting schemas are stored on a server
               hosted by College of Arts and Sciences at The Ohio State University and on a Google
               SVN repository. Readers may download copies of those source files via a link in the
               drop-down navigation menu. Digital scans of the manuscript pages, scans of
               plates from contemporary sources, and photographs of the journal are stored in the
               Media Manager application hosted by the College of Arts and Science at The Ohio State
               University. The files constituting the project's Web site are stored on a Web server
               hosted by the College
               (http://people.cohums.ohio-state.edu/ulman1/lockhart-journals/lockhart-edintro.html#introduction).
            </p>
            <p>
               <emph rend="bold">Archiving of Digital Assets</emph>. Once the edition is complete,
               its digital assets will be archived in The Ohio State University
               Knowledge Bank (https://kb.osu.edu/dspace/). 
            </p>

         </editorialDecl>

         <refsDecl>
            <p>
               <emph rend="bold">Markup of Physical Structure and Page Layout</emph>. The manuscript
                  <emph rend="bold">pages</emph>, encoded by the empty page break or &lt;pb/&gt;
               element, are the primary physical structures represented in the markup. Each
               &lt;pb&gt; element includes a &quot;facs&quot; attribute identifying the unique ID of
               a high-resolution scan of that image in the Media Manager application. <emph
                  rend="bold">Line breaks</emph> (i.e., lineation determined or influenced by the
               physical constraints of the page rather than compositional choices by the author) are
               encoded with the empty &lt;lb/&gt; element. No attributes are included in the
               &lt;lb&gt; element. Because Smith wrote on lined paper, when he skips a line printed
               on the paper for any reason, we encode a &lt;lb/&gt; that, in the view arranged by
               manuscript pages and lines, will appear as an empty numbered line. </p>
            <p>
               <emph rend="bold">Markup of Textual Structure</emph>. The <emph rend="bold">diary
                  entry</emph>, encoded by a &lt;div&gt; element with the attribute-value pair
               &quot;type='Entry'&quot;, constitutes the primary textual structure represented in
               the markup. Each entry contains a
               &lt;dateline&gt; element and one or more paragraphs. Each dateline may include a
               &lt;name&gt; element with (optionally) a @type attribute containing one of
               the following values: city, region; and a &lt;date&gt; element with a
               @when attribute whose value is in the form YYYY-MM-DD. The value of the
               @when attribute represents the editors' judgment about the actual date when the entry
               was composed; the contents of the &lt;date&gt; element represent what Smith actually
               wrote, even if he entered the date incorrectly.
            </p>
            <p>
               Entries consist of a series of <emph rend="bold">paragraphs</emph>. Where indicated
               by context, indentation of a line from the left margin of a page, line breaks part-way across
               a page, or additional white space between lines, paragraphs are encoded with the
               &lt;p&gt; element and no attributes.
            </p>
            <p>
               If present, any prefatory text preceding the dateline may be encoded as a
               &lt;head&gt; element at the beginning of an entry (i.e., within the
               &lt;div&gt;element and before the &lt;dateline&gt;).
            </p>
            <p>
               <emph rend="bold">Level of Transcription/Encoding</emph>. This markup scheme supports
               a modest range of presentations, from semi-modernized/corrected to semi-diplomatic.
               The basic transcription follows the manuscript verbatim. Various manuscript features
               (e.g., cancellations, interlinear or marginal additions, tears in pages) are encoded,
               as are regularized versions of proper names and dates and standard versions of
               nonstandard spellings and expansions of abbreviations. </p>
            <p>
               <!-- NOTE: Update to include informationa about TEI ODD files. -->
               <emph rend="bold">Customization of the TEI P5 Schema</emph>. Customization consisted primarily of restricting
               encoding to certain modules and elements as well as enforcing some attribute values. See the ODD file for 
               complete details.
            </p>
            
         </refsDecl>

         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="LCSH">
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>

      </encodingDesc>

      <profileDesc>
         
         <!--
         The text profile, tagged <profileDesc>, contains "classificatory and contextual information 
         about the text, such as its subject matter, the situation in which it was produced, the 
         individuals described by or participating in producing it, and so forth" (TEI P4X, ch. 5).
         -->

         <creation>
            <date>2014-04-17</date>
         </creation>


         <!-- Note any languages that appear in your document (use multiple tags, if necessary). -->
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">English</language>
         </langUsage>

         <!-- Identify and describe any hands (i.e., individuals' handwriting) that appear in your document. -->
         <handNotes>
            <handNote xml:id="EELHand" medium="pencil">Ernest E. Lockhart's hand.</handNote>
         </handNotes>

         <textClass>
            <!-- 
            Supply a list of keywords for your document from the Library of Congress Subject Headings
            -->
            <keywords scheme="#LCSH">
               <term>Diaries</term>
               <term>Antarctica</term>
               <term>Antarctica--Discovery and exploration--American</term>
            </keywords>

         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>

      <revisionDesc>

         <!--
            The revision history, tagged <revisionDesc>, allows "the encoder to provide a history of 
            changes made during the development of the electronic text" (TEI P4X, ch. 5).
            Add additional changes at the top of the list.
         -->
         <change when="2013-12-16" who="HLU">Created first drafts of TEI customization files, Relax NG schemas, TEI transcription, and XSL stylesheets. </change>

      </revisionDesc>

   </teiHeader>

   
   <text> <!-- Open main text div. -->
     <group> <!-- Open text group -->
        <text xml:id="eel-journal2" type="boundJournal"> <!-- Begin text 1, bound journal #2. -->
        <body> <!-- Being the body of journal #2. -->
         <!-- 
            We begin in medias res on Christmas Day, 1940. The value of the xml:id
            attribut of of the first Entry follows the pattern eel-YYYYMMDDa, 
            where eel stands for Ernest E. Lockhart,YYYYMMDD identifies the date, 
            and "a" represents the first entry for a given day.
         -->
         <!-- HLU section begins here -->
            <pb facs="journal-2-01.jpg" n="/f/f6740eaf-5b89-47d7-87f8-ff9c9e993803"/>
            <pb facs="journal-2-02.jpg" n="/d/d6953828-9c18-4223-934c-fcdf6d224837"/>
            <pb facs="journal-2-03.jpg" n="/7/7a0c1a5b-fc4e-428b-a3cc-a9e686ad3d38"/>
            <pb facs="journal-2-04.jpg" n="/1/16127fab-3e46-4d3e-be62-faf82ab2cbaf"/>
            <pb facs="journal-2-05.jpg" n="/e/e57988fb-3960-435f-a308-ebfafaa4892a"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">1</fw>
            <head>
               <lb/>
               <lb/>Journal covering period Dec 25 1940 until return home
               <lb/>about May 1<hi rend="superscript underlined">st</hi> 1941
               <lb/>
            </head>
            <div xml:id="eel-19401225a" type="entry">
               <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-25">Wednesday December 25 1940</date></dateline>
               <p>
                  <lb/>At the exact moment when christmas bells should have
                  <lb/>begun ringing here in the <placeName>Antarctic</placeName> if any christmas bells
                  <lb/>had been available, <persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> <persName>Jack</persName> <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> and I were making
                  <lb/>our last big "Putsch" toward <rs>the base</rs> We had left
                  <lb/><placeName ref="FortWiener">Fort Wiener</placeName> at 930 PM and at 11 PM when we were
                  <lb/>only 10.5 miles from <rs>the base</rs> decided not to camp until
                  <lb/>morning but push on in. <del rend="strikethrough"><persName ref="Tony">Tony</persName> and the <unclear>rest</unclear></del> While we were
                  <lb/>resting we drank a toast to ourselves — as a party — and
                  <lb/>to a merry christmas, finishing up the half a pint which
                  <lb/>I had <seg ana="metaphor">nursed</seg> along so carefully for two and a half months. <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName>
                  <lb/>and I started out again and again and for a while had some
                  <lb/>difficulty staying ahead of the dogs. They were running now
                  <lb/>just as well as they did when we first hit the good
                  <lb/>surface we were travelling over. <persName>Jack</persName> and <persName><unclear>Sevene</unclear></persName> still
                  <lb/>combining new teams and he was driving them. <name type="dog">Dinch</name> and
                  <lb/><name type="dog">Pearl</name> were pinched up in the loads. I am quite certain
                  <lb/>that we should never have made the base when we did
                  <lb/>if we hadn't combined our teams. At one o'clock we
                  <lb/>could just see the base and the airplane looming on the
                  <lb/>horizon. <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> had been seeing things for several hours
                  <lb/>but always he had to say <said aloud= "true" direct= "true">I guess I was wrong</said>
                  <lb/>when a large <ref type="trailflag">trail flag</ref> <del rend= "strikethrough"><unclear cert="high">br</unclear></del> <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="NoteTrail"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="NoteTrail">Dr. Lockhart makes several mentions to "the trail" and "trail flags/markers" throughout the journal; 
                     he is likely referring to the trails created between the West Base and supply depots and/or science stations, for groups traveling to and from these locations. Lockhart was a member of one the trail parties, the Ford Ranges Biological Party, which was tasked with gathering biological information, 
                     and when possible, geological/glaciation data <bibl><ref target="#Bertrand"><title level="m">Americans in Antarctica</title></ref></bibl></note>. came into view. All sorts
                  <lb/>of thoughts began clicking through our minds as the <rs>base</rs>
               
                  <pb facs= "journal-2-06.jpg" n="/d/d30a3d29-fe7e-4bf6-a941-541638ebc568"/>
                  <fw type="pageNum" place="top">2</fw>
           
              <lb/>became larger and larger. <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName><del rend= "strikethrough"><unclear cert="high">br</unclear></del>, I know, was especially
                  <lb/>anxious to get into the barracks <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="notebarracks1"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="notebarracks1">The barracks that are written about are presumably living quarters, where the men on the expedition slept and spent any down time.</note> to tell his stories. The
              <lb/>rest of us were wondering what the present set up was like-
              <lb/>we had heard so many reports while we were out on the trail
              <lb/>that we had no idea what we were walking into. I
              <lb/>think the thought uppermost in our minds was food. While
              <lb/>we were out on the trail we were perfectly satisfied with our
              <lb/>somewhat rigid diet but now that we were approaching some-
              <lb/>thing of quite different. I said that I probable wouldn't eat very much
              <lb/><persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> said he would eat only a ham sandwich and a cup of coffee.
              <lb/><persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> and <persName>Jack</persName> said they were going to fill up. We all had our
              <lb/>doubts whether <persName ref="#Gutenko">Gutenko</persName> would have anything for us.
              </p>
              <p>
                 <lb/>When we had come about 2 miles from the base,<persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName>
                 <lb/>and I stopped <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack</persName> who was leading and suggested that we
                 <lb/>let <persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> take his team in first. <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> skied ahead breaking
                 <lb/>trail with <persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> following a short distance behind I skied
                 <lb/>ahead of old <name type="dog" ref="#Spot">Spot</name>. <persName ref="#Siple">Paul</persName> came out to meet us and gave
                 <lb/>us a good hand clapp as we came up to him. There was
                 <lb/>preliminary gossip as we endrived in. We parked in
                 <lb/>front of the balloon house <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="noteballoonhouse1"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="noteballoonhouse1">The balloon house that is written about is a place where radar information and radiosonde balloons were kept. Radar tracking and work with the climate was also done here. </note> where we were met by almost the
                 <lb/>whole camp personnel. We had been wondering whether any
                 <lb/>but a dozen few would be waiting up for us and now were
                 <lb/>surprised to see everyone. While we were answering various
                 <lb/>questions we net up camp and staked out the dogs. <persName>Douglas</persName>
                 <lb/>and <persName ref="#Wiener">Wiener</persName> hauled over some seal meat they had cut. The
                 <lb/>dogs sure enjoyed it and then yelped for more. By that time
                 <lb/><persName ref="#Gutenko">Gutenko</persName> said that <unclear>clun</unclear> was nearly ready and we all <unclear cert="medium">repaired</unclear> to
              
                 <pb facs="journal-2-07.jpg" n="/b/b057d443-5967-4034-98aa-63d5da97307b"/>
               <fw type="pageNum" place="top">3</fw>
               
                  <lb/>the barracks<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="notebarracks1"/>. We took our clothes off and weighed in.
                  <lb/><persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> weighed 193 before and 173 after (in same clothes) <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack</persName>
                  <lb/>weighed 159 before and about 158 after. <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> weighed 189
                  <lb/>before and 163 after I weighed 162 before and 150 after.
                  <lb/>Those of us who lost weight lost only the fat that we had
                  <lb/>put on during the winter night. <persName ref="#Gutenko">Gutenko</persName> really put out a
                  <lb/>meal. tomato juice, tomato soup steak potatoes and even
                  <lb/>figs for dessert and coffee. I really ate my share thus
                  <lb/>not living up to the statement I made on the trail. We
                  <lb/>had come in at 2AM having <seg ana="metaphor">covered</seg> the 34 miles in less
                  <lb/>than 16 hours which was very good time considering the stops
                  <lb/>we made, this surface and the condition we and the dogs
                  <lb/>were in. Then we sat around and talked for several more
                  <lb/>hours. <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack</persName> and I went out to sleep in the tent but <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName>
                  <lb/>and <persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> stayed inside. It was almost six oclock before
                  <lb/>we got out there <persName ref="#Arnold">Arnold</persName> came out with us and fed us with
                  <lb/>some of the dish and there was a lot of it.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I slept <seg ana="adage">the sleep of the blessed</seg> for about three hours and
                  <lb/>then dozed for about three hours <del rend="strikethrough"><unclear cert="low">f</unclear></del> more. <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack</persName> and <persName>Doug</persName>
                  <lb/>talking in the next tent convinced me that it was time to get
                  <lb/>up. after dressing I went into the galley to have my first
                  <lb/>different breakfast in several months. There was fruit toast
                  <lb/>cheeze and coffee and I had pleanty of all. From then
                  <lb/>on I spent the time until dinner cleaning up a little and
                  <lb/><seg ana="metaphor">chewing the fat</seg> a lot. The dinner was one of the <persName ref="#Gutenko">Gutenko's</persName> specials
                  <lb/>turkey with sweet potatoes asparagus spinach
                  <lb/>dressing cranberry sauce after boullion; we had a little
               
               <pb facs="journal-2-08.jpg" n="/7/7e20064a-fc13-42fd-a452-63a23c83f0c2"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">4</fw> 
                  
                     <lb/>christmas spirit and strawberry pie to top things off then
                     <lb/>more lulling until <seg ana="metaphor">show time</seg>. We saw the <title level="m" ref="#jfih">Jones family in
                     <lb/>Hollywood</title><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="notemovies1"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="notemovies1">A 1939 comedy starring Jed Prouty and Spring Byington.
                        <bibl><ref target="#IMBdJF"><title level="a">Jones Family in Hollywood</title></ref></bibl></note>
                  and <title level="m" ref="#rb">Risky Business</title> <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="notemovies2"/>
                  <note resp="ed" xml:id="notemovies2">A 1939 crime drama starring George Murphy and Dorothea Kent. There is no relation to the 1983 movie of the same name starring Tom Cruise.
                     <bibl><ref target="#IMBdRB"><title level="a">Risky Business</title></ref></bibl></note>. I enjoyed both of them.
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>It had been blowing about 35-40 miles an hour all day
                     <lb/>and drifting so badly that I decided to sleep in. <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack</persName> 
                     <lb/>however braved the storm and slept out. <del rend="strikethrough">All in</del>
                 </p>
                 <p>
                    <lb/>All in all this has by far been the most eventful
                    <lb/>christmas I have ever experienced. 
                 </p>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>The base has been operating on a very peculiar schedule<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="schedule"/>
                     <note resp="ed" xml:id="schedule">The schedule that Lockhart frequently mentions refers to the daily
                        schedule on which the camp operated. Members of the expedition kept schedules that corresponded 
                        with their duties (cooking dinner, taking pictures, operating the radio, or taking air samples, 
                        for example). The schedules were complicated by the odd hours of daylight in Antarctica: during the
                        height (December/January) of summer, there was continuous light. In his diary, Charlie Passel notes
                        that periods of darkness gradually increased beginning in March, and by late April, winter had set 
                        in, and it was continuously dark. The sun returned, faintly at first, near the end of August. 
                        Lockhart mentions the schedule around camp being quite lax, and Passel's diary confirms this. 
                        Passel cites the cook's accidental but frequent sleeping in as the source of the problem. Presumably, 
                        while on on the trail, the schedule was more closely followed becasue there were less people to account
                        for.<bibl><ref target="#Passel"><title level="m">Ice: The Antarctic Diary of Charles F. Passel</title></ref></bibl></note>
                     <lb/>since the trail parties went out. <persName ref="#Gutenko">Gutenko</persName> gets up about 1-2
                     <lb/>PM and works preparing the only meal of the day a dinner
                     <lb/>The rest of the men get up anytime between 2 and 6 and then 
                     <lb/>stay up until they get tired enough to go to bed again about
                     <lb/>6-7-8 in the morning. The only work being done around camp
                     <lb/>is general duty and evacuation work- not much of the latter
                     <lb/>as yet. The camp is divided into two groups each of which
                     <lb/>does the cleaning up and galley duty in alternate days. In  
                     <lb/>off moments the fellows go skiing and walking with the dogs.
                     <lb/>All of the pups which were hardly able to walk when we
                     <lb/>left now have the run of the camp. They certainly are a
                     <lb/>nice bunch. <persName ref="#PappyGray">Pappy Gray</persName> has those which he harnesses to
                     <lb/>the airplane sled and drives around. In general the men
                     <lb/>here haven't much to do and take their time doing it.
                     <lb/>The men who have regular schedules to meet such as the
                     <lb/>radio men and the weather man appear at their regular 
                     <lb/>intervals but otherwise any semblance of regularity has
                     <lb/>disappeared. I was puzzled to see such a system of what
                  
               <pb facs="journal-2-09.jpg" n="/e/e04d1ba7-3ba0-4922-b5f4-74690eba7d9f"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">5</fw>   
               
                  <lb/>we have here now in a system but learned that it
                  <lb/>all came about because the best time for taking
                  <lb/>airplane pictures is in the early morning hours. During
                  <lb/>the flying day when everyone was waiting for breaks in
                  <lb/>the weather this new arrangement of sleeping days and 
                  <lb/>staying up nights became the vogue. We of the biological 
                  <lb/>party <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="biological"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="biological">Lockhart was a member of the Biological Party which was a sledging party, and he acted as physiologist and radio operator for the party. The party was led by biologist Perkins and included a dog driver, Colombo, with 2 dog teams
                     each pulling 2 sleds in tandem, Richardson, who served as meteorological observer and transferred to their party at 105-mile depot, and Fitzsimmons, physicist for the seismic station who left the Biological Party at 105-mile depot. The party's destination was the western mountains of Ford Ranges, and they 
                     were tasked with gathering biological information as well as studying geology and glaciation. The party departed on October 15, 1940 and returned to camp on Dec 25, 1940 having traveled 725 miles in 72 days. On November 25, 1940 the biological party raised the US flag at slope at the southwest corner of peak No 167, west side of Mt Iphigene. 76 degrees 31’S 145 degrees 45’W.They
                     succesfully brought back biological specimens and geological data as well as a daily meterological record, journal, and photos.<bibl><ref target="#Bertrand">Bertrand 435-436</ref></bibl></note> are finding it difficult to change from the rigorous
                  <lb/>schedule we have been observing to this not so rigorous
                  <lb/>one of the base.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>For the first time since we left the base I have
                  <lb/>been really sore in my muscles. I don't know whether
                  <lb/>it is due to the long run made on the last day or to
                  <lb/>the lack of any follow up exercise today. 
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>All of the radiograms<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="radiogram"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="radiogram"> These radiograms were messages sent via vocal radio 
                     contact between the Expedition and the people back home. They were made possible by members of the Army Amateur Radio System relaying the messages stateside 
                     to and from the families. This served as the main form of contact home throughout the Expedition <bibl><ref target="#QST">"U.S. Antarctic Service Expresses Appreciation"</ref></bibl></note>
                     that had come in during my absence 
                  <lb/>were given to me. One of them had not been read over the air
                  <lb/>It was from <persName ref="#Beatie">Beatie</persName> and wished me a merry christmas. <seg ana="aetiologia">The main
                  <lb/>item of the message, however, lead me to believe that some of my 
                  <lb/>friends would not have a merry christmas; <persName ref="#JackMahan">Jack Mahan</persName>'s <rs ref="#MrMahan">father</rs>
                  <lb/>died about a week ago.</seg> I was very sorry to hear of it <choice><sic>allthough</sic><corr>although</corr></choice>
                  <lb/>I had been expecting it. Evidently his exceptionally strong heart
                  <lb/>just couldn't stand up any longer under the high pressure. It
                  <lb/>is better that he is gone because for several years he has 
                  <lb/>been very unhappy about his condition particularly because he 
                  <lb/>realized that there was no hope of his ever recovering. I
                  <lb/>always enjoyed the moments I spent with him talking
                  <lb/>about boats and travel. I'm certain he would have been
                  <lb/>interested to hear about the trip I am now about to com-
             
                  <pb facs="journal-2-10.jpg" n="/9/960c09a7-4b71-4178-af01-76b2587d91dd"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">6</fw>   
                  <lb/>plete. <persName ref="#Beatie">Beatie</persName> did not say whether <persName ref="#JackMahan">Jack</persName> came home for
                  <lb/>the funeral. Since <persName>Ned</persName> and <persName>Bill</persName> have gotten married and
                  <lb/>have moved out on their own only <persName ref="#MrsMahan">Mrs. Mahan</persName> and <persName>Margaret</persName>
                  <lb/>will be living in <placeName ref="#ArlingtonStreet">Arlington Street</placeName>. 
                  <lb/>
               </p>
            </div> <!-- End of first dated entry. -->
            <div xml:id="eel-19401226a" type="entry">
               <lb/><dateline><date when= "1940-12-26">Thursday, December 26 1940</date></dateline>
               <p>  
                  <lb/>I slept very well in my old cloth bag. I am lost now
                  <lb/>that I don't have a watch and consequently with the present
                  <lb/>schedule I didn't know whether I should get up or try to go
                  <lb/>back to sleep. The predicament was relieved by <persName ref="#Arnold">Arnold</persName> who
                  <lb/>happened to pass by. I got up when he said it was 11 30
                  <lb/>The whole biological party was in the galley preparing breakfast
                  <lb/>egg toast figs prunes coffee. Already I have forgotten how
                  <lb/>delicious <add place="above" rend="^">were</add> the oatmeal and cocoa of the trail. Although I
                  <lb/>meant to get going on my cleaning up for metabolism tests<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="metabolism"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="metabolism">Dr. Lockhart ran metabolism tests on volunteers 
                     to test the physiological effects of the cold. The volunteers were tested before and after a 3-month period on the trails and ate a specific diet. The results of the tests showed slightly lowered basal metabolism, 
                     increase in blood sugar levels, and changes in respiration and body temperature. For more information about their diets, see Lockhart's article.<bibl><ref target="#Bertrand">Bertrand 429</ref></bibl></note>
                  <lb/>but I started writing reading and talking so very little was 
                  <lb/>done. <persName ref="#BuckBoyd">Buck Boyd</persName> and I went skiing down to the <geogName>barrier edge</geogName><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="barrieredge"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="barrieredge">
                     Lockhart is likely referring to the edge of the Ross Ice Shelf <bibl><ref target="#Passel"><title level="m">Ice: The Antarctic Diary of Charles F. Passel</title></ref></bibl></note>
                  <lb/>to see if the blizzard had carried out any of the <geogName>bay</geogName><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="bay"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="bay">
                     When referring to "the bay," Lockhart is always referring to the Bay of Whales <bibl><ref target="#Passel"><title level="m">Ice: The Antarctic Diary of Charles F. Passel</title></ref></bibl></note> ice.
                  <lb/>We found that the whole <geogName>bay</geogName> was still iced over and unless
                  <lb/>something drastic happens within the next two weeks we certainly
                  <lb/>are going to have a very difficult time getting out of this place.
                  <lb/>Well we shan't worry about that for a while. 
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I forgot to mention in yesterday's account that the tractor<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="#tractor"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="tractor">West Base had a T-20 International crawler style of tractor. It was used for transport, unloading supplies from the ships, and to stash supplies by pulling trains of sleds to lie food and fuel in caches and depots for the sledging parties. 
                     The tractor parties went ahead of the sledging parties and established trails.<bibl><ref target="#Bertrand">Bertrand 414; 422</ref></bibl></note>
                  <lb/>had gone into a crevase about 10 miles from <placeName ref="#depot105">105</placeName> and the 
                  <lb/>situation looked impossible. Since the storm was raging out
                  <lb/>there <seg ana="adynaton">nothing could be done at the moment.</seg> Today at <del rend="strikethrough">the</del>
                  <lb/>the radio schedule time we were happy to learn that the
               <!--
                  Yonina-H: begin below this comment transcribing journal-2-11.jpg) with a page break.
                  You are "inside" a paragraph that begins on journal-2-10, but we will
                  resolve that encoding later. For now, this encoding is valid.
               -->
               
               <pb facs="journal-2-11.jpg" n="/3/3ce5f373-3c15-4241-bd63-4d5c552ac4ce"/>
               <fw type="pageNum" place="top">7</fw>
                     <lb/>impossible situation had been overcome; the tractor and
                     <lb/>its loads had passed the crevasse had gotten into
                     <lb/>another small one but was able to keep going and had
                     <lb/>arrived at 105. Some of the boys will now continue home
                     <lb/>with their dog teams. <persName>Larry</persName> will stay with the tractor
                     <lb/>gang and with his dog team attempt to evacuate <persName>Fritz</persName>.
               </p>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>At this time&#x2014;about 2 AM&#x2014;I don't feel particularly
                     <lb/>tired so am staying up<unclear>.</unclear> I ha<subst instant="true"><del type="overwritten">d</del><add place="inline">ve</add></subst>d been reading <title level="m">Death
                        <lb/>Sails with Magellan</title> <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="#NoteMagellan"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="NoteMagellan">A novel set during Magellan's voyage from the point of view of his crewmen, ending in his death, written in 1937 <bibl><ref target="#Magellan">"Death Sails With Magellan"</ref></bibl> </note> but stopped to help <persName ref="#Court">Court</persName> release
                     <lb/>one of his <choice><sic>raysende</sic><corr>radiosonde</corr></choice> <choice><sic>ballons</sic><corr>balloons</corr></choice><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="noteradiosondeballoons1"/><note xml:id="noteradiosondeballoons1">Radiosonde balloons were used to fly into the air and measure atmospheric parameters. The measurements were then sent back to a fixed reciever in the balloon house.</note>. It got caught in one of
                     <lb/><persName>Railey's</persName> antennas but I was able to climb the pole
                     <lb/>and free it. While helping him I noticed a bunch
                     <lb/>of skua gulls <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="NoteSkua"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="NoteSkua">Arctic skuas, also known as "parasitic jaegers," are a type of seabird that primarily feed by stealing food from other birds, although they are known to hunt as well <bibl><ref target="#NatGeo"><title level="a">Arctic Skua</title></ref></bibl>. These birds largely live at seas, except to come ashore in order to breed during the Arctic summer <bibl><ref target="#NatGeo"><title level="a">Arctic Skua</title></ref></bibl>. Study of these birds was part of the 
                          mission to gather biological information on plants and animals native to the Arctic.<bibl><ref target="#Bertrand"><title level="m">Americans in Antarctica</title></ref></bibl></note>.
                          on a refuse pile and decided to try my
                     <lb/>skill again. I walked carefully toward them with
                     <lb/>the revol<subst><del><gap reason="overwritten"/></del><add place="inline">ver</add></subst> ready but two of the pups came up
                     <lb/>passed me and scared them <damage agent="water" extent="0" unit="word"/>away. <!-- Not sure if this is a spelling error, passed for past 'came up past me and ..' or if it's a list lacking commas 'came up, passed me and ..'. Lockhart doesn't use commas consistently in lists, so it could be either --> Next time I
                     <lb/>shall make sure there are no pups around when I
                     <lb/>go after the gulls.
                  </p>
                  <lb/>
                </div>
               <div xml:id="eel-19401227a" type="entry">
                  <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-27">Friday December 27 1940</date></dateline>
                  <p> 
                     <lb/>I woke up several times du<damage agent="water" extent="1" unit="word" />ring the night and
                     <lb/>wondered each time whether I <damage agent="water" extent="1" unit="word">shouldn't</damage> get up. Always
                     <lb/>there were men stirring around, the same light was
                     <lb/>shining the window so I was continually confused
                     <lb/>as to the time. I realized at last that it was time to
                     <lb/>get up when I heard the stove being made. I knew
                     <lb/>then it was noon time. I got up and made my own
                 
               
               <!--
                  Jennifer-B: begin below this comment transcribing journal-2-12.jpg) with a page break.
                  You are "inside" a paragraph that begins on journal-2-11, but we will
                  resolve that encoding later. For now, this encoding is valid.
               -->
               <pb facs="journal-2-12" n="/5/511e1fda-51d8-4c3f-b481-0f4e565a2c82"/>
               <fw type="pageNum" place="top">8</fw>
                  <lb/>as is the custom. I made <subst><del rend="overwritten"><gap></gap></del><add place="inline">some</add></subst> beautiful
                  <lb/>ham scrambled eggs from frozen whole eggs milk butter
                  <lb/>salt and nutmeg; they really were delicious. To go with    
                  <lb/>them I had cherries toast and coffee. After breakfast
                  <lb/>I started cleaning uo my joint and decided to do some
                  <lb/>washing at the same time<supplied reason="omitted" resp="ed">.</supplied> During the day I washed
                  <lb/>two pairs of underwear and two woolen shirts. I still
                  <lb/>have some socks and mitt liners in the wash water<supplied reason="omitted" resp="ed">.</supplied>
                  <lb/>Other clothing I packed into the duffle bag and I got that
                  <lb/>out from under my feet. Glassware began to go into
                  <lb/>the sink and little by little order appeared out of chaos<supplied reason="omitted" resp="ed">.</supplied>
                  <lb/>The job isn't complete yet but it is well on its way
                  <lb/>and another day should see me ready for work. One
                  <lb/>of the big jobs was the clearing of the <persName>Haldane</persName> apparatus
                  <lb/>and all day job if there ever was one - those damned
                  <lb/>stop cocks take years off my life. Just before dinner
                  <lb/><persName>Perk</persName> and I went out and chopped seal meat, this
                  <lb/>semi frozen stuff is a cinch to cut compared with that
                  <lb/>we had in the tunnels. The dogs hardly know what to     
                  <lb/>make of the seal meat. While on the trail their blocks
                  <lb/>would be chewed and swallowed within a minute or two
                  <lb/>but now only after a great deal of labor do they get enough 
                  <lb/>real meat from the big chuncks to make a good mouthful<supplied reason="omitted" resp="ed">.</supplied>
                  <lb/>After dinner those of us who had no chores during the 
                  <lb/>day were asked to fill the snow melter. The snow
                  <lb/>melter requires filling only about once every five days
                  <lb/>as compared with every other day during the old regime.   
               
              
               <!--
                  Sean-K: begin below this comment transcribing journal-2-13.jpg) with a page break.
                  You are "inside" a paragraph that begins on journal-2-12, but we will
                  resolve that encoding later. For now, this encoding is valid.
               -->
            
           
      
               <pb facs="journal-2-13" n="/1/12f99dbd-ffe1-45a9-b2bd-0b2223148468"/>
               <fw type="pageNum" place="top">9</fw>
               <lb/>after that a few minutes of reading and <seg ana="metaphor">chewing the
               <lb/>fat</seg> and <subst><del rend="overwritten">than</del><add place="inline">then</add></subst> more cleaning. The trail gang
               <lb/>came in at eight oclock by radio and said
               <lb/>that they wanted to evacuate <persName>Fritz</persName> tomorrow <subst><del rend="overwritten"><gap></gap></del><add place="inline">en</add></subst>
               <lb/>masse. I think <persName>Fritz</persName> will try to get them to put
               <lb/>it off for another day. I shall take <persName>Arnold's</persName>
               <lb/>midnight <choice><sic>meterological</sic><corr>meteorological</corr></choice> observations so that he can
               <lb/>get a little more sleep in one stretch than he
               <lb/>has been accustomed to.
             
                  </p>
               <lb/>
            </div>
           <div xml:id="eel-19401228a" type="entry">
              <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-28">Saturday December 28 1940</date></dateline>
              <p>
                 <lb/>An early start on the daily log today <subst><del rend="overwritten">bea</del><add place="inline">because</add></subst> I am
                 <lb/>faced with one of those moments when I should be doing
                 <lb/><choice><orig><distinct type="archaic_orthography" time="11-16">some thing</distinct></orig> <reg source="OED">something</reg></choice> but am not.
                  
   
              </p>
          
              <p>
                 <lb/>I had asked both <persName><unclear cert="medium">Peuk</unclear></persName> and <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> to awaken me if either
                 <lb/>of them got up before 10 AM. I did this because already
                 <lb/>I am begninng to tire of the present all-night schedule, and want
                 <lb/>to do my work in the day time. However neither of them were
                 <lb/>up when <persName>Pappy Reece</persName> called <persName>Bailey</persName> at 11 AM consequently
                 <lb/>it was that time when I got up. I had offered to take
                 <lb/><persName ref="#Court">Court's</persName> noon observation but he was up and took it himself.
                 <lb/>I got some instruction on changing sheets on the triple register
                 <lb/>so that again I shall be assistant <choice><sic>meterologist</sic><corr>meteorologist</corr></choice>. After
                 <lb/>this instruction I went into the galley to prepare my breakfast
                 <lb/><persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> was already there and told me there were some frozen
                 <lb/><choice><sic>straw berries</sic><corr>strawberries</corr></choice> outside the door. I had some of them with corn flakes
                 <lb/>and cream. They sure were good. While I was eating them
                 
            <pb facs="journal-2-14.jpg" n="/5/5debfbea-aaeb-4e48-8d0c-b2aa8b0c8828"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">10</fw>
                  <lb/>I prepared what probably will be my usual <foreign xml:lang="french">piece-de-resistance</foreign>
                  <lb/>scrambled eggs <foreign xml:lang="french">ala</foreign> <persName>Lockhart</persName>. These with toast and coffee
                  <lb/> completed the morning repast.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>In the laboratory I learned up a little more and am now
                  <lb/>ready to begin metabolism tests in the morning. <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> will
                  <lb/> be the first victim. I also changed water on the socks I
                  <lb/>had been soaking overnight and then sat down to read a bit
                  <lb/>more in <title type="m">Death Sails with Magellan</title><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="#NoteMagellan2"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="NoteMagellan2">See note on page 11</note>. <persName ref="#CharlesFord">Charles Ford</persName> the
                  <lb/>author certainly had done a marvellous job in this book
                  <lb/>I shall have to get it for my own library when I get home.
                  <lb/>Just as <persName ref="#BuckBoyd">Buck</persName> and I were going out skua gull hunting
                  <lb/><persName ref="#Siple">Paul</persName> stopped me to show some of the airplane pictures.
                  <lb/><geogName type="mountain" ref="#HalFlood">Hal Flood</geogName> is certainly a large and beautiful mountain
                  <lb/>He also said that he was going to see if it wouldn't 
                  <lb/>be possible to name <del rend="strikethrough">one of the</del><add place="above">a</add> mountain in the region
                  <lb/>beyond <geogName type="mountain" ref="#HalFlood">Hal Flood</geogName> after each one of the members of the
                  <lb/>Expedition. I think that would be quite something and
                  <lb/>hope the idea will be approved. <persName ref="#BuckBoyd">Buck</persName> and I did not
                  <lb/>get any skua gulls&#x2014;he is not <seg ana="metonymy">the shot</seg> he professes to be.
                  <lb/> In the future before the ships come in&#x2014;by the way, it is said
                  <lb/>that the <name type="ship" ref="#Bear">Bear</name> has already left <placeName ref="#NewZealand">New Zealand</placeName> for the <placeName>Bay</placeName>&#x2014;
                  <lb/>I shall do a little target practicing every day. <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> has
                  <lb/>just come in saying that there were more skua gulls out 
                  <lb/> there and brought in one as evidence.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/><del rend="strikethrough"><unclear>Even</unclear></del> I spoke to <persName ref="#Bailey">Bailey</persName> about getting a contact with the
                  <lb/>folks. He said that although conditions were very bad he
                  <lb/>would speak to <persName ref="#CharliePassel">Charlie</persName>. It is so little trouble for them to              
         <pb facs="journal-2-15.jpg" n="/d/d478311c-345a-4728-bde3-f72769e0f239"/>
         <fw type="pageNum" place="top">11</fw>            
               <lb/>get over there that it is worth the chance they will be
               <lb/>taking.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>There is going to be a mail bag sponsored by the <name ref="#BostonTraveler">Boston
               <lb/>Traveler</name> in <date>Jan 31</date>. We may not be able to get it
               <lb/>here because the ships will be on their way or almost
               <lb/>ready to go. It won't be <choice><sic>worth while</sic><corr>worthwhile</corr></choice> to tell the folks
               <lb/>to say a few words to me. It won't be very long now
               <lb/>until I see them again anyway.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/><seg ana="anesis">Enough for now.</seg>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div xml:id="eel-19401229a" type="entry">
            <lb/><dateline><date when="19401229">12/29/40</date> <time>1:30am</time></dateline>
            <p>
               <lb/>Not long after <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> brought his skua gull in <persName ref="#Wiener">Wiener</persName> went out
               <lb/>with his 22 rifle and brought back two more which <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName>
               <lb/>immediately worked on for blood samples. He had some trouble
               <lb/>getting the birds to bleed and then trouble getting the blood to
               <lb/>centrifuge properly. I made a few suggestions such as using
               <lb/>oxalate to prevent the blood from coagulating and the faster centrifugation
               <lb/>of the fresh blood. I hope to kill a few more so that I can skin them
               <lb/>and salt them down to take back.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>After dinner I got a few things ready for the morning metabolism
               <lb/>test on <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> and then spent some time bringing in coal and taking
               <lb/>out the garbage, chores assigned to me or my share in today's
               <lb/>cleaning up. The rest of the evening was spent in reading. While
               <lb/>I was out feeding the dogs, <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> and <persName ref="#Bailey">Bailey</persName> killed a few skua gulls
               <lb/>with the shotgun. It is lucky that the gulls are not 
               <lb/>yet accustomed to the shots or there would be much <del rend="strikethrough">less</del> fewer
               <lb/>targets available.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>I shall go to bed about <time>1:30</time> and get in a few hours sleep <del rend="strikethrough"><unclear cert="medium">be</unclear></del>           
           <pb facs="journal-2-16.jpg" n="/2/2f288865-f1a4-480b-8ff3-ff2f1a381d8a"/>
           <fw type="pageNum" place="top">12</fw>              
                <lb/>before the metabolism tests take place.
                <lb/>
              </p>
           </div>
           <div xml:id="eel-19401229b" type="entry">
              <lb/><dateline><date when="19401229">Sunday Dec <del rend="strikethrough">30</del><add place="above">29</add> 1940</date></dateline>
              <p>
                 <lb/>I had a very difficult time getting up this morning. Although
                 <lb/>I wanted to get up at <time>10</time> it was close to <time>11</time> before I descended
                 <lb/>from my heaven. I dressed and then woke <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName>. The metabolism
                 <lb/>test did not go off very well and we shall repeat it. We
                 <lb/>finished up just in time for me to take the noon observation
                 <lb/>and change the sheets. In the afternoon I began jumping
                 <lb/>the gas analysis apparatus and after finishing that <seg ana="metaphor">made an
                 <lb/>end of</seg> <title type="m">Death Sails with Magellan</title> <note target="#NoteMagellan" type="annotation">See note on page 11</note>. No gun practice today
                 <lb/>After dinner got ready for the urine analysis and completed
                 <lb/>my sock washing. Then came the seal chopping chore. The dogs
                 <lb/>sure make a fuss over the seal meat probably because they
                 <lb/>are getting plenty of it. <persName><unclear cert="medium">Sut</unclear></persName> brought in the first Adelie<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="AdPen"/>
                 <note resp="ed" xml:id="AdPen">Adelie penguins (Pygoscelis adeliae) were one of the many types 
                    of animals studied by the scientists on this expedition. Similar to Lewis and Clark and their
                    cataloging of the plants and animals they found during their exploration of the Louisiana 
                    Territory in the early 1800s, <persName ref="#Perk">Jack Perkins</persName> spent much of his 
                    time researching Antarctic animals. For knowledge’s sake, he caught them, skinned some of 
                    them for their pelts, drew their blood, and even tried to take some of the animals back to
                    the United States for further study. Attempts to transport these creatures, however, were 
                    unsuccessful <bibl><ref target="#PerkBiology"><title level="a">Biology at Little America III, the West Base
                       of the United States Antarctic Service Expedition 1939-1941</title></ref></bibl>.</note>
                 <lb/>penguin and <persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> has been spending most of the evening
                 <lb/>drawing blood and skinning it. There should be more of them
                 <lb/>in one the ice within the next few days. <persName ref="#Asman">Asman</persName> and <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> took
                 <lb/>the <name ref="#tank">tank</name> out for <seg ana="metaphor">a spin</seg> and were not able to get it up out of
                 <lb/>the <geogFeat>bight</geogFeat> so they left it there. They gave it another try tonight
                 <lb/>but it was <seg ana="metaphor">no soap</seg>. They will have to wait a while longer until
                 <lb/>the surface gets a little harder. <del rend="strikethrough">They</del> The boys don't do much
                 <lb/>work around here but they do sit and <seg ana="metaphor">chew the fat</seg>. More 
                 <lb/><choice><sic>arguements</sic><corr>arguments</corr></choice> can arise over the most obscure&#x2014;and some not
                 <lb/>so obscure&#x2014;topics that I have <choice><sic>every</sic><corr>ever</corr></choice> imagined. Right
                 <lb/>now the cook who has been considered&#x2014;by himself&#x2014;an authority
                 <lb/>on almost any subject one can bring up has been telling the boys             
         <pb facs="journal-2-17.jpg" n="/7/7720f3e3-93eb-47d7-a27e-68622120c331"/>
         <fw type="pageNum" place="top">13</fw>
               <lb/>that he rolls <del rend="strikethrough">the</del> oranges before squeezing out the the juice in order
               <lb/>to get the citric acid out of the skin. <persName ref="#Shirley">Shirley</persName> argues that he
               <lb/>rolls the oranges in order to break the skin and the cellular
               <lb/>structure inside. They appealed to me being the chemist to
               <lb/>settle the argument.  I tried to <seg ana="metaphor">steer clear</seg> but finally sided
               <lb/>with <persName ref="#Shirley">Shirley</persName> which action made the cook <seg ana="metaphor">leak water</seg> a
               <lb/>little --- but not much.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>I began reading <title>Gone with the Wind</title><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="#NoteGTW"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="NoteGTW">The 1936 novel by Margaret Mitchell about the fate of plantation heiress Scarlett O'Hara, infamous for its almost nostalgic portrayal of slavery and plantation life, but also extremely popular internationally to this day. Famously adapted into the 1939 film starring Vivien Leigh and Clark Gable, which Lockhart also discusses<bibl><ref target="#WikiGWTW">"Gone with the Wind. Wikipedia."</ref></bibl></note> and hope it won't
               <lb/>take too much of my time.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>I have come back from the trail with an intense desire to
               <lb/>do some more camping - preferably in <country ref="#Canada">Canada</country> - and all the
               <lb/>other activities that go with it hunting and fishing. I
               <lb/>presume that the best way to begin is to go some advertised 
               <lb/>camp and hire a guide for a week or so. <del rend="strikethrough">I shall get</del>
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>I shall get out of this mess here and go to bed where
               <lb/>I can read in peace.
            </p>
         </div>
         <pb facs="journal-2-18.jpg" n="/9/9940712b-a2cd-4eaa-92a9-e650af6a8fd1"/>
         <fw type="pageNum" place="top">14</fw>
         <div xml:id="eel-19411231" type="entry">
            <lb/><dateline><del rend="strikethrough">Wednesday January 1 1941</del>
               <lb/><del rend="strikethrough">At last the new year has</del>
              <lb/><date when="1941-12-31"></date>Tuesday December 31 1941 <corr evidence="internal">(1940)</corr></dateline>
            <p>
               <lb/>We have been operating such an erratic schedule and
               <lb/>also have to deal with <term>Greenwich Mean Time</term><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="#GMT"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="GMT">Because the expedition is at one of the poles, they technically are in all time zones at once but experience it as a single day. They appear to have chosen GMT as their offical time to go by, which Lockhart has here temporarily lost track of.<bibl><ref target="#GMTAntarctica">"Antarctica"</ref></bibl></note> that
               <lb/>I have been confused concerning the day and date for
               <lb/>several days. Yesterday I thought today was to be New Year
               <lb/>and now that we are actually in the New Year by camp
               <lb/>schedule I am still during today.  Now, however, I think 
               <lb/>I am fairly well straightened out.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>Yesterday which normally would have been written up early
               <lb/>this morning <seg ana="metaphor">slipped by</seg> with no entry entirely because I had
               <lb/>gotten so far into <title>Gone with the Wind</title> <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="#NoteGTW2"/><note xml:id="NoteGTW2" type="annotation" resp="ed">See note on page 17</note>that wartime was a thing
               <lb/>of minor importance.  I read that amazing <subst><del rend="strikethrough">epis</del><add place="above">narrative</add></subst> of life
               <lb/>among the Southerners during the <name>Civil War</name> days until almost
               <lb/>AM.  I wasn't reading all of the time but enough of the time 
               <lb/>so that work which should be the main object these days
               <lb/>stagnated.  The book which begins <del rend="strikethrough">I</del> mildly and almost
               <lb/>boringly soon gets under way and its power makes itself
               <lb/>evident.  <region>The South</region> which has been a mystery to me and
               <lb/>no doubt to countless other <name>Americans</name> will soon become in
               <lb/>my mind something more than the land of cotton, belles,
               <lb/>"gentlemen" and mint juleps.  Perhaps even the answer to 
               <lb/>the legendary or hereditary hate most <name>Southerners</name> have 
               <lb/>for <name>Northeners</name> in general would be evident.  At any rate
               <lb/>I felt then that I should get a little American History into
            </p>
         <pb facs="journal-2-19.jpg" n="/D/deb45e3a-81a3-4f00-b7e3-88e35c2e76c7"/>
            <p>
               <lb/>my head in an entirely pleasant manner.  Now after
               <lb/>having continued my reading through that part of the book
               <lb/>in which the war has ended and the "Cause" lost <del rend="strikethrough">do</del> I do
               <lb/>begin to get the idea underlying all of the hatred that has
               <lb/>been instilled in the present generation by parents, grand
               <lb/>parents or even great grand parents the latter of whom were
               <lb/>the younger generation of those never-to-be-forgotten days.
               <lb/>If the Yankees had been able to win the war without
               <lb/>the <persName ref="#ANB">Sherman</persName>-in-<placeName ref="#Atlanta">Atlanta</placeName> episode perhaps all of the
               <lb/>stigma which now is attached <del rend="strikethrough">th</del>to the word Northener
               <lb/>might have been avoided.  Conerning the <name>Civil War</name> no
               <lb/>one can say "that's all ancient History" because in
               <lb/>the South, as far as I can gather from some of the Southern boys
               <lb/>here, the <name type="event">Civil War</name> is still being fought with almost the 
               <lb/>same intensity as in the days of the actual war itself.  I
               <lb/>am now about to embark on the history of the post war days
               <lb/>which are to be considered as bad if not worse than <del>those</del>
               <lb/>the war days themselves.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>Yesterday I worked on <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> again and today should have
               <lb/>worked <del>of</del> on <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack Richardson</persName> but he was up even later
               <lb/>than I so I didn't bother to wake him at ten this morning.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>Last night part of the time was spent analyzing air
               <lb/>samples that had been taken outside. The interesting part
               <lb/>of this work was the very low percentage of oxygen in the air
               <lb/>the carbon dioxide value which was relatively quite high
               <lb/>was not as accurate a result as the oxygen value so cannot
               <lb/>hold as much importance as the latter.  In taking these
            <pb facs="journal-2-20.jpg" n="/2/260a8f2d-eed9-433a-b3a2-677212c7965e"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">16</fw>
                  <lb/>samples I am cooperating with <persName ref="#Court">Court</persName> the meteorologist who
                  <lb/>tells me when to take the samples. The prime requisite is
                  <lb/>that the wind must have been blowing steadily from one
                  <lb/>direction for more than six hours. I shall do as many
                  <lb/>of these analyses as time and energy — mostly energy — will
                  <lb/>permit. When correlated with the weather data <persName ref="#Court">Court</persName> has they
                  <lb/>should be of some value to whomever studies that sort of
                  <lb/>thing. My interest in the matter lies only in the fact that
                  <lb/>I may be the only man for some time to come who will have
                  <lb/>an accurate apparatus for gas analysis here in the <placeName>Antarctic</placeName>.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I tried to get some shots at skua gulls with the hand
                  <lb/>gun but evidently they have become somewhat man shy because
                  <lb/>I couldn't get close enough to shoot. I shall have to learn
                  <lb/>to shoot the shot gun so that I can get them <del rend="overwritten">i</del>on the wing.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Tonight at radio schedule time we learned that the boys
                  <lb/>want to abandon the tractor; they just can't make any progress
                  <lb/>at all. The tractor goes into the snow up to its belly even
                  <lb/>with no load. In order not to l<gap reason="overwritten"/>ose the valuable loads which
                  <lb/>have been made even heavier by the addition of the outpost's
                  <lb/>stuff it has been decided to send <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> and <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack</persName> out with
                  <lb/>18 dogs and two sleds. <persName ref="#Ferranto">Ferranto</persName> is hauling several dog sleds
                  <lb/>which are extra so that the single <del rend="strikethrough">do</del> sled dog teams can
                  <lb/>once more be <del rend="strikethrough">brought ba</del> made double sled dog teams. At
                  <lb/>least <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> and <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack</persName> will be able to carry home all the gear
                  <lb/>our party left with the tractor and probably some besides. We
                  <lb/>sure hope that the scientific specimens can be brought back.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/><persName ref="#Perk">Jack Perkins</persName> has just completed some beautiful jobs on the
            <pb facs="journal-2-21" n="/6/62075637-9661-48cc-b73d-16b55c7b6a3c"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">17</fw>
                  <lb/>Adelie an Emperor and a snowy petrel. The skins have
                  <lb/>turned out beautifully.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Yesterday I had messages from <persName ref="#mamma">mamma</persName> and <persName ref="#Beatie">Beatie</persName>
                  <lb/>and in <persName ref="#mamma">mamma's</persName> she said that she was expecting a penguin
                  <lb/>skin and since there seem to be plenty of Emperors around
                  <lb/>perhaps I should get busy and skin one myself. I
                  <lb/>hope to get an Adelie at least later on. They are small
                  <lb/>enough <del rend="strikethrough">to</del> not to be <choice> <sic>to</sic> <corr>too</corr></choice> bothersome and would make
                  <lb/>something really unique for a den. I hope also to get
                  <lb/>a skua gull and a snowy petrel but the chances are
                  <lb/>I shan't be able to.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I had a message from the <persName ref="#Guernsey"><choice> <sic>Guernsey's</sic> <corr>Guernseys</corr></choice></persName> today <del rend="strikethrough">wh</del>
                  <lb/>wishing me a happy new year and a safe return. I
                  <lb/>have also had a message from <persName ref="#Mary">Mary</persName> and <persName ref="#Carl">Carl</persName> but at the
                  <lb/>moment I can't remember what day it came in. I
                  <lb/>certainly am anxious to get home. I can see now that
                  <lb/>I shan't spend much time travelling across country. When
                  <lb/>I start for home I shall want to get there as soon as
                  <lb/>possible.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>We almost made a broadcast today. This is the second
                  <lb/>time I have almost made one from down here. <persName>Wag<gap rend="overwritten"/>ner</persName>
                  <lb/>the short wave director and sponsor of the <affiliation>Mail Bag</affiliation> wanted
                  <lb/>to have both bases say something <gap reason="overwritten"/>for New Years to the folks
                  <lb/>in the <country>United States</country>. Conditions have been so bad recently
                  <lb/>that little hope for a strong signal was held. They
                  <lb/>had trouble pulling <placeName ref="#EastBase">East Base</placeName> through but they finally did
                  <lb/>It was not until about an hour and a half later that our
            <pb facs="journal-2-22" n="/e/ee43a5aa-0d07-45c2-b54b-dbf8b7e67102"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">18</fw>
                  <lb/>signal came through strongly enough for rebroadcasting.
                  <lb/>The signal strength held only for a few minutes <gap rend="overwritten"/>and not
                  <lb/>long enough for our choral singing to take place. At
                  <lb/>the last minute almost a few of us worked out the words
                  <lb/>to <title level="a">Auld Lang Syne</title> and <title level="a">Show Me the Way to Go Home</title>. None
                  <lb/>of us knew all of both songs completely. <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> was to
                  <lb/>accompany us with his <gap rend="overwritten"/><choice><abbr>uke</abbr><expan>ukelele</expan></choice>. Just as we were about to
                  <lb/>go on our signal strength dropped and our chance was
                  <lb/>gone. Ah well another time maybe.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>And now to bed.
               </p>
                  <lb/>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="eel-19410101a" type="entry">
                  <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-01">January 1 194<del rend="overwritten">0</del>1 Wednesday.</date></dateline>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Happy new year! This is one of the strangest new <gap rend="overwritten"/> years
                  <lb/>I have had since I can <del rend="strikethrough">rembe</del> remember. Its strangeness
                  <lb/>lies in the fact that it is just like any other day I have had
                  <lb/>since my return to camp. More likely it will be similar to
                  <lb/>Christmas a week ago in that we shall have turkey but beyond
                  <lb/>that it's just another day to be marked off on the calendar
                  <lb/>signifying that one less day must be lived through until the
                  <lb/>ships come, depart and we are home again.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Home again! What visions in the future that small phrase
                  <lb/>conjures up! <del rend="strikethrough">All though</del> Although I am certain I have work
                  <lb/>which will be of some <gap rend="overwritten"/>inor importance in the scientific literature
                  <lb/>th<gap rend="overwritten"/>e greatest gain comes to me in a personal way. I am now
                  <lb/>a firm believer that one trained so completely in theoretical matters
                  <lb/>as I have been in the past should go away on an expedition for
                  <lb/>a year or two; here in this small world of ours, for instance, one                  
               <pb facs="journal-2-23.jpg" n="/4/498886ed-6a42-4026-9b5f-75b211d23125"/>
               <fw type="pageNum" place="top">19</fw>
           
               <lb/>meets men from many walks of life and learns quickly
               <lb/>to adjust oneself to meet each personality. One learns
               <lb/>the meaning of work and what a working man thinks 
               <lb/>about the type of work not requiring a strong back and 
               <lb/>plenty of perspiration. One learns many new handicrafts 
               <lb/>under the guidance - <del rend="strikethrough">half heart</del> half hearted sometimes to be sure - 
               <lb/>of men who might be <unclear cert="high">classed</unclear> as masters of their arts. If one 
               <lb/>is so priviled<add place="above">g</add>ed that <del type="strikethrough">his</del><add place="above">ones</add> work involves a trail trip then the
               <lb/>art of living among the elements and on only the bare necessities
               <lb/>one acquires a confidence, an assurance and an interest <!-- confident about the word, but it has some larger gaps or spaces in between letters -->
               <lb/>in things utterly foreign to one's early training and profits
               <lb/>according to one's ability to absorb and retain. Many small 
               <lb/>never-to-be-forgotten incidents are <unclear>engraved</unclear> in one's mental 
               <lb/>filing cabinet and whether or not they serve as the basis for 
               <lb/>future activities remain if only as memories. It is as though
               <lb/>an encyclopedia of many phases of life has been opened; those
               <lb/>with eyes ear and tongue profit. I am sure that my
               <lb/>home life in the future will be immeasurably more pleasant
               <lb/>because I have invested several years to reap my <unclear cert="high">interest</unclear>
               <lb/>some time later. Time alone will tell the actual value of this
               <lb/>trip to the <placeName>Antarctic</placeName> and the time when dividends should be
               <lb/>showing begins almost immediately. 
               <lb/> 
           </p>
            </div>
              <div xml:id="eel-19410103" type="entry">
                  
                    <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-03"><del rend="strikethough">Tuesday</del><add place="above">Friday</add> January <del type="strikethough">2</del><add place="above">3</add> 1940</date> </dateline><!-- in the id it gives the correct date; not sure how to indicate his error of writing 1940 when it should be 1941 -->
                 <p>
                 <lb/>Alarm clocks have no place in my system of living. Never
                 <lb/>have I used one as a constant companion and now that 
                 <lb/>I am using one I don't go by it. Since I have been trying to
                 
              
           <pb facs="journal-2-24.jpg" n="/8/821a5dea-fe96-424f-bd0a-8acf8941c8f6"/>  
           <fw type="pageNum" place="top">20</fw> 
           
                 <lb/>to<!-- yes there are two tos --> get up at least by <time>ten</time> in order to <unclear cert="high">run</unclear> metabolism tests<!-- comma would make sense here -->
                 <lb/>I have borrowed <persName ref="#Court">Court's</persName> alarm clock but when it rings I
                 <lb/>just shut it off without waking up and go back to sleep<unclear>.</unclear> Some
                 <lb/>of the fellows ask me to call them at specific times but usually I
                 <lb/>forget until sometime<!-- until and sometime are written a bit more faintly than the rest of the text --> later. No damage has been done yet<!-- might not be period here --><unclear>.</unclear> </p>
                 <p> 
                 <lb/>There was some excitement here last night. I didn't stay up 
                 <lb/>to follow it completely but did get in on the tail end<unclear>.</unclear> The trail
                 <lb/>parties have been dogged<!-- ged fainter --> unfortunately by soft surface<!-- t and surface fainter --> and heavy 
                 <lb/>loads and are getting low on gas for the tractor and dog food.
                 <lb/>Last night after the schedule the airplane gang decided to take the
                 <lb/><name type="aircraft" ref="#Condor">Condor</name> out with supplies and bring back some of the load<unclear>.</unclear><!-- very faint dot looks like a faded period here and is a good word space away from typical end of sentence punctuation -->
                 <lb/>The weather was not so hot<!-- was not so hot fainter --> with some overcast coming in from
                 <lb/>the east. They took off about 11PM and <unclear cert="high">soon</unclear> reported that <!-- faint dot at the edge of the right margin -->
                 <lb/>the overcast was becoming heavier. Not long after<!-- after a bit fainter --> they said they 
                 <lb/>saw the dog teams at <placeName>71</placeName> but because of overcast could not land.
                 <lb/>They passed over the expectant men and flew on to the tractor 
                 <lb/>party which was at <placeName>92</placeName>. There they were able to land leave some
                 <lb/>food and gas and take on some load<unclear>.</unclear> As they rose into
                 <lb/>the air to make another attempt to land at <placeName>71</placeName><unclear>,</unclear><!-- the comma is very faint --> the star <!-- if that is a period this might be a new sentence; hard to tell with the "t" -->
                 <lb/>board motor began sputtering and finally died altogether<unclear>.</unclear><!-- seems to be the end of a sentence but no punctuation; his punctuation here is rather uncharacteristically lax; perhaps he was writing quickly or when he was half-asleep? -->
                 <lb/>The plane made a safe landing at about <placeName>80</placeName> midway 
                 <lb/>between the <unclear cert="high">parties</unclear> and after making a rapid check up
                 <lb/>found that #4<!-- # sign written high and not on the line --> cylinder had failed and the piston had 
                 <lb/>gone right through the cowling. Since this was the master 
                 <lb/>cylinder things looked black. <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> and <persName ref="#pappygray">Pappy</persName> warmed
                 <lb/>up the <name type="aircraft" ref="#Beechcraft">Beechcraft</name> and took off about <time>2:30 AM</time> <persName ref="#PappyGray">Pappy</persName> had
                 <lb/>all the spare cylinder gear he could find in the shop but
                 
             
               <pb facs="journal-2-25.jpg" n="/4/4e9c39a9-e9f6-4c9a-9d6a-6d2f89f42729"/>
              <fw type="pageNum" place="top">21<!-- seems faintly underlined and written on a slant in the very rounded corner of the page --> </fw>
                 
                 <lb/>to no avail what was needed was a complete new engine.
                 <lb/><persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> brought back <persName ref="#PappyGray">Pappy</persName> and <persName ref="#Giles">Giles</persName> and then went out
                 <lb/>for <persName ref="#Siple">Paul</persName> and <persName ref="#Mac">Mac</persName>. <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> had to go all the way to the 
                 <lb/>tractor and then to the plane. The overcast that had been
                 <lb/>increasing had become so bad that <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> was afraid 
                 <lb/>he had missed the plane when he had flown some time 
                 <lb/>and had just decided to make <del rend="strikethrough"><unclear>tlo</unclear>back</del> tracks back to 
                    <lb/>the base when the <name type="aircraft" ref="#Condor">Condor</name> loomed up. He landed <del rend="strikethrough"><unclear>too</unclear></del> and 
                 <lb/>while <persName ref="#Siple">Paul</persName><!-- Paul is written somewhat faintly --> and <persName ref="#Mac">Mac</persName> were getting ready took off again 
                 <lb/><add place="above" rend="^">accompanied by <persName>Paul</persName></add> with food and dog food for the dog team parties. They
                 <lb/>could fly no more than 25 feet off the ground - overcast
                 <lb/><unclear confidence=".4">pinning</unclear> them down but made the trip of 10 miles successfully <unclear>.</unclear>
                 <lb/>After a few minutes of greetings and <unclear cert="high">fare wells</unclear> they went 
                    <lb/>back to the <name type="aircraft" ref="#Condor">Condor</name>. After packing in as much gear a<!-- something written over the "a" -->s the
                 <lb/>little plane would stand the three men turned for home
                    <lb/>leaving the <name type="aircraft" ref="#Condor">Condor</name> in what will probably be her last  
                 <lb/>landing place. She tried to do her job but just wasn't 
                 <lb/>good enough. <persName ref="#Pete">Pete</persName> had some difficulty getting down here 
                 <lb/>at the base but landed safely. Now the trail parties 
                 <lb/>will have to battle their way in and the <name type="airfact" ref="#
                    ">Beechcraft</name> will
                    <lb/>make some flights out to the <name type="aircraft" ref="#Condor">Condor</name> to salvage some of the 
                 <lb/>valuable instruments such as the drift indicator worth about 
                 <lb/>$1500. We all are happy that the accident didn't happen
                    <lb/>when the <name type="aircraft" ref="#Condor">Condor</name> was 500 miles from the base. </p>
                 <p>
                 <lb/>My reading has tended to be southern in nature<unclear>.</unclear>
                 <lb/>After finishing <title>Gone with the Wind</title><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="#NoteGTW3"/> <note resp="ed" xml:id="NoteGTW3" type="annotation">See note on page 17</note><!-- might be a slightly larger space than usual after Wind --> I started in on <title>South
                 <lb/>Moon Under</title><!-- might be another slightly space after Under --> and found it to be concerned with poor
            
                    <pb facs="journal 2-26" n= "/6/619ac374-eef5-49d7-8b1c-12661079e5ed"/>
                 <fw type="pagenumber" place="top left">22</fw>
              
                  <lb/>whites in <placeName>Florida</placeName>. I have spoken to <persName ref="#Shirley">Shirley</persName> about it and 
                  <lb/>hope he <unclear cert="high">reads</unclear> it. I should like to know if it at all <unclear cert="unknown">aw</unclear>
                  <lb/>accurate picture of the State where he lived much of his boyhood.
                  <lb/><title level="m">Gone with the Wind</title><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="NoteGTW4"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="NoteGTW4" type="annotation">See note on page 17</note> tapered off slightly in <unclear cert="high">interest</unclear> and left me
                  <lb/>hanging in the air. I am not certain whether <persName type="fictional">Rhett Butler</persName>
                  <lb/>and <persName type="fictional">Scarlett</persName> should have found happiness or whether the ending 
                  <lb/>as <persName>Margaret Mitchell</persName> made it was more in keeping with the
                  <lb/>whole <unclear cert="high">tone</unclear> of the book and a just reward for <persName type="fictional">Scarlett</persName>. As I
                  <lb/>read the book and thought about the movie that has been made
                  <lb/>from it <persName>Clark Gable</persName> certainly is the man to play <persName type="fictional">Rhett Butler</persName>
                    <lb/>I am not so sure about <persName>Vivien Leigh</persName> as <persName type="fictional">Scarlett</persName><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="notemovies3"/>
                    <note resp="ed" xml:id="notemovies3">The film <title level="a">Gone with the Wind</title> was released in 1939 to rave reviews. Like Lockhart, the producers found Scarlett O'Hara difficult to cast; over 1,400 actresses auditioned for the part before Vivian Leigh was chosen. <bibl><ref target="#IMBdGwtW"><title level="a">Gone with the Wind</title></ref></bibl></note>!
                  </p>
                  <p>
                  <lb/>We had a mail bag today from <placeName>Kansas City</placeName> but <unclear cert="high">the</unclear> re-
                  <lb/>ception fell off so abruptly after the variety <unclear cert="low">here</unclear> that the letters
                  <lb/>were heard only very indistinctly. I know I had one letter <!--the fact tha he's talking bout hearing letters makes it very confusing as to what type of messege he's talking about. Or he made a typo when he wrote 'heard'--> from
                  <lb/><unclear cert="medium"><persName ref="#mamma">mamma</persName></unclear> but couldn't even get the gist of the letter.
                  </p>
                  <p>
                  <lb/><unclear cert="high"><persName ref="#Asman">Asman</persName></unclear> has been taking the <unclear cert="high">tank</unclear> out every night now that
                  <lb/>the temperature has fallen somewhat. He is trying to make a 
                  <lb/>hard path from here to the old cache so that he can get
                  <lb/>some of the boxes down there. Tonight he got stuck and had to 
                  <lb/>abandon a load he was attempting to haul. 
                  </p>
                  <p>
                  <lb/>Got in another air analysis but aside from that I have done
                  <lb/>nothing constructive all day. I've got to get <unclear cert="low">in</unclear> the <unclear cert="low">half</unclear>.
                  </p>
                  <p>
                  <lb/>The ice shows no signs of breaking out of <placeName>the Bay</placeName>. <unclear cert="high">It</unclear> <unclear cert="high">sure</unclear>  
                  <lb/>will be a job loading if some of it at least doesn't go out - and 
                  <lb/>soon.  
             </p>
              </div>

               <div xml:id="eel-19410104" type="entry">    
                <pb facs="journal 2-27" n="/f/f41e9278-255c-4170-950b-f3f63d03fe4f"/>
               <fw type="pagenumber" place="topright">23</fw>
               <lb/><dateline><date>Saturday January 4th 1941</date></dateline>       
           <p> 
                <lb/>Until the ships arrive, the days will be quite the same
                <lb/>only occasional variation will relieve the monotony which is 
                <lb/>heightened because the <unclear cert="high">hour</unclear> of departure is indeed not far off. 
                <lb/>The variety of today's <unclear reason="script" cert="high">routine</unclear> was the trip I took with the dogs
                <lb/>down to <placeName>the Bay</placeName>. After dinner I got <unclear cert="high"><persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName></unclear> to help me haul
                <lb/>a seal out of the tunnel <del>and</del> in order to have something to feed
                <lb/>the dogs after we got back. While we were waiting for
                <lb/><persName ref="#Court">Court</persName> who was to accompany us <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName>and I dug out the 
                <lb/>sled and harnessed the dogs. <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName>then skied off in the 
                <lb/>direction of the tank which had stopped about <num type="fraction">1/2</num> mile from
                <lb/>camp. I had put on <unclear cert="high">my</unclear> skiis <!--he writes the workd 'skis' strangely here. There is an extra dot which seems like it goes with an extra letter i --> and was about to <unclear cert="medium">reach</unclear> the
                <lb/><unclear cert="unknown">ge</unclear> <!--I honestly have no clue what these couple of letters are, excpt that they are not part of the word before them--> pole when the team started with <persName ref="#Court">Court</persName> aboard. <!--He wrote a word that startes with a capital C and ends with a lowwercase t, but I can't tell what it is. In context, its ptobably not a person or a dog; the dogs were pulling the sled with it and Lockhart told them to stop. If it was a person, then the person would have told the dogs to do that. --> I
                <lb/>shouted myself hoarse in <num type="cardinal">thirty</num> seconds trying to get them
                <lb/>to stop. <name type="dog">Spot</name> could hear me and wanted to stop but
                <lb/>the onward ruch of my <unclear cert="low">nea</unclear> quartet that really wanted to
                <lb/>go made him keep going. They finally stopped several 
                <lb/>hundred yards out of camp. When I came up they were 
                <lb/>stil very anxious to get going but I made them get down
                <lb/>and wait for my command to go. <name type="dog">Spot</name> answered the
                <lb/>commands very well and we headed toward the tank which 
                <lb/>had started back toward the camp. <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> thought he would 
                <lb/>ski ahead and make a trail so that the team would follow
                <lb/>but the team went right by him. I stopped and he joined 
                <lb/><persName ref="#Court">Court</persName> in the shed giving me a load of about <num type="cardinal">300</num> <measure>lbs</measure>. The dogs
                <lb/>were breathing hard now but their enthusiasm was unlimited. 
                <lb/><name type="dog">Spot</name> was right out in front with his line tight and behaved
              
              <pb facs="journal 2-28" n="/4/41ed994d-53c8-48d4-a6a3-45841f33f590"/>
              <fw type="pahenumber" place="top left">24</fw>
            
                 <lb/>beautifully. We finally hit the trail to the barrier cache <!--the last three latters of the world barrier are pretty smudged here-->
                 <lb/>and as we headed toward it we saw <persName><name type="nickname">Pappy</name>Gray</persName> in the 
                 <lb/>distance with his great team of three dogs. I stopped
                 <lb/>and waited for him to come up and there he followed me
                 <lb/>down to the barrels. We parked the teams and went to the
                 <lb/>edge and saw several seals spouting in one of the cracks
                 <lb/>Those seals don't know it yet but they will become dog meat
                 <lb/>before long: <!-- The period here has a second dot above it so it looks like a colon; in context it could easily be read as a period--> We shall take the whole bunch of dogs down to
                 <lb/>the barrier hill seals and haul<del>e</del> <!-- the e he deleted here was on the end of the word haul--> them to the top by dogs and
                 <lb/>after cleaning them bring them back to camp. 
            </p>
            <p>
                 <lb/>A great deal of ice is just about ready to crack out and 
                 <lb/>a good strong sough wind should carry out a great deal
                 <lb/>of it.   With only about a week to go before <name type="ship">The Bear</name> gets 
                 <lb/>here perhaps much of it will go out. 
            </p>
            <p>
                 <lb/>We finally headed for home with my dogs leading. 
                 <lb/> <unclear cert="unknown">Iuti</unclear> dogs kept right bahind and in a few minutes we were
                 <lb/>back in camp.    
            </p>
            <p>
                 <lb/>I then fed the dogs and left them tired but contented
                 <lb/>Before going to bed I did an air sample and read a
                 <lb/>little. After I was in bed I also read. My bedtime reading 
               <lb/>consists of <title type="no-fictionalbook">Homo versus Mr <persName>Darwin</persName></title><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="NoteLyon"/> <note resp="ed" xml:id="NoteLyon">Much like Lockhart describes, a book that examines statements Darwin made before or around 1872 on his then recently published The Descent of Man, that takes a mostly negative stance on his work. <bibl><ref target="#LyonDarwin">"Homo vs. Darwin"</ref></bibl></note>a discussion of <persName>Darwin</persName>
                 <lb/>then most recent book <title type="non-fictionalbook">The Descent of Man</title>. I bought the former
                 <lb/>in <placeName ref="#NewZealand">New Zealand</placeName> to accompany the latter which I have at home
            </p>
            <p>
                 <lb/>It was <time>three AM</time> before I turned out the light. I was
                 <lb/>fearful for my early rising but I didn't have anything particular
                 <lb/>to do tomorrow so I <!--Here the word I looks like it was added in after the words arounf it--> can sleep in if I feel that way.    
            </p>
           </div>
           
           <pb facs="journal-2-29" n="/3/32efdaee-b13d-4de5-a78b-8a38d1d92f44"/>
           <fw type="pageNum" place="topright">25</fw>
            
            <div xml:id="eel-19410105a" type="entry">
               <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-05">Sunday January 5 1941</date></dateline>
               <p>
                  <lb/>As I expected I didn't get up very early. I woke up at
                  <lb/>930 and thought I would lie there until 10 but I fell
                  <lb/>asleep again and didn't wake again until 1130.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>After doing an air sample I read most of the afternoon
                  <lb/>I am learning a great deal from <title level="m" ref="Stefansson">Hunters of the Great North</title><ptr target="NoteStefansson" type="noteAnchor"/><note xml:id="NoteStefansson" resp="ed">An account of Vilhjalmur Stefansson's Alaskan expedition in 1906-1907 <bibl><ref target="#Stefansson">"Hunters of the Great North"</ref></bibl> </note>
                  <lb/>and was especially please to come <del rend="strikethrough">a pa</del> across a passage
                  <lb/>on dog driving which was my theory of dog driving in black
                  <lb/>and white; it goes as follows. page 118. <quote>"The Eskimo idea
                  <lb/>was that a dog should be treated with great consideration, and
                  <lb/>his opinion was that a good dog would pull about as long as he
                  <lb/>has any strength without being whipped. . . . that the only
                  <lb/>approved Eskimo method of inducing dogs to work is either by
                  <lb/>shouting to them and trying to cheer them up by <supplied reason="omitted from the transcription of the source">the</supplied> voice, or else
                  <lb/>by having some person walk ahead of the team of whom the dogs
                  <lb/>are so fond that they will pull hard to try to keep up. I
                  <lb/>regret to say that during the twelve years following 1906 the
                  <lb/><placeName>Mackenzie River</placeName> Eskimos adopted the custom of whipping dogs.<del>"</del>
                  <lb/>. . . . that whipping tired dogs was one of the white man's
                  <lb/>customs."</quote>
                  <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="hunters"/><note xml:id="hunters" resp="ed">
                     Lockhart quotes this long passage out of order. The clause "that whipping tired dogs was one of the white man's customs"
                     occurs before the rest of the passage quoted here <bibl><ref target="#Stefansson">Stefansson 118</ref></bibl>.
                  </note>My short experience on the trail has <choice><sic>lead</sic><corr>led</corr></choice> me to
                  <lb/>agree whole heartedly with this. I do whip a lead
                  <lb/>dog when he won't keep his line tight but only enough to
                  <lb/>convince the dog that he is doing something wrong. These
                  <lb/>dogs are so intelligent that they know when they aren't
                  <lb/>working as they should. I never beat a dog and never
                  <lb/>hit one hard enough to lame it or make it sore.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>As a governor on my impatience I usually use my hand
               <pb facs="journal-2-30" n="/3/3e5d8217-95b3-4431-b19b-f90dd2b900ec"/> 
               <fw type="pageNum" place="topleft">26</fw>
                  <lb/>knowing that I won't hit hard enought to hurt my hand.
                  <lb/>One day, however, <name type="dog" ref="#Sheila">Sheila</name> tried to bite me when I was
                  <lb/>freeing her from the gang line and I really laced into
                  <lb/>her. Biting is one thing that should never be tolerated in
                  <lb/>dogs. Sometimes when I have boxed <name type="dog" ref="#Spot">Spot</name>'s ears he has
                  <lb/>reached up and taken my gloved hand but to show he
                  <lb/>was only protesting my action he never closed down
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I have noticed several times the pups which are running
                  <lb/>loose, would try to steal a piece of meat from one of the tethered
                  <lb/>dogs. The true viciousness of the large dogs immediately comes
                  <lb/>out and luckily for the small dogs they scamper away but only
                  <lb/>in the nick of time. I should hate to say what would happen
                  <lb/>to a pup should a dog like <name type="dog" ref="#Spot">Spot</name> get a good grip on it when
                  <lb/>no one was around.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I am trying to train <name type="dog" ref="#Spot">Spot</name> not to touch his meat until
                  <lb/>I tell him to. He does very well and lets me take meat
                  <lb/>away from him after he has started to eat. He is really
                  <lb/>a good dog. I sent a message to <persName ref="#Beatie">Beatie</persName> telling her
                  <lb/>to feed <name type="dog" ref="#Petedog">Pete</name> well because I was bringing a 90 lb dog
                  <lb/>home. Just wait until they see him.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>This evening we had a reshow of <title level="m" ref="#Blondie">Blondie</title><ptr type="noteAnchor" target="notemovies4"/>
                  <note resp="ed" xml:id="notemovies4">A 1938 comedy starring Penny Singleton as Blondie Bumstead. This was the first of 28 movies about Blondie and her husband Dagwood.<bibl><ref target="#IMBdB"><title level="a">Blondie</title></ref></bibl></note> which made
                  <lb/>us laugh as much as if it were only the first time we had
                  <lb/>seen it.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I have <persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> in the basket tomorrow so I think I
                  <lb/>shall go to bed now. It is almost two AM.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/><persName ref="#Cruzen">Cruzen</persName> has been made a commander.
               </p>
               <p>
                  The dog teams should be in sometime soon—several days.
               </p>
            </div>
           <pb facs="journal-2-31" n="/0/0809ecaf-5206-4733-b003-546f2f045970"/> 
           <fw type="pageNum" place="top-right">27</fw>
           <div xml:id="eel-19410109a" type="entry">
              <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-09">Thursday January 9<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> 1941</date></dateline>
              <p>
                 <lb/>Things have been happening around here so rapidly
                 <lb/>that I haven't been able to find time even to sit down
                 <lb/>for a few minutes and at the moment I shall be
                 <lb/>able to make only a few notes.
              </p>
              <p>
                 <lb/>Today at 8 PM we hear that the <name type="ship">Bear</name> was
                 <lb/>only 190 miles from <geogName>the Bay</geogName> and with clear sailing
                 <lb/>should be in tomorrow afternoon about 6 PM. <persName>Jack</persName> and
                 <lb/><persName>Doug</persName> have taken a trail tent down to the barrier and
                 <lb/>are spending the nigth there. I doubt, however, that they
                 <lb/>will be the first to see the <name type="ship">Bear</name> come in. She won't
                 <lb/>really be able to come in because the ice hasn't gone
                 <lb/>out yet. We <del rend="strikethrough"><unclear>not</unclear></del> may have a job loading stuff but
                 <lb/><del rend="strikethrough">at</del> right now we hope only to be able to get out far
                 <lb/>enough so that we can get our mail.
              </p>
              <p>
                 <lb/>The weather was good enough today so that the
                 <lb/><rs>Beechcraft</rs> was able to make two flights out to the <name type="aircraft">Conder</name>.
                 <lb/>The drift <unclear>sought</unclear> some radio gear and all the d<del rend="overwritten">a</del>uffle bags
                 <lb/><del rend="overwritten"><unclear>sm</unclear></del> minus some of their content were brought in. The
                 <lb/><name type="ship">Conder</name> is now at the mercy of the elements forever.
              </p>
              <p>
                 <lb/>During the past three days I have been making
                 <lb/>daily runs down to the <hi rend="underlined">old ca</hi>che  to pick up a seal and
                 <lb/>bring it back to camp. Twelve seal have been killed so far
                 <lb/>and about 6 have been brought back. Today while
                 <lb/>I was down onn the bay ice having parked the team up
                 <lb/>above on the barrier my companions, <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> <persName><addName type="nickname">Doc</addName></persName> and <persName>Joe
                 <lb/>Wells</persName>, and I were disturbed in our picture taking and
                 <pb facs="journal-2-32" n="/1/10894952-c9d4-42f8-bd1b-9ef6df38aca7"/>
                 <fw type= "pageNum" place="top">28</fw>
                 <lb/>fun with the seals by the noise of a dog fight. We
                 <lb/>hurried up and found the team had moved about 
                 <lb/>100 yards and that most of the dogs were all tangled
                 <lb/>up. After straightening them up I found <name type="dog">Shippy</name>
                 <lb/>tangled up in his harness and a sorry looking mess
                 <lb/>he had a bad gash under his left forearm and was
                 <lb/>in such poor shape although alive that if <persName>Joe</persName> had
                 <lb/>had any shells left in the 45 I should have put him
                 <lb/>out of his misery right then. I tied him on the sled and
                 <lb/>had <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName>hold him while we made the trip back to camp.
                 <lb/>After arrival at camp I went in to get a revolver and shells
                 <lb/>and told <persName>Siple</persName> that I was going to shoot the dog. He
                 <lb/>wanted me to get <persName>Dick's</persName> opinion on the dog's condition. When
                 <lb/><persName>Dick</persName> saw him he said he had seen dogs in worse condition
                 <lb/>and that I sould let <name type="dog">Shippy</name> stay in the <unclear>machine</unclear> shop
                 <lb/>for a while I really didn't want to do this because
                 <lb/><name type="dog">Shippy</name>had been a good dog, had done his work well and
                 <lb/>probably would be okay if he lived to reach the states.
                 <lb/>I would rather shoot my dogs there than subject them to a
                 <lb/>sea voyage none of them likes because most of them are
                 <lb/>not pets and most likely will be done away with later on.
                 <lb/>Well, I left him in the medicine shop until after dinner
                 <lb/>when he began throwing up. I spoke to <persName>Dick</persName>again and
                 <lb/>he said since it was my dog I could do whatever I
                 <lb/>wanted with him. I took him out to the wind <unclear>moa</unclear>
                 <lb/>around the old <unclear>cedar</unclear><unclear>ha</unclear>and gave him two shots
                 <lb/><persName>Troy</persName>accompanied me to see his old friend die a death
                 <pb facs="journal 2-33" n="/4/44478c9d-f855-48a0-9d1b-0bff2c740f8d"/>
                 <fw type="pageNum" place="top">29</fw>
                 <lb/>probably more humane than any of the other dogs would get.
                 <lb/>As we watched him after the shot had been fired his
                 <lb/>tail wagged a few times and we thought he must 
                 <lb/>be enjoying a whole seal in dog heaven. Without 
                 <lb/>doubt <name type="dog">Shippy</name>will live in my mind long after the
                 <lb/>others have become faded memories. He well deserves
                 <lb/>it because he was one of my best dogs. 
              </p>
              <p>
                 <lb/>The tractor party<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="tractorparty"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="tractorparty">Tractor parties had to prepare the equipment as well as weigh and package the dog and human food and pemmican and plan details before the sledging parties could take off.
                    The sledging parties would travel distances ranging from 200-1200 miles round trip, so they needed supplies ready on the trail in depots to have a full sledge
                    load at the start of their trips, and on the way back, they would need food and fuel. The First Eastern Tractor Party, which left on September 18, consisted of Warren as the leader and navigator, Passel
                    as radio operator, and Boyd controlling the tractor that pulled a train of sleds loaded with supplies. Moulton laid and marked the trail as they headed east from their base 
                    and established 105-mile depot and laid caches of dog food along the way. This tractor party returned to base on Oct 3, 1940. Another party, the Second Eastern Tractor Party, left on October 2, 1940 and followed
                    the trail established by the first tractor party. This party was led  by Asman who drove the tank. He pulled the caboose and sleds with 8 tons
                    of supplies and tractor fuel. Clyde Griffith and Louis Colombo were also in this party, and their goal was to add more supplies to the 105-mile depot and transport materials to Rockefeller Mountains
                    for a seismic station. They returned to base on Octover 9, 1940.<bibl><ref target="#Bertrand">Bertrand 432-440</ref></bibl></note> came back Monday morning about 
                 <lb/>7AM. They made a <unclear>min o tap</unclear>dash in from 90. <unclear>fantastically</unclear>
                 <lb/>for our party they brought in with them our dog sled with
                 <lb/>all our extra gear on it. 
              </p>
              <p>
                 <lb/>The dog team party came in Tuesday morning. They
                 <lb/>they had camped at <placeName>Fort Wiener</placeName> Monday night but left
                 <lb/>at 3AM Tuesday morning. The <unclear>survey</unclear> party came in first
                 <lb/>about 9AM. <persName>Ike Schlossback</persName> was the last man in. All
                 <lb/>all of them looked as crumby as our party did when we 
                 <lb/>arrived. 
              </p>
              <p>
                 <lb/>Now that everyone is in and the trail season is over
                 <lb/>this <unclear>loosens</unclear> our Party's <unclear>moods.</unclear> A lot of <persName ref="#Fitz">Fitz</persName>'s gear, two
                 <lb/>of <persName>Dick's</persName> dogs, 3 of Bursey's and one of <persName><unclear>Larry's</unclear></persName> and of
                 <lb/><unclear>common</unclear> the Condor.
              </p>
              <p>
                 <lb/>I shall take <persName ref="#Fitz">Fitz</persName> in the <unclear>bashel</unclear> tomorrow for the start
                 <lb/>in the trail parties. There are only 6 men I want to get
                 <lb/>but there may be a <unclear>repeat</unclear> in the group. I am planning
                 <lb/>on a week. 
              </p>
           </div>
          <pb facs="journal-2-34" n="/6/6d39d1ce-b6a1-4093-a5f3-c47bf9d1d37b"/>
          <div xml:id="eel-19410110" type="entry">
             <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-10">Friday January 10<hi rend="superscript">Fr</hi></date></dateline>
             <p>
                <lb/>Day of days. The <name type="ship">Bear</name> has came in.  
             </p>
             <p>
                <lb/>I didn't get to bed until about 6 that morning. <persName>Arnold</persName> wanted 
                <lb/>me to do our <unclear>andyin</unclear> he thought would be continental air
                <lb/>he thought I might take a sample and do the analysis tomorrow
                <lb/>but since I have only one <unclear>willching</unclear> bottle and I needed that for
                <lb/>this morning. I had to finish the analysis almost immediately. 
                <lb/>In the meantime I took a bath. Wonder of wonders! Actually
                <lb/>I think I was ashamed into it, by the way the boys who came
                <lb/>in from the trail meticulously removed the layers of dirt that had
                <lb/>accumulated while vacationing in the mountains.
             </p>
             <p>
                <lb/>After doing the analysis I went to bed for a few hours and
                <lb/>then ran a metabolism test on <persName ref="#Fitz">Fitz</persName>.
             </p>
             <p>
                <lb/>About four o'clok the <name type="ship">Bear</name> came in on the radio and said
                <lb/>that they would be in at 5:30. However since they did not
                <lb/>realize how close they were to the bay and they were already tied
                <lb/>up when I arrived on the <unclear>ceene</unclear> at quarter of five. After the
                <lb/>crew had sunk the dead men a group of us were welcomed around
                <lb/>by Captain <persName>Cruzen</persName> and then we went out to the admiral's
                <lb/>quarter's (unoccupied) and recieved our mail. I was one
                <lb/>of the most fortunate ones and had a large bundle including
                <lb/>some files and some candy. I also received the money I had
                <lb/>asked for. I hardly knew which letter to open first but
                <lb/>decided to open the smallest one and save the big one, like
                <lb/><persName><unclear>Reasie's</unclear></persName> and <persName><unclear>Carl's</unclear></persName> and <persName><unclear>Jean's</unclear></persName> for the end because they would
                <lb/>cover most of the <unclear>hint</unclear>in which I <unclear>care</unclear> especially <unclear>intrusted.</unclear>
                <lb/>I read a few in the ship and then <unclear>ami</unclear> back to the base <unclear>above</unclear>
             </p>
           
           
           <pb facs="journal-2-35.jpg" n="/7/7fcaf75e-b11c-4550-b8c6-1f54f7e00792"/>
         <fw type="pageNum" place="top">31</fw>
            <p>
               <lb/>I read them all all over again. I had one from <persName ref="#Mary">Mary</persName>
               <lb/>which had in it some pictures of <persName ref="#Carl">Carl</persName> and her and
               <lb/>one of one of her sisters. I enjoyed also the pictures
               <lb/><persName ref="#Beatie">Beatie</persName> sent of <name type="dog" ref="#Petedog">Pete</name>, <name type="dog" ref="#Peterdog">Peter</name>, <persName ref="#clinton">Papa</persName>, and the house. Both
               <lb/><persName ref="#Van">Van</persName> <del rend="strikethrough">I</del> and <persName ref="#Vivian">Vivian</persName> sent letters with pictures in them of the
               <lb/>new baby. <persName ref="#George">George</persName> also sent pictures in his letter. Other
               <lb/>letters came from <persName ref="#Dave">Dave</persName> and <persName ref="#Mary">Mary</persName>, <persName ref="#Henry">Henery</persName>, <persName ref="#Dot">Dot</persName>, <persName ref="#Elenore">Elenore</persName>
               <lb/><persName ref="#Jenene">Jenene</persName>. <del rend="strikethrough"><unclear cert="low">Is</unclear></del> I had one of <del rend="strikethrough">of</del> the most pleasant of times
               <lb/>I have had in a long while.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>Some of the boys from the west came up to the base
               <lb/>and <persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> had I thought had a great time showing <add place="above" rend="^">them</add> around
               <lb/>and telling them all his experiences.
               <lb/>With the coming of the <name type="ship" ref="#Bear">Bear</name> the Exploration really is on the
               <lb/>wane. The <name type="ship" ref="#Star">Star</name> will be in after a couple of weeks and
               <lb/><placeName ref="#WestBase">West Base</placeName> will become a thing of the past. The sooner
               <lb/>the better.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div xml:id="eel-19410113a" type="entry">
               <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-13"><del rend="strikethrough">Jul</del>Jan 13 1941</date></dateline>
             <p>
               <lb/>This place has become a mad house and an open
               <lb/>house. During <del rend="strikethrough"><unclear cert="unknown"></unclear></del> the past few days everyone has been
               <lb/><del rend="strikethrough"><unclear cert="unknown"></unclear></del>irritation everyone else cause greatly little work has
               <lb/>been done. Movies have been shown to the sailors every 
               <lb/>night and after the shows <persName ref="#BuckBoyd">Buck</persName> takes them down to 
               <lb/>the <unclear cert="low">barrier</unclear> on the <placeName ref="#WestBase">West Base</placeName> <unclear cert="low">limited</unclear> - the 
                
                 with
               <lb/>the dog sled hitched on behind. I have given several
               <lb/>dog sled rides.
             </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>Today a little more order has prevailed. I ran a 
            <pb facs="journal-2-36.jpg" n="/0/00f6b1f6-ee2b-45cd-bd18-44400d0a3392"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">32</fw>
                  <lb/>metabolism test on <persName ref="#CharliePassel">Charlie Passel</persName> and am continuing
                  <lb/>my air analysis. <persName ref="#Arnold">Arnold</persName> made a very valuable suggestion
                  <lb/>and I shall follow it. I shall take air samples<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="airsamples"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="airsamples">Dr. Lockhart collectet air samples
                       throughout the Expedition for research on oxygen levels in the atmosphere. His work was published in 1942 where he provided a summery of his findings. Dr. Lockhart
                       wrote "Analysis of the lower atmosphere of the Antarctic were made using the Haldane portable apparatus. A veriable deficiency in the oxygen content of the air, too 
                       great to be attributable to insturment error, was found. The value for oxygen range from 20.76 to 20.48 volume percent. Since all possible sources of error were eliminated,
                       the deficiency in considered to be real."<bibl><ref target="#Lockhart1942">"Oxygen Defiency in Antarctic Air"</ref></bibl></note> on the
                  <lb/>way back and check the idea that the oxygen content
                  <lb/>of the atmosphere varies with the latitude If this works out
                  <lb/>I should have a curve showing on increase to <placeName ref="#EastBase">East Base</placeName>
                  <lb/>or there about a decrease to the <geogName ref="#Equator">equator</geogName> and there are
                  <lb/>increases of air to <placeName ref="#Seattle">Seattle</placeName>. This would be something
                  <lb/>worth while to the meteorologists and can be done with little
                  <lb/>expendeture of time.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/><persName ref="#Perk">Perk</persName> has two valuable finds both Ross seals<ptr type="noteAnchor" target="ross"/>
                  <note resp="ed" xml:id="ross"> The Ross Seals are the most rare typle of seal found in the Antarctic. Some explorations cite only observing
                  a few Ross seals during their entire time in the Antarctic, making any sighting worth noting.<bibl><ref target="#Allen">"Extinction and Vanishing Mammals"</ref>
                  </bibl></note>a
                  <lb/>male and female. These seals are very brave and have 
                  <lb/>not been reported for many years.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Recently <persName ref="#Malcolm">Malcolm</persName> has threatened to take a walk
                  <lb/>and <persName ref="#DocFrazier">Doc Frazier</persName> has made the recommendation that he
                  <lb/>be watched constantly. One of the Expeditions projects on the
                  <lb/>way home will be to get him back safely.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/><persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> is driving my team while I am busy and he
                  <lb/>doesn't seem to be doing so well. He isn't as strict with
                  <lb/>the dogs as I am and they, intelligent animals as they 
                  <lb/>are, take advantage of his good nature.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>A hole has been made in the back of the food cache and
                  <lb/>much of the stuff is being moved out.
               </p>
            </div>
           <pb facs="journal-2-37.jpg" n="/8/8079e385-54cd-4150-83cf-d2e8bd8d3aee"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">33</fw>
            <div xml:id="eel-19410114a" type="entry">
               <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-14">1/14/41<del rend="strikethrough">W</del>Tuesday January 14 1941</date></dateline>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Had <persName ref="#Richardson">Dick</persName> in the basket this morning; everything <unclear>went</unclear>
                  <lb/>off <unclear cert="medium">alright</unclear>.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/><emph style="underline">For</emph> breakfast we had some fried eggs sunny side
                  <lb/>up. <name type="ship" ref="#Bear">The Bear</name> exchanged several crates purchased <emph style="underline">in</emph>
                  <lb/><placeName ref="#NewZealand">New Zealand</placeName> for some of our while frozen eggs. They
                  <lb/>sure were good. I had these with some Virgina ham.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>The wind had come up during the night and
                  <lb/>about <time>ten</time> this morning the ice in the <geogFeat>Bay</geogFeat> began
                  <lb/>breaking up and the <name type="ship" ref="#Bear">Bear</name> <emph style="underline">had</emph> to move out. <unclear>If</unclear> in
                  <lb/>having to stay out all day. The ice which had expanded
                  <lb/>from <num>1.5</num> to <num>2</num> miles past the new <unclear>laviner</unclear> cache all cracked
                  <lb/>up and was being taken out by the SSE wind. It looks 
                  <lb/>as though it will crack out as far back as the cache,
                  <lb/>which means a lot of <geogFeat>Bay</geogFeat> ice has to move out. It
                  <lb/>also means that we may have an easier time loading
                  <lb/>than was expected.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I read the reports of the expedition that have been
                  <lb/>published in various newspapers and reprinted in the <date>March</date>
                  <lb/>issue of the <title level="j" ref="#ThePolarTimes">Polar Times</title>. I have never seen such a 
                  <lb/>mess of rubbish collected together in one small volume in
                  <lb/>my life. It was all "the Admiral this" and "<persName ref="#Richard">Byrd</persName> that"
                  <lb/>No matter where the airplanes flew the mountains they saw
                  <lb/>had been previously "discovered" by <persName ref="#Richard">Byrd</persName>. One clipping
                  <lb/>also stated that the admiral made flights and took
                  <lb/>pictures enough "to map accurately" about <measure>35000</measure> sq.
                  <lb/>miles of <emph style="underline">new</emph> territory. We all know that they only
         <pb facs="journal-2-38.jpg" n="/2/29660762-216a-434c-97a1-f246fa4f8e8c"/>
         <fw type="pageNum" place="top">34</fw> 
                <lb/>camera taken on those flights was a Leica and no
                <lb/>attempt was made to make overlaps or circles of pictures.
                <lb/>It is doubtful whether the admiral knew accurately where
                <lb/>he was. The reports said he discovered new mountains
                <lb/><num>300</num> miles from here and we know that there are no 
                <lb/><emph style="underline">new</emph> mountains within <num>300</num> miles of the base. <sic>in</sic>fact the
                <lb/>plows had to tax their range to the limit to get into
                <lb/>new territory.  Our trail party was <num>300</num> miles from the
                <lb/>base and we didn't see any mountains that had never
                <lb/>been seen before. The blarney that was written about
                <lb/>the dangers we faced while unloading was exaggerated
                <lb/>so much that we wondered if we were on the same
                <lb/>expedition. It was hoped by all hands that since this
                <lb/>was a government expedition all of the exaggeration and
                <lb/>untruths would be cut out of the reports.  We feel that
                <lb/>the type of publicity so necessary to a private expedition
                <lb/><del rend="strikethrough">was</del>is absolutely unnecessary for this expedition.  However,
                <lb/>since <persName>Byrd</persName> seems to be the only one who is getting credit
                <lb/>for all the work done down here even though he has 
                <lb/>had actually little to do with the goings on, it must
                <lb/>be he and his stooge <persName ref="#Hawthorne">Hawthorne</persName> who have contrived to
                <lb/>keep the exaggerations and untruths on the same high
                <lb/>plane as maintained on previous expeditions. <persName>Hawthorne</persName>
                <lb/>who is coming down in the <name type="ship" ref="#Star">Star</name> presumably to collect
                <lb/>film journals diaries etc is suspected of having his
                <lb/>own ax to grind--a book on the expedition for the
                <lb/>Admiral--and consequently will have little cooperation
               </p>
       <!-- Misha Me Fecit -->
               <pb facs="journal-2-39.jpg" n="/a/a95e7b8a-3a8d-4a07-9b3f-7a12798fa0ee"/>
               <!-- Don't rememer what to put for the n attribute... Ask Lewis...-->
               <fw type="pageNum" place="top">35</fw>
               <!-- 35 should be underlined? -->
               <p>
                  <lb/>He has already done some funny things with film
                  <lb/>entrusted to him when he came down last year so
                  <lb/>I doubt that he will be given the same opportunity
                  <lb/>this time. So far as some of us are concerned his
                  <lb/>plans will be defeated because we have received orders
                  <lb/>from <persName>Dr. Wade</persName> the chief scientist to turn <!-- upper insertion --> in to him <!-- snip -->anything
                  <!-- Look up pername handling -->
                  <lb/>that can have <!-- deletion -->a<!-- snip --> bearing on our own scientific reports
                  <lb/>This we shall gladly do because we trust him where as 
                  <lb/>we don't trust <persName>Hawthorne</persName>. No matter now. All
                  <lb/>the dish will come out in the wash.
               </p> 
            </div>
         <div xml:id="eel-19410115a" type="entry">
            <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-15">Wednesday January 15 1941</date></dateline>
               <p>
                  <lb/>No metabolism test this morning but we did have
                  <lb/>eggs sunny side up again. For the first time in my
                  <lb/>life I ate four eggs at one sitting and I believe I
                  <lb/>could have eaten a couple more.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>All of the <!-- Spelling? -->food<!-- snip --> going back much of the radio gear
                  <lb/><!-- Spelling? -->meterological<!-- snip --> equipment and aviation gear has already
                  <lb/>been taken down to the <geogName>barrier edge</geogName>. It looks as though
                  <lb/>it won't be difficult to get <!-- underline -->all<!-- snip --> of the stuff going back
                  <lb/>down to the cache. Once down there it won't take long to
                  <lb/>load the stuff on the ships. The <name type="ship">Star</name>, by the way,
                  <lb/>has been in <placeName>Dunedin</placeName> several days and should be here
                  <lb/>about the 28th of the month.<!-- Date there? --> In another three weeks
                  <lb/>we shall be leaving and glad to do so.   
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/><persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> had been doing a good job with the dogs even
                  <lb/>if he does get lost now and then and the team
            <!-- Misha Exit -->
           <pb facs="jouranl-2-40.jpg" n="/c/c459ce06-004e-4068-b349-a293327f6170"/>
         <fw type="pageNum" place="top">36</fw>
            <lb/>runs away occasionally.</p>
            <p>
               <lb/>I made up some Benedict's for <persName>Due</persName> and he shows
               <lb/>a negative test.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/><persName>Pete</persName> and <persName>Wiener</persName> made their hop this afternoon. <persName>Pete</persName>
               <lb/>wants to crack this altitude record <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="noteAltituderecords"/><note resp="ed" xml:id="altitiderecords">Thomas Petras, also knows as Peter, was a pilot on the expedition. On March 9th 1940, Peter broke the record at that time for highest airplane flight over Antarctica by flying 21,050 feet up in the beechcraft on a cosmic ray research flight. Lockhart presumably calls this 'last fall' because seasons are reversed in Antarctica. <bibl><ref target="#Wings1980"></ref><ref target="#Bertrand"></ref></bibl></note>he set up last fall. <persName>Murry</persName>
               <lb/>is cosmic ray observer and also will take charge of the bottles
               <lb/>I sent up for air samples. When they came down I got
               <lb/>some pictures of the landing. <persName>Wiener</persName> had carried out my
               <lb/>instructions and I removed the flasks. They went up only to
               <lb/><measure>17000 ft</measure> because the rubber tubing caused the wings to
               <lb/>vibrate. After dinner I got <persName ref="#BuckBoyd">Buck</persName> to light his oxygen torch
               <lb/>so that I could seal off the flasks. It was unsucessful
               <lb/>because the pressure inside the flasks was so great that
               <lb/>holes <subst><del rend="strikethrough">blew out</del><add place="above">were made in</add></subst> in the tubing where it was heated. I have
               <lb/>one flask that will be good enough for air analysis here
               <lb/>but only as an indicator.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>I had a "gram" from his men saying she was sorry
               <lb/>not to have sent mail on the <name type="ship">Star</name> but would have letters
               <lb/>for me in <placeName>Valpo</placeName>.
            </p>
            <p>
               <lb/>I didn't do much else but sit around and talk to
               <lb/><persName ref="#Klondicke">Klimdike</persName> about <placeName>Alaska</placeName>. I went to bed after my
               <lb/>midnight metereological observation.
            </p>
            
         </div>
            <pb facs="journal-2-41.jpg" n="/4/4dcdda8f-e271-4a15-b50a-852c9f3e3945"/>
            <fw type="pageNum" place="top">37</fw>
            <div xml:id="eel-19410116a" type="entry">
               <lb/>
               <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-16">Thursday January 16 1941</date></dateline>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Had <persName ref="#Bursey">Jack Bursey</persName> in the basket this morning. I think
                  <lb/>this will be the last because I want to <del rend="strikethrough">have</del> start
                  <lb/>packing my stuff for home. The <unclear>Star</unclear> which is
                  <lb/>leaving <placeName>Dunedin</placeName> tomorrow will be here about the 27<hi rend="superscript">th</hi>
                  <lb/>and I want to have everything ready. I shall try
                  <lb/>to avoid any last minute rush as I had in Boston
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Most of the day was spent doing gas analyses.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/><persName ref="#Tony">Tony</persName> presented me not only with a special <name type="ship">Bear</name>
                  <lb/>cachet but also with cancelled stamped envelope<subst><del rend="overwritten">d</del><add place="inline">s</add></subst>
                  <lb/>bearing the cancellation st<subst><del rend="overwritten">p</del><add place="inline">a</add></subst>amps of the various places
                  <lb/>visited on her trip down here. They make a very valuable
                  <lb/>collection. When I get home I shall make a cachet
                  <lb/>of linoleum or wood and cachet these envelopes. Then
                  <lb/>they will be collectors items.  
                  <ptr type="noteAnchor" target="cachets"/><note xml:id="cachets" resp="ed">
                     A cachet is "[a] printed, embossed or (usually) handstamped inscription or device impressed on a cover
                     to denote the special circumstances in which it has been posted (e.g. an expedition or special flight)"
                     <bibl><ref target="#Philatelic"><title>(Bennet and Watson 12)</title></ref></bibl>; a cancellation is a mark used to deface a stamp so that it cannot be used again
                     <bibl><ref target="#Philatelic"><title>(13)</title></ref></bibl>.  As Lockhart indicates here, cachets and cancellations from mail processed on polar expeditions are highly prized 
                     among philatelists (stamp collectors) due to their rarity   <bibl><ref target="#South-Pole"><title level="m">South-Pole.com</title></ref></bibl>; <bibl><ref target="#ASPP">
                        <title level="m">American Society of Polar Philatelists</title></ref></bibl>.
                  </note> I also shall have
                  <lb/><persName>Wallace</persName> the yeoman and postmaster aboard the <name type="ship">Bear</name>
                  <lb/>cancel some stamped envelopes so that I can have
                  <lb/>many left over after I send my mail out.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>Not much activity in camp today. <persName>Pete</persName> made
                  <lb/>several <unclear>hops</unclear> just for fun and also to make a
                  <lb/><placeName ref="#BayofWhales">Bay of Whales</placeName> <del rend="strikethrough">sun</del> aerial survey with <persName ref="#Shirley">Shirley</persName> doing the
                  <lb/>photographing. <persName ref="#Richardson">Jack R.</persName> and <persName ref="#Fitz">Fitz</persName> layed out some
                  <lb/>markers.
               </p>
               <p>
                  <lb/>I spent some time reading funny <unclear cert="medium">parts</unclear>.
               </p>
            </div>
            <pb facs="journal-2-42.jpg" n="/3/307a134d-da7d-4fd0-b6f0-36894ed902b7"/>
            <pb facs="journal-2-43.jpg" n="/f/f3da51c0-d53b-4431-8185-bf2366dddc11"/>
            <pb facs="journal-2-44.jpg" n="/7/7f363505-4a1f-4261-8438-98b840c4f9bb"/>
            <pb facs="journal-2-45.jpg" n="/d/d0f7a89a-bed8-48ff-b739-9a12056532e1"/>
           <div xml:id="eel-undated-1" type="entry">
              <p>
                 <lb/><hi rend="underlined">Outgoing mail.</hi>
                 <lb/><rs>Folks</rs><gap reason="deletion" unit="chars" extent="1"></gap> <persName ref="#Beatie">Beatie</persName>, <persName>Carl</persName>, 
                      <persName>Mrs. <unclear>Mann</unclear></persName>, <persName><unclear>Van</unclear></persName>, <persName>George</persName>, 
                      <persName>Laurie</persName> &amp; <persName>Henry</persName>,
                 <lb/><persName><unclear>Burker</unclear></persName>, <persName>Bob Harris</persName>, <persName>Bill Leckie</persName>, 
                      <persName>George Low</persName>, <persName>H. D. Lockhart</persName>,
                 <lb/><persName>Priscilla</persName>, <persName>Dave</persName>, <persName>Dorothy</persName>, <persName>Mrs. Heiborn</persName>, 
                      <persName><choice><sic>The Guernsey's</sic><corr>Guernseys</corr></choice></persName>.
              </p>
           </div>
            <pb facs="journal-2-46.jpg" n="/d/d38e7754-5bff-48d5-89cc-0e262e1134f3"/>
     </body> <!-- Close body of journal 2 text. -->
     </text>  <!-- Close journal 2 text. -->
     <text xml:id="eel-journal2-radiograms">   <!-- Open text #2, telegrams inserted in journal #2. -->
            <body> <!-- Open body of text #2. -->
               <div xml:id="eel-19401226b" type="radiogram" subtype="sent" facs="journal-2-47">
                  
                  <opener>
                  <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-26" type="sent">Dec 26 1940</date></dateline>
                     <address>
                        <lb/><persName ref="#MrsMahan">Mrs J L Mahan</persName>
                        <lb/><addrLine>38 <ref type="ArlingtonStreet">Arlington Street</ref></addrLine>
                        <lb/><addrLine><ref type="HydePark">Hyde Park</ref> Mass</addrLine>
                     </address>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>Extremely sorry to hear of <persName ref="#MrMahan">Mr Mahan</persName>'s passing. Had been looking
                     <lb/>forward to telling him of my many adventures. Feel certain
                     <lb/>that he is resting more peacefully now than he did during recent
                     <lb/>years. Anxious to get home to see you all again.
                  </p>
                  <lb/>
                  <closer>
                  <lb/><persName>Earl</persName></closer>
                  </div> 
               <div xml:id="eel-19401231" type="radiogram" subtype="recieved" facs="journal-2-48">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-28" type="recieved">8 dec 1940</date></dateline>
                     <lb/>wlcm <ref type="Wilmington">wilmington</ref> del not date
                     <lb/><persName>LOCKHARD</persName>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>enjoyed your xmas greetingx best wishes for the new year and a safe
                     <lb/>return
                  </p>
                  <lb/>
                  <closer>
                     <lb/><persName>mary</persName> and <persName>carl</persName></closer>
               </div>
                
             
               <div xml:id="eel-19401231a" type="radiogram" subtype="sent" facs="journal-2-49" n="/4/4bfcf4fd-687b-48e2-9169-0c1d69d9ba36">
                  <opener> 
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-31" type="sent">Dec 31 1940</date></dateline> 
                     <address>
                        <lb/><persName>Mrs. W H Mann</persName>
                        <lb/><addrLine>1281 Ramona Ave</addrLine>
                        <lb/><addrLine>Cleveland Ohio</addrLine>
                     </address>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>Arrived back at base for christmas. Had a wonderful trip. Awaiting
                     <lb/>arrival of ships for mail they hold. Anxious to get back to see
                     <lb/>everyone. Return via <placeName>Valporaiso</placeName> <placeName ref="#Panama">Panama</placeName> and <placeName>Seattle</placeName>. May have a 
                     <lb/>few days to spend with you while crossing country. Arrive <placeName>Seattle</placeName>
                     <lb/>middle April. Happy new year to all. 
                  </p>
                  <lb/><closer><persName>Earl</persName></closer>
               </div>
               <div xml:id="eel-19401231b" type="radiogram" subtype="sent" facs="journal-2-50" n="/b/bbbadca7-b003-4003-a8a6-5b63720cd93d">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-31" type="sent">Dec 31 1940</date></dateline>
                     <address>
                        <lb/><persName>Mr George W Trefts</persName>
                        <lb/><addrLine>730 Atlanta Ave</addrLine>
                        <lb/><addrLine>Webster Groves, Mo.</addrLine>
                     </address>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>Still out on trail when you spoke over air. Reception very poor.
                     <lb/>Sorry. Thanks for sending pictures to <persName ref="#mamma">mother</persName>. Leave here for
                     <lb/><placeName>Seattle</placeName> end of January. Please pass word along to <persName>Karlstrom</persName>.
                     <lb/>Arrive middle April. Be seeing you on way home if possible. 
                     <lb/>Happy new year.
                  </p>
                  <lb/><closer><persName>Earl</persName></closer>
               </div>
               <!-- A div for a radiogram from an earlier date would go here. -->
               <div xml:id="eel-19401231e" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-53" n="/9/9fcd6e47-dbf3-4447-9214-6280bf6f3425">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-31" type="received"><del type="overwritten">27</del>31 dec 1940</date></dateline>
                     <lb/>18 <name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">wlmc</name> <placeName>mattapan mass</placeName> <date when="1940-12-27" type="sent">dec 27</date>
                     <lb/><salute><persName>ERNEST E LOCKHART</persName></salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>had a letter from trefts x hope you had a talk with him <choice><sic>frirday</sic><corr>friday</corr></choice>
                     <lb/>night as he expected to x he sent me two nice enlargements of snaps
                     <lb/>you took in <placeName ref="#helsinki"><choice><sic>helsiki</sic><corr>helsinki</corr></choice></placeName> x missed <persName>carl</persName> this <choice><sic>xmas</sic><corr>christmas</corr></choice> had <choice><sic>peteinstead</sic><corr>pete instead</corr></choice> x i
                     <lb/>hope my penguin is coming along x remember i'm going to have him
                     <lb/>mounted so if it will be easier to just <choice><sic>dring</sic><corr>bring</corr></choice> his hide ok by me
                     <lb/>happy new year
                  </p>
                  <lb/><signed><persName ref="#mamma">mother</persName></signed>
               </div>
               <div xml:id="eel-19410101" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-54" n="/c/cdaed0da-eaf8-4e74-accc-daa62ff14cb3">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-01" type="received">JAN 1 1941</date></dateline>
                     <lb/>NR 12 <name ref="#WLMC">WLMC</name> <placeName ref="#Wellesley">WELLESLEY MASS</placeName> <date when="1940-12-29" type="sent">DEC 29</date>
                     <lb/><salute><persName>EARL LOCKHART</persName></salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>HAPPY PROSEPEROUS NEW YEAR X HOPE TO <add place="above">me</add> GET YOU ON RETURN <add place="above" rend="^">to the U.S.</add> X <persName ref="#Guernsey">THE GUERNSEYS</persName>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div xml:id="eel-19400102a" type="radiogram" facs="journal-2-55" n="/D/d008d323-2484-4321-bf8a-a17ef90e075a">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/>3 <name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">wlmc</name> <placeName ref="#Wellesley">wellesley mass</placeName> <date when="1941-12-28" type="received">dec 28</date><dateline><date when="1941-01-02" type="transmitted">Jan 2 1941</date></dateline>
                     <lb/><salute><persName>LOCKHART</persName></salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>happy and prosperous new year x hope to meet you on return to united
                     <lb/>states
                  </p>
                  <lb/><closer><persName ref="#Guernsey">the george guernsey</persName></closer>
               </div>
               <div xml:id="eel-19410103a" type="radiogram" facs="journal-2-56" n="/C/cb5e3b56-14a4-46e0-9f63-dbecb3c47d5e">
                  <opener>
                    <lb/><date when="1941-01-03" type="received">Jan 3 1940</date>
                    <lb/><persName ref="#Guernsey">Mr Guernsey and Family</persName>
                     <lb/><placeName ref="#UplandRoad">7 Upland Rd
                     <lb/>Wellsley Mass</placeName>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>Arrived back at base in time for Christmas. Had wonderful trip with
                     <lb/>dogs in new territory. Now anxiously waiting for mail on ships not
                     <lb/>far from here. Also anxious <choice><orig>toget</orig><corr>to get</corr></choice> home again. W shall return vis
                     <lb/>Valparaiso <placeName ref="#Panama">Panama</placeName> and Seattle. Journey's end probably in May.
                  </p>
                  <lb/><closer>Earl</closer>
               </div>
                <div xml:id="eel-19401210a" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-58" n="/c/c54c11a9-659f-4566-b4f8-b81635104f9f">
                 <opener>
                    <lb/>2 <name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">wlmc</name> <placeName ref="#Boston">boston mass</placeName> <date when="1940-12-05" type="received">dec 5</date> <dateline><date when="1940-12-10" type="transmitted">10 dec 1940</date></dateline>
                    <lb/><salute><persName ref="#EEL">earl <choice><sic>lockhard</sic><corr>lockhart</corr></choice></persName></salute>
                 </opener>
                 <p>
                    <lb/>just discovered that you can receive messages on this trip you are
                    <lb/><choice><sic>talking</sic><corr>taking</corr></choice> x sorry not to have <gap reason="overwritten with x's" unit="chars" extent="2"/>nt anything for before x hope you are well
                    <lb/>x little <name type="dog" ref="#Peterdog">peter</name> now weighs 26 pounds x bring on your husky x everyone look<seg type="softhyphen">
                    <lb/></seg>ing forward anxiously to your2return we <gap reason="overwritten with x's" unit="chars" extent="4"/> all well and happy x eight
                    <lb/>inches o<gap reason="overwritten"/>f snow for thanksgiving all well
                 </p>
                    <lb/><closer><persName ref="#Beatie">beatie</persName></closer>
                    <!-- There are some handwritten letters in pencil on the bottom of this radiogram. Possibly used to send it? -->
                </div>
               <div xml:id="eel-19410116" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-59" n="/4/4741f814-0c98-42d0-89e7-013bfe2836fa">
                  <opener> 
                  <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-16" type="received">JAN 16/41</date></dateline>
                     <lb/>
                     <lb/>
                  <lb/><placeName>CLEVELAND OHIO</placeName> <name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">WLMC 1139</name>
                  <lb/>
                  <lb/>
                  <lb/><salute><persName>DR LOCKHART</persName></salute>:
                  </opener>
                 <lb/><p>4x14 X SORRY DIDNT GET LETTER OFF ON <name>NORTH STAR</name> X
                 <lb/>WILL WRITE MAIL CARE CONSUL AT <placeName>VALPO</placeName> AS SUPPOSE YOU WILL PICK
                 <lb/>UP MAIL THERE X <persName ref="#Daumcarden">DAUMCARDEN</persName> NOT ABLE TO CONTACT YOU X EAGERLY 
                 <lb/>AWAITING YOUR VISIT X HOPE TO GET LETTER FROM THERE
                 </p>
                 <lb/><closer>LOVE BON VOYAGE</closer>
                 <lb/> 
                  <lb/><signed><persName ref="#MargaretMann">MARGARET MANN</persName></signed>
               <lb/><!-- FL is written to the far left of the telegram -->
               </div>
               
               <div xml:id="eel-19410112b" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="joutnal-2-60" n="/e/efe1a485-9da8-4377-9e86-670ad7a12672">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/>9 <name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">wlmc</name> <placeName>richmond xx ind</placeName> <dateline><date when="1941-01-09" type="sent">jan 9</date></dateline>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-12" type="received">12 jan 1941<!-- to the far right --></date></dateline>
                     <lb/>
                     <lb/><salute><persName>LOCKHART</persName></salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>
                     <lb/>
                     <lb/>dear doc x shall contact <name>karlstom</name> in <placeName>seattle</placeName> immediately x am to
                     <lb/>be drafted next month x hope to see you in june on your way east
                     <lb/>x your folks send their regards
                  </p>
                      <lb/><signed>the gear man<!-- indented to the far right --></signed>
               </div>
               
               <div xml:id="eel-19401128" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-61" n="/3/32bdfaa4-9bad-41c9-9066-c3a102046801">
                 <opener>
                  <lb/><name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">2 WLMC</name> <date>28 nov 1940</date>
                  <lb/>FROM <placeName type="city">CLEVELAND</placeName> 0 <abbr>NOV</abbr> NO DATE 
                  <lb/><persName type="misspelling">LOCKHARD</persName> <!--This is probably a typo but lets not rule out that lockhard could be a nickname-->
                  </opener> 
                  <p>
                     <lb/>
                  <lb/>think of you often x hope you are enjoying pleasnt summer and iteresting 
                  <lb/>trip x fattering calif <!--I'm sure it means fattening calf--> against your return x love
                  <lb/>
                  </p>
                  <closer>
                  <lb/> <signed><persName>margaret</persName></signed>
                  </closer>   
                  <note><lb/> NOW- <del type="pen-scrates">4</del>
                  <lb/>0825
                  <lb/>28
                  </note> <!--The 2 is followed by illegible scribbles here; the three lines after margaret were all wrtten in after and at an angle-->
                               
               </div>  
                 
               <div xml:id="eel-19401222a" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-62" n="/4/4c005625-1a86-48c5-904b-89cd52cea965">
                <opener>
                   <lb/><name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">25 wlmc</name> <placeName type="city">cleveland</placeName> <date type="sent">dec 19</date> <date type="received">22 Dec 1940</date>
                  <lb/><persName>LOCKHART</persName>
                </opener> 
                  <p><lb/>
                  <lb/>
                  <lb/>we will be thinking of you on xmas day x hope you will make a 
                  <lb/>merry christmas for yourself at the <placeName>south pole</placeName> x will <!--it looks like the letter i in will was put over a letter e--> we talk to
                  <lb/>you during the holidays
                  <lb/>
                  </p>
                  <closer>
                     margaret mann
                  </closer>
                  <note><lb/>
                    <lb/>N U W - 4 <!--This could be either a 4 or a capital H-->
                    <lb/>0817
                  </note> <!-- Again, these last two lines were written in afterward -->
                  
               </div>  
                  
                <div xml:id="eel-19401225b" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-63" n="/3/350707bb-644c-48c6-b010-fbf4af419233">
                 <opener>
                    <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-25" type="received">25 DEC 1940</date></dateline>
                    <lb/>NR5 <name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">WLMC</name> <date when="1940-12-21" type="sent">DEC 21</date> <placeName>BOSTON MASS</placeName>
                    <lb/><persName>DR LOCKHART</persName> <!-- Should this be treated as an address? Probably. -->
                    <lb/><salute>dear <persName>earl</persName></salute>
                 </opener>
                 <!-- Is any of the information in the opener a "byline"? -->
                 <p>best wishes for a happy christmas. at least you can have
                    <lb/>real snow balls on your tree. little <name type="dog" ref="#Peterdog">peter</name> now weighs 31 lbs and stands
                    <lb/>20 inches. with this i am sending bad news . <rs>jack mahans father</rs> died
                    <lb/>on wednesday spent evening with them . he was <choice><sic>burried</sic><corr>buried</corr></choice> today be seeing
                    <lb/>you soon . love from all friend and family . thanks giving picture
                    <lb/>of <geogName>south pole</geogName> appeared in <title level="j">new york times</title> . some beard.</p>
                   
                   <closer>love
                    <lb/><signed><persName ref="#Beatie">beatie</persName></signed>
                   </closer>
               </div>
               
               <div xml:id="eel-19401226" type="radiogram" subtype="sent" facs="journal-2-64" n="/c/cb88c987-4c24-46d8-9b95-0b7859981f5c">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-26" type="sent">Dec 26 1940</date></dateline>
                     <address>
                        <lb/><persName ref="#mamma">Mrs C D Lockhart</persName>
                        <lb/><addrLine>49 Taunton Ave</addrLine>
                        <lb/><addrLine><placeName>Mattapan Mass</placeName></addrLine>
                     </address>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>Arrived back at the base xmas eve.  Had a wonderful time. Am
                     <lb/>now looking forward to return home.  Also to arriv<subst><del rend="overwritten with X's">ival</del><add place="above">al</add></subst> of ships
                     <lb/>for the mail they will bring.  Keep the candle in the window
                     <lb/>because it <choice><sic>wont</sic><corr>won't</corr></choice> be long now.  Will return to <placeName>Seattle</placeName> with <name type="ship">Star</name>.
                  </p>
                  <signed><persName>Earl</persName></signed>
               </div>
               <div xml:id="eel-19401218" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-65" n="/c/cb88c987-4c24-46d8-9b95-0b7859981f5c">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-18" type="received"> 18-DEC-1940</date></dateline>
                     <lb/> 2 <name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC"> WLMC</name><date when="1940-12-18" type="sent">DEC 16</date><placeName>RICHMOND IND</placeName>
                     <lb/><persName>LOCKHART</persName>
                  </opener>
                  <p>Dear Doc merry XMAS X I shall speak from <placeName type="city">Indianapolis</placeName>
                     <lb/>to you at Little America via Mail Bag Friday Dec. 20th hope you listen </p>
                  <closer>
                     <lb/><signed><persName>George</persName></signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
               
               <div xml:id="eel-19401219" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-66" n="/0/087da746-b373-4b8a-8f14-80ba6177e366">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-12-19" type="received">19-DEC-1940</date></dateline>
                     <lb/><persName>LOCKHART</persName>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/><persName>George W. Trefts</persName> will speak to you over WGEO next Friday 2oth.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <lb/><persName>BY</persName>
                  </closer>
               </div>
               
               <div xml:id="eel-19410104a" type="radiogram" subtype="sent" facs="journal-2-57" n="/2/21277b97-80c3-4419-929a-cbe1199256e1">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-01-04" type="sent">January 4 1941</date></dateline>
                     <address>
                        <lb/><persName ref="#Beatie">Miss Beatrice R Lockhart</persName>
                        <lb/><addrLine>49 Taunton Ave</addrLine>
                        <lb/><addrLine><placeName ref="#Mattapan">Mattapan Mass</placeName></addrLine>
                     </address>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>Am looking forward to the letters I know will be on the <name type="ship" ref="#Bear">Bear</name> and 
                     <lb/>the <name type="ship" ref="Star"><!-- When I made this notation, there wasn't an entry for the Star, so I did this preemptively. If Erin uses something else for the Star's xml:id, then this is wrong.-->Star</name>. Lost about ten pounds while on the trail but I could
                     <lb/>stand that. Hope to bring home my lead dog. He is one of the
                     <lb/>largest dogs we have in camp. Weight about ninety pounds. He
                     <lb/>is some dog even though the fellows make fun of him.
                  </p>
                  <lb/><signed><persName ref="#EEL">Earl</persName></signed>
               </div>
               
               <div xml:id="eel-19410109" type="radiogram" subtype="recived" facs="journal-2-67" n="/3/3718a2d2-860d-48f8-a7ab-5ed54a1437bc">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-01-09" type="recived">9 jan 1941</date></dateline>
                     <lb/>7 <name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">wlmc</name> <placeName ref="#Boston">boston mass</placeName> <date when="1941-01-06">jan 6</date>
                     <lb/><salute><persName ref="#EEL">EARL LOCKHART</persName></salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>dear <persName ref="#EEL">earl</persName> x we are anxiously watching the papers for news of the arrival
                     <lb/>of the <name type="ship" ref="#Bear">bear</name> x what rejoicing there will be in your neck of the woods
                     <lb/>x weather has turned cold here x feels like your summer x little <name type="dog" ref="#Peterdog">petere</name>
                     <lb/>now <num>thirty five</num> pounds x love
                  </p>
                  <lb/><signed><persName ref="#Beatie">beatie</persName></signed>
               </div>
               
               <div xml:id="eel-19410109b" type="radiogram" subtype="sent" facs="journal-2-68" n="/4/45528f49-dcdb-4ded-bf96-07f60c260cf0">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1940-01-09" type="sent">Jan 9 1941</date></dateline>
                     <address>
                        <lb/><persName ref="#mamma">Mrs C D Lockhart</persName>
                        <lb/><addrLine>49 Taunton Ave</addrLine>
                        <lb/><addrLine><placeName ref="#Mattapan">Mattapan Mass</placeName></addrLine>
                     </address>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/>The <name type="ship" ref="#Bear">Bear</name> arrives tomorrow. This is my last message although the
                     <lb/><name type="ship" ref="#Star">Star</name> probably wont leave before the first in <date>Febuary</date>. So
                     <lb/>it wont be long now until I climb the front stairs. Love to
                     <lb/>everyone. Will send airmail from various ports. 
                  </p>
                  <lb/><signed><persName ref="#EEL">Earl</persName></signed>
               </div>
               
               <div xml:id="eel-19410416" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-69" n="/3/3a1cb2ab-66fc-495d-974f-54174222c435" >
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-04-16" type="received" >16 APR 1941</date></dateline>
                     <lb/>5<name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">WLMC</name> <placeName>BOSTON MASS</placeName>
                     <lb/><salute><persName><sic>LOCKHARD</sic></persName></salute> 
                  </opener>
                 <p>
                    <lb/>DEAR EARL X YOUR LETTER AND PICTURES RECEIVED MONDAY X IT WAS GOOD TO ACTUALLY
                    <lb/>HAAR FROM YOU X THANK GOODNESS YOUR DOG IS LOSING WEIGHT X <name type="dog" ref="#Petedog">PETER</name> IS NOW
                    <lb/><measure><num>58</num>LBS</measure> X LETTERS WAITING A VALPO AND BALBOA X WE ARE ALL WELL AND
                    <lb/>LOOKING FARWARD TO <date>JUNE FIRST</date>X ONE MORE LETTER GOES TO BALBOA TODAY X LOVE
                 </p>
                   
                  <closer>BY <persName ref="#Beatie">BEATIE</persName></closer>
                </div>   
               <div xml:id="eel-19400419" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-70" n="/2/2a6d7bed-4810-48f4-9f2a-75d31b7d506d">
                 <opener>
                    <lb/>7 NIJS FB Z NIJS 182030 WTDU GR 37
                    <lb/>
                 </opener> 
                 <p>
                    <lb/>MSG DR E E LOCKHART X COULD YOU ARRANGE WITH THE POWER THAT BE
                    <lb/>AND SEE IF YOU CAN GET ONE OF SHELIA PUPS FOR ME X LET ME KNOW
                    <lb/>MANY THANKS REGARDS TO ALL <persName ref="#Tony">TONY COLUMBO</persName>
                    <lb/>
                    <!-- See if this bottom should be closer but without LB -->
                 </p> 
                 <closer>
                    <dateline><date when="1940-04-19" type="received">0040/19 APR</date></dateline>
                 </closer>
               </div>
               <div xml:id="eel-19410427" type="radiogram" subtype="received" facs="journal-2-71" n="/6/6ba69e71-75d0-4690-a21d-b8648a4159e4">
                  <opener>
                     <lb/><dateline><date when="1941-04-27" type="received" >27 r 1941</date></dateline>
                     <lb/>2<name type="call-sign" ref="#WLMC">WLMC</name> <placeName>NEW YORK NY</placeName> <date>APR 23</date>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <lb/><persName>DR ERNEST LOCKHART</persName>
                     <lb/><persName ref="#BillLeckie">BILL LECKIE</persName> WANTS TO KNOW WHAS YOUR EXPERIECE WITH HARRIS FOOD MIXTURE
                     <lb/>SATISFACTORY OR UNSATISFACTORY STOP DID MEN FIND IT PALATABLE OR UNPALATABLE
                     <lb/>STOP <persName ref="#BillLeckie">BILL LECKIE</persName> WANTS TO KNOW WILL <persName>DR LOCKHART</persName> INTERVIEW REPRESENTATIVES
                     <lb/><orgName ref="#Colliers">COLLIER WEEKLY</orgName> AT <placeName>BALBOA</placeName> IN CONNECTIONWITH ARTICLE ON HARRIS FOOD MIXTURE
                     <lb/>PROJECTED FOR BRITISH EMERGENCY FEEDING STOP PLEASE HAVE CABLE COLLECT
                     <lb/>TO ME 122 EAST FORTY SECOND STREET NEWYORKCITY STOP <persName>J E MACDONALD</persName> U S DEPART
                     <lb/>MENT OF INTERIOR AUTHORIZED THIS INQUIRY
                  </p>
                  
                  <closer> BY <persName ref="#BillLeckie">WILLIAM LECKIE</persName></closer>
               </div>
               <!-- A div for a radiogram from a later date would follow. -->
            </body> <!-- Close body of text #2, telegrams. -->
         </text> <!-- Close text #2, telegrams. -->
    </group> <!-- Close text group. -->
  </text> <!-- Close main text div -->
</TEI>